<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>lanVoyager | toHave-N-haveNot</title>
  
  <subtitle>大道无形</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-01-31T20:04:10.148Z</updated>
  <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>lanVoyager</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Arequipa - La Ciudad Blanca</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/c24783fa/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/c24783fa/</id>
    <published>2020-01-28T22:31:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-31T20:04:10.148Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Arequipa, known as the white city and the most beautiful city in Peru. It was true! One of my favorite cities in my South America trip, not only for its beautiful city but also for its surrounding nature. I highly recommend you put it on your travel itinerary! If you ever visit Arequipa, you have to check out <strong>Salinas y Aguada Blanca National Reserve</strong>!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1nIf_NQu-qS5OOSBJcGK2_9lUWkl_H7H8"><a id="more"></a><h1 id="Arequipa-Journey-Restarted"><a href="#Arequipa-Journey-Restarted" class="headerlink" title="Arequipa - Journey Restarted"></a>Arequipa - Journey Restarted</h1><p>Arequipa was not on my original travel itinerary. It came cross to my mind during my ‘real-time’ travel planning in Lima. Based on Google, it was claimed to be the most beautiful city in Peru. Whenever I saw superlative adjectives for a place, I have to check it out. So after resting in normal life in Lima for almost a week, I decided to continue my real journey in South America. Yes, no more computer work, grocery shopping, hanging out with friends and convenient city life! I need to TRAVEL!</p><p>If you never heard of Arequipa before, it is the second largest city in Peru and surrounded by three handsome volcanos. One can easily find good restaurants, bars and cafes to chill, visit various museums in the city or choose to go for outdoor adventures like multiple hiking in Colca canyon, day tours in the national parks, white river rafting etc. Trust me, just come to Arequipa, it has almost  everything you want (just not that famous like Machu Picchu).</p><p>Let’s start with what you can do in the city.</p><h2 id="Plaza-de-Armas"><a href="#Plaza-de-Armas" class="headerlink" title="Plaza de Armas"></a>Plaza de Armas</h2><p>Undoublably the most beautiful plaza in Peru or you can say in South America. I was stunned when I saw it!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1QJ8W7fGJx5E6H12Y8W4U-J0Z6hYPce9l"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZtcrNt5GW1qpRlKR5uWC6kj6ZN1AeLlc"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1_uRC87mBTRPBmMgtblQB-6VZ4G5SMP_U"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Cu5_sbla-dOuwlWiZ7taz1SnpkpjFEC2"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1-527ejZkX0iueb4mZHSUs64xKpH8mMEK"><h2 id="Free-City-Walking-Tour"><a href="#Free-City-Walking-Tour" class="headerlink" title="Free City Walking Tour"></a>Free City Walking Tour</h2><p>In most of the South America large cities, you will find free city walking tour. It says FREE but actually the walking tour is tip-based. I found it good for travelers to get to know the history, culture of the city in a nutshell. With the tour guide, we started from Plaza de Armas, then visited hidden pretty neighborhoods, the traditional San Camilo Market, stopped at several churches and museums for general information. </p><p>Sample stops of my walking tour.</p><p>A historical tiny neighborhood. There we also learnt the Christian-Inca green cross with combinations of symbols from two religions.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1cv6rHXa0y67DigKTi2eBtOkkFgsafLwL"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1z321o059J4wR6XWryMBBtalvVAfObvqc"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1E_4rX72ndYJiDXJdZE_6At7fQ8ymucCN"><p><strong>San Camilo Market</strong></p><p>Like most of the Peruvian cities, there is a local market close to the Plaza de Armas. San Camilo Market is the most authentic market you will find in Arequipa. You will find food courts, butchers, local spices, fruit stalls. </p><p>Remember the renowned French engineer Gustave Eiffel? The buildings and roofs were designed by him. Not sure why there are so many his works in Peru. Yes, you will find his design in Cusco as well.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1O1tLBT4ZIi_Q747iu_iYw92V9FNBobe2"><p>Peru is the country for POTATOS. Guess how many kinds of potato can be found in Peru? Over <strong>3,200</strong>?! You may need to spend your lifetime to try them all! To be honest, I cannot tell too much differences among them…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1-7aTBBLDbhbpj2AxRgBoa7ogVyVmw71p"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZZtbv9SlopcE-hHfbFb6tzc7J_jdBc9N"><p>Another interesting thing you can find in the market is the witch’s stands, where you can find Inca medicines from herbs and animals…The witches are also known to help you to keep your love relationships magically. You are welcomed to consult your problems there. For me, it is a pass :) </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1k4-eh3KxXJ6ESh2qWpHLJnAkHluPzbs6"><p><strong>Queso Helado (Cheese Ice cream)</strong></p><p>Suggested by our tour guide, the best queso helado place in Arequipa. It is DELICIOSO!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1e75Ez8t272YVniDGVWInkX5TRtnJmQ3J"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1jHE8vn4OvASRh6Ecufy_yJRT6T1ZlGPw"><h2 id="Santa-Catalina-Monastery"><a href="#Santa-Catalina-Monastery" class="headerlink" title="Santa Catalina Monastery"></a>Santa Catalina Monastery</h2><p><em>Santa Catalina is one of the most impressive colonial religious buildings in Peru. The large convent is a ‘city within a city,’ covering over 20,246 square meters (218,000 square feet) and preserving the characteristics of 16th and 18th centuries, with narrow twisting streets, tidy plazas, colorful courtyards, and simple living quarters with Spanish names like Córdova, Sevilla, and Toledo. The delicate pastel colors of the buildings contrast with bright flowers, period furnishings, and religious art making it the <strong>picture-perfect</strong> place to explore some of the history of Arequipa.</em></p><p>But Santa Catalina is actually a nunnery guarded by imposing high walls. The nuns entered the monastery would live their whole life and even buried inside. For religious reasons I understand this but to me it sounds like a prison. Put my personal feelings aside, the monastery shows a masterpiece of colonial architectural design and many people claim that you can get best portrait photography there.</p><p><strong>Ticket Price: 12.5 USD/ 40 soles (yes, a little bit pricy)</strong></p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1iZ-MTI7ZC3RhMqB8qlzuPitadIkzyJE9"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZTOPbRwiNegDonBZZRG7H9uXWgtzIyu6"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=17Bh2rDpJGQMkpC7rm-FNkAENzhf3rlHL"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1KBacFBgYJHRcTAj6zs7IFe0r1WRDCslO"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1JD2Hz6KRfcD9H9-BU8gIhK2iO7bZcHRZ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bQiJ1bDX4M5rmrF5wlujn3rODI9L9Xd4"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1F45d7A6Mwjyc6rIMDmvoayUQ7e9hA1eG"><p><strong>Mandu Alpaca</strong></p><p>Located very close to Arequipa historical center,  Mandu Alpaca has a very small zoo, a gallery and a museum that you can learn the tradition, process and history of alpaca textile industry. </p><p>For those who have not seen alpacas and llamas, there is your chance to feed and pet them for FREE!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1lpfsJxswsE-KgShuFJeNfFX4sOd822pq"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1FmNAjAexnCVZKeIssW1ZxR0bBQn17L9_"><p>There is a museum that tells you the differences in animal fibers. The finest fiber is from Vicuna followed by alpaca. The expensive cashmere turns out to be the third.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZmXH3yfglH6pOuNIsxM0RZdDDX4McObi"><p>Also, there you can find traditional hand-made rugs.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Hvql5p6o82A2E12arueRdLgW-FM2Mzee"><h2 id="Selina-Arequipa"><a href="#Selina-Arequipa" class="headerlink" title="Selina Arequipa"></a>Selina Arequipa</h2><p>Selina again! Why this hostel can be listed as one of my tourist spot in Arequipa? It is the most beautiful Selina among all I stayed and I rested there for two days without touring at all in Arequipa. Yes, one day after my two-day hiking tour in Colca Canyon. I can chill out all day long in its garden or by the pool side.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1glnV2vFbLOUst7JiPXlB29sffYLq5IX_"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1fw0TjQDIrlMBhuT9FCvnDCEfgoZ37Gyd"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=11puibDN9_mg2ZRdQQNnjDwonNeExRFWc"><h2 id="Other-Places-inside-Arequipa-City"><a href="#Other-Places-inside-Arequipa-City" class="headerlink" title="Other Places inside Arequipa City"></a>Other Places inside Arequipa City</h2><ul><li>Yanahuara District - for its panorama view of the city and the white buildings, colonial-era churches and leafy plazas. Not that special compared to the central district in my opinion.</li><li>Museo Santuarios Andinos - for the best-preserved of all the Inca mummies - a ice-preserved girl sacrifice named Junita. While being one of the most popular museums in Arequipa, I did not go there. No courage and interest to see dead human bodies…</li></ul><h1 id="Colca-Canyon"><a href="#Colca-Canyon" class="headerlink" title="Colca Canyon"></a>Colca Canyon</h1><p>Colca canyon is listed as a must-go place if you are in Arequipa and the second most visited place in Peru (first being the Machu Picchu). It is also known as the second deepest canyon in the world and best place to spot the Andean Condor! Information collected, how come I would miss this spot on my South American adventure? I need to conquer it, right? So I signed up on a two-day hiking tour.</p><p>Friends, especially friends from the Grand Canyon State, no need to conquer it through hiking… a touristic one-day bus ride is probably enough if you really want to go. Or you can make your decision based on my hiking experience.</p><p>My tour agency told me it would be an easy hike with all food and lodge (not a tent) organized.  All I need was a daypack for water, some exchange cloth and swimming suit for the pool in the lodge and the outdoor hot spring for the second day. Trekking difficulty was anything from EASY! It almost destroyed my confidence in outdoor activities…</p><p>The two-day hiking tour started at hostel pickup at 3 a.m. After 3.5 bus ride, we arrived for breakfast at Chivay town around 7 a.m.</p><p>Before embarking on our trek, we made a stop at Cruz Del Condor to observe the world’s largest flying birds with over 3 meter wing span in action. That was stunning!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1HL-UcXCYmZ4_8sJqlltJfcSlRkSkOnqD"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=16-XLoO0JM6SIvFek-tWG-TNQ6Jewvsxe"><p>Then the minivan left our group at the trailhead with a nearby volcano in action. Yes, the white thing far way was not cloud but the smoke from an erupting  volcano.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1-cFB-UXLgGmG7GgKaLZHM6-o15RlOXiF"><p>We soon started our first leg of trekking at approximately 3300 meters in altitude. It was a three-hour decent of 1200 meters on loose gravel with soaring temperature under direct sun!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1UUaXLY01NFwzUgtdv5MEGRxo5iyv6oPg"><p>The first two hours went OK. But gradually, I was not able to keep up with the group. Fine, I admit I was the oldest in our group (they asked you to put your ID and age on a sheet before the trekking) but I thought really I was grouped with professional mountain climbers! Also I was in my new pair of hiking shoes which was killing me. Just in two hours, I had five blisters on my feet and one blood-fed toe nail… My guide was not helping but kept pushing me to speed up saying that we are behind the schedule. Which was not that true. Before we started, we were told time-stamps of the breakpoints. We arrived lunch place on-time! Remember, I was in a group of ‘professionals’. This made me felt like a slow-paced mid-school student who constantly being called in front of your classmates by your teacher while you were trying your best to keep up with your peers.</p><p>Anyway, we had our bird-sized lunch at lunch stop, probably 5 thumb-nail sized llama meet with little veggies and rice. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=19X-yqiB51eYcjMXSEZXVHRaQw2ht77hs"><p>Soon after lunch, we continued our way to the village for the night going up and down the canyon, crossing villages and rivers. The oasis with swimming pools were our destination for day-one, which was lovely. After   another 3-hours hiking we arrived Oasis de Sangalle.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1iCY-6n1bHA-83tts9SU1TRPLKynIXtt_"><p>So day one was completed after 13 km hiking total descending of 1500 meters before sunset at around 6pm. The lodge was basic but the swimming pools were nice. However, I was too exhausted to try the pool.  Dinner was provided at 8:30pm even worse than lunch, only kid-size pasta with tomato sauce and flakes of cheese. That was the only protein I had for dinner after almost seven hours hiking! </p><p>After the dinner, we were told about the schedule for the second day:</p><p>4:30 am - start trekking</p><p>8:00 am - reach the top</p><p>8:30 am - breakfast</p><p>9:30 am - bus pickup</p><p>Again, the guide emphasized the importance of sticking to the time since bus would not wait for us…I only had a nap on that night, since we finished our dinner really late at around 9:30pm. With the most two active group members assigned to my room, I was not able to sleep until 11:30pm. No matter what happened, we gathered as a group in the cold and dark morning of the second day at 4:30 am. Our guide again ‘kindly’ asked me to consider taking a mule up. I nodded and started the last leg of the trek. This part is the most challenging since the trail has only one direction that is up, up and up (elevation gain of about 1500 meters) in 3.5 hours. Without any doubt, I was soon left behind which was OK and I prefer to ‘climb’ in my own pace without my guide pushing me all the time. But actually, I was not alone. There were people along the trail hiking in normal to slow speeds. But soon I met a group of guides at one of the breakpoints. ‘Lan, you are too slow. You should take the mule up and I already checked they only had two mules left! We are not going to wait you at the top!’ my guide shouted. This made me pissed off and got really angry! I was on the move all the time with only water break and there lots of people from other groups behind me. I would like to shout back to him, but I was out of my breath. So I fought back, ‘I am here to conquer the trail not for a mule ride. If I would be late, you do not need to wait for me and I would find my way back on my own’.  I don’t want to be rude, but being polite sometimes does not work. I left the guides behind and slowly climbed up. Magically since then, my guide changed his attitude and kept moving with the ‘turtles group’ as all other guides did! Finally, I made it to the top at 8:05 am on foot!</p><p>After 10 minutes rest, our group continued walking to the village for breakfast. Yes, another 20-minute walk to breakfast place?! At least this time was on the flat surface. The guide told the group, we would have fried eggs for breakfast, so let’s go! I do not know what made eggs so special like caviar in South America, but eggs are my favorite protein source even now I am back in the U.S. You can try to have veggies only for several days, and then have a boiled egg. The taste will make you feel in heaven!</p><p>After the breakfast, finally the highlight of the 2-day Colca canyon trekking tour, the outdoor hot spring! Remember we are in the volcano area? Another erupting volcano near the spa. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1jJMe5kHXFFMI7Hlj4oCCjXzRrthEEi2j"><p>The only downside about the hot spring is that it only have very basic facilities and pools are not that clean. With this beautiful surroundings and springs from the volcano, Peruvian people maybe you can borrow some ideas from the Japanese?</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1KhB6AKqHG0IHybr4I082yIfGnTnyzh1f"><h2 id="Colca-Canyon-Summary"><a href="#Colca-Canyon-Summary" class="headerlink" title="Colca Canyon Summary"></a>Colca Canyon Summary</h2><p>Based on the information from Google, Colca Canyon ranks the second deepest canyon in the world. But our guide told us it is actually the forth deepest. The first and second are in China and the third is Grand Canyon. I am Chinese and lived in the Grand Canyon State for over 3 years. I’d say, trekking in Colca Canyon is not worth the pain. The geographic landscapes are not as stunning as Grand Canyon! I maybe biased, for me, Arizona and Utah are way better than it! </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1FZp7B23FKUkQM3AqBTVISCPR_pJZEwjT"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1MziUwqHCQ4wQRMEu4PYBfwTrgLtNFfs-"><p>The cost of the 2-day Colca Canyon trekking tour:</p><ul><li>Guided tour: 90  soles</li><li>Colca Canyon National Park entrance ticket: 70 soles</li><li>2-day lunch (not included in the tour): 30 soles</li><li>Hot Spring (not included in the tour): 15 soles</li></ul><h1 id="Salinas-y-Aguada-Blanca-National-Reserve"><a href="#Salinas-y-Aguada-Blanca-National-Reserve" class="headerlink" title="Salinas y Aguada Blanca National Reserve"></a>Salinas y Aguada Blanca National Reserve</h1><p>I was a little bit disappointed after the Colca Canyon tour until my visit to Salinas National Reserve. It was a huge WOW to me! Its landscapes are unique and stunning! Also this place was recently open to public in 2019 and there are few people. For the day I went, there were only two groups, eight people in total in the park. You own the park! The national park is home to many wild animals like vicunas, pumas, flamingos, wild birds etc. Also not one, not two but tons of llamas and alpacas!</p><p>Words are not enough to describe its beauty. Let’s prove it by pictures. The day I went was cloudy and raining. It would be thousands times better in a sunny day.  </p><p>The landscapes:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1L0mptosGjg4eX6N137Fw60KKMUOQIqGQ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1-SyV7YKb0sYYHlm9nj4bIvN2i5OZ9sdH"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Nrw5PENpxol6li66dQ0BFxHDCCMhD218"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1MLmaFEWkYjitAgL0GklvKE1LZHBxBNrF"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1b9L3_k2M0M9fR8805Xo_QezjLBd-PnjC"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=160ODgGIjiqBxBVjSXMD8mO9wK38ca4ON"><p>A group of vicunas relaxing on the ‘salt flat’. It is actually not salt but some white chemicals which I don’t remember. Sorry, my poor Spanish.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1c_y0a94xiAQyPnmh7ExaCfMNJJGtsMLC"><p>Now the nature in action and proof of puma existence. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1qPoAGLh8muK-YUA6zPMW_741Gy5wLZar"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1S6xZJxvWlD70z2fEt5kyTG96m9ORIXT7"><p>I observed many wild birds, but my fixed 50mm lens failed to capture them in far distances. Only had these two photos to show you the number of birds in the park.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dyizOgDrYhmDsEU8iH-Yv4OIdcWDKcBN"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1rqmjd9enoVgHvDOR1dG9PcC6DPTZdA5X"><p>Lastly, tons of llamas and alpacas. This tour will make you not fooled or flock to one or two llamas in the rest of your South American trip.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1UOa5q1aXn0gy5vjJZcGV2CBIVNSjB2fT"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1_tfuWN4O51lK3PeBL98jaOvm-yGHSc9i"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1H-244QwQmvcy1S_4sUM4pjbC5F6NY5u_"><p><strong>The cost of this one-day tour is only 95 soles including everything and 1 breakfast and 1 lunch.</strong></p><h1 id="Cuisine-in-Arequipa"><a href="#Cuisine-in-Arequipa" class="headerlink" title="Cuisine in Arequipa"></a>Cuisine in Arequipa</h1><p>Over and over again, I need to emphasize that the Peruvian food is the best among all South American counties I visited (Argentina being the second, sorry, Peru wins for its diversity in food.) There are traditional Peruvian dishes that probably you will only find in Arequipa. </p><p>Rocotos Rellenos (stuffed chili pepper with meat and cheese) and llama meat plate. Buffet lunch costed 30 soles at 2-day Colca Canyon trekking tour:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Nt8J6Xj0LYPNm7RZsN19OILolAGinBLp"><p>Chupe de Camarones (Arequipeno River Shrimp Soup) at <a href="https://www.victoriaarequipa.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Restaurant Victoria</a>. Cost: 50 soles.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=18mnyXSFQIbnLTSOJh5XjmJyKWepvSfMQ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1PnxA9HFlM2UlpKyDqL_Xr2trbFurC5w4"><p>Beef stew with local black corn wine at <a href="https://www.facebook.com/labenitadelosclaustros/?rf=2418517484831510" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">La Benita</a>, my favorite restaurant in Arequipa. Cost: 30 soles!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1bSs-3nGzcEDcxqmnocF0Q_Lq5v0TjRzY"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1TjesyZnip3pBSfNp51iKlfd9-D94YR4p"><p>Alpaca steak grilled on a hot stone with live Peruvian music! Cost: 45 soles.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1D0LTyWqIzTMOoBeRCExvApv1Fd8_E08E"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1blumw9NQsEvli6KQ9jLHJmcwa0alHx3u"><p>Fried river trout and beef shank soup, included in the Salinas Reserva tour.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1uyd-Z5DgXf1BdNSS3PLJqM6CiDe6faFP"><p>Street tamel for 2 soles.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1dSV7y7V1OTNkcag18C-h7ZLFYQj5McPX"><h1 id="Log"><a href="#Log" class="headerlink" title="Log"></a>Log</h1><p>Wonderful Arequipa stay from September 26 to October 3, 2019.</p><p>Next stop: Cusco (Overnight bus to Cusco at 20:30, Oct. 3, 2019)</p><p><em>This post was published at Phoenix on January 31, 2020.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Arequipa, known as the white city and the most beautiful city in Peru. It was true! One of my favorite cities in my South America trip, not only for its beautiful city but also for its surrounding nature. I highly recommend you put it on your travel itinerary! If you ever visit Arequipa, you have to check out &lt;strong&gt;Salinas y Aguada Blanca National Reserve&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1nIf_NQu-qS5OOSBJcGK2_9lUWkl_H7H8&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Arequipa" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Arequipa/"/>
    
      <category term="Peru" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Peru/"/>
    
      <category term="The white City" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/The-white-City/"/>
    
      <category term="Colca Canyon" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Colca-Canyon/"/>
    
      <category term="Salinas y Aguada Blanca National Reserve" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Salinas-y-Aguada-Blanca-National-Reserve/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>limaMiraflores</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/e6bb6b3c/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/e6bb6b3c/</id>
    <published>2020-01-27T19:53:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-28T22:26:21.250Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lima take 2! This time it made me feel like coming back home. OK, I have to admit I travel for nature, local people, and native cultures but every time I stopped by a large city, it made me smile! You will soon see my deep love for Santiago and Buenos Aires, and not that deep love for La Paz…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1wJ24LMhR-dtAHlkVo_qAUtAGsDA1U0_J"><a id="more"></a><h1 id="The-Pro-Airport-Ground-Transportation"><a href="#The-Pro-Airport-Ground-Transportation" class="headerlink" title="The Pro Airport Ground Transportation"></a>The Pro Airport Ground Transportation</h1><p>My flight from Iquitos was delayed for 1.5hrs and I arrived Lima at 2am in the morning. My first hostel in South America, was 1900 Backpackers in Lima central district. It was very nice and staff were welcoming. But for my second stay I would like to explore the famous trendy Miraflores district in Lima. For your information, there is <a href="https://www.airportexpresslima.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">airport shuttle</a> connects you between the airport and Miraflores district. But it only runs between 7am to 12am. The only choice for me was the taxi to go to downtown. Back in August 20, I connected 1900 Backpackers hostel for a private airport pickup for 20 USD which is the standard cost for hotel pickup. After one month travel in Peru, I think it is way too expensive. So I decided to find a taxi on my own. Please note, Jorge Chavez International airport is located next to main street, it only takes you 5 minutes until you can find local buses or cabs. While some people may tell you it is unsafe to do that, I think it was fine. So I carried 20+kgs of my backpacks and walked to the main street and very soon I was able to find a taxi and negotiated for 20 soles to Miraflores. Did you see the word ‘negotiated’? Yes, I was able to speak some Spanish words and was very proud of myself for this!</p><p>For a side note, the Chinese brand Huawei is so popular in South America, it has advertisement broads in almost all South American airports, airplanes and major cities. I was even ‘blamed’ by a tour guide (in San Pedro de Atacama Chile) for not having Huaiwei cell phone as being a Chinese since she was waiting for the latest Huaiwei model to show us how to take a photo of the moon through a telescope…Sorry, I know Huawei is awesome but I have my love of Nokia…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1IXkanARUOn0R5LYlfMFSeN69LM3AApgh"><p>The same applies for Chinese cigarettes like Zhonghua and Double Happiness, although Chinese cigarettes were not easily found in convenient stores.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Q3ImkfukF3tFSOkBzbZuZXZRPLyDPuyu"><h1 id="My-Private-Tour-Guide-Cynthia"><a href="#My-Private-Tour-Guide-Cynthia" class="headerlink" title="My Private Tour Guide - Cynthia"></a>My Private Tour Guide - Cynthia</h1><p>Before I start to talk about my second tour in Lima, I have to say a big THANK YOU to my local friend Cynthia. Cynthia has a warm heart for helping people out. When I was struggling to figure out the price for a mini van to Gocta waterfall at the bus terminal in Chachapoyas, as an English teacher, Cynthia came to me for help. Yes, she was the one who provided me the non-touristic hiking trail for the exhausting 8-hour adventure in Peruvian Andes. So on the bumpy drive to Gocta, we chatted along the way. It turned out that she lives in Lima and once she knew I would re-visit Lima she gave me her WhatsApp account and asked me to contact her when I came back to Lima. I sent her a message on the second day of my arrival just wanted to ask for a local good shopping mall so that I could buy a new pair of hiking shoes. To my surprise, she kindly said that she would take me tour Lima from a local’s perspective. It was not a one-day tour. She met me on a Sunday and then she took me to different places since that day after her work 3-days in a roll. I think if I would stay in Lima longer, she would even take me to nearby mountain for a weekend-hiking.</p><p>With Cynthia, I was able to take public transport visited various neighborhoods, famous Jockey shopping mall, tried several great local restaurants. Here is my lovely Peruvian friend, Cynthia (she gave me the approval for posting her picture in my blog)!</p> <img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=16B9J6ZDeuCWVlGxzi0qy3pHfvGb4UGrC"><h2 id="Barranco-and-Chorrillos-Districts"><a href="#Barranco-and-Chorrillos-Districts" class="headerlink" title="Barranco and Chorrillos Districts"></a>Barranco and Chorrillos Districts</h2><p>On our first day of city tour, Cynthia took me to Barranco district known as the SoHo of Lima, Peru. There are plenty of things to do in Barranco; it is full of renowned art galleries, cute boutiques and trendy coffee shops, that were once colonial mansions of Lima’s elite. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1nbEBXeQoNOV_PZnvwXErnGgW6imIT8P9"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1T0OwdtQMUtiUWxBrUnwuRghpZ_FfIKCY"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZFd-9kbrGsdBEM9n0VowyVQGPKsDT1Lu"><p>We were luckily picked interviewed by a research group from University of San Martin de Porres for the traveling experience in Lima. I was on local TV! </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1S2ZXUWebrkZ421e5VIZ4ynOrmn24pXer"><p>The Barranco neighborhood also happens to be situated along the costal cliffs overlooking the Pacific Ocean. We walked along the costal boulevard and hit Chorrillos district. There was nothing too much to visit Chorrillos but Cynthia’s school was located there and it was on our way to get the public bus back to Lima downtown.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1wJ24LMhR-dtAHlkVo_qAUtAGsDA1U0_J"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1VvLj0GKxGQnEm2ylI6io5xNEOgkX17ew"><h2 id="Magic-Water-Tour-Park-of-the-Reserve"><a href="#Magic-Water-Tour-Park-of-the-Reserve" class="headerlink" title="Magic Water Tour - Park of the Reserve"></a>Magic Water Tour - Park of the Reserve</h2><p>If time allows during your stay in Lima, I highly recommend you to check out Park of the Reserve.  For a price of 4 soles, you can watch the water and light show there. Please check the website for its show time. </p><p>The park actually locates in Lima central district. However, during my first stay, the park was closed for some special event. I was not very interested in the water show, again I was in South America for nature! But Cynthia highly recommended me for a visit. So one day after her work, she took me there. It turned out to be a wonderful experience. While the show is only for half an hour, the park is huge with various fountains lit up at night and one can easily spend 2-3 hours for the visit.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=10PaUTeEdd-VyjMbqvXrbrFTTbsSQh75m"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1XAIlThUJAzbUrzeHT7KH_sv0an1PXKmN"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Zm1sae7Bi_-RLOn_eNZOmWUR0MClFXaQ"><h2 id="Jockey-Plaza"><a href="#Jockey-Plaza" class="headerlink" title="Jockey Plaza"></a>Jockey Plaza</h2><p>Jockey Plaza is probably one of the biggest shopping center in Lima. My old Northface hiking shoes were broken in Gocta hiking trail and I was desperately in need for a new pair of hiking shoes for many future hiking trails to be conquered. Cynthia took me shopping around in central Lima district, and Miraflores. Those mini shopping stops all failed due to the two reasons. One was that I need a trustworthy brand and the second and most importantly was that I am OVER the average size for people in South America…the average height for women is 155cm (5’1 feet) and 165cm (5’5 feet) and I am 178cm (5’10)? So our last resort was Jockey Plaza. There is nothing to much to say about Jockey Plaza, it just like most malls in the U.S. But we went there on a weekday after Cynthia’s work. Before we set off, she told me it was really close by. That night, we started by an express bus by waiting in line to purchase the bus ticket for about 15min then got into the station waiting line for another 20min to get on the express bus. Check out the waiting lines on the freeway cross bridge, they were all waiting to get in! The in-vehicle time was only 20 minutes since they have designated bus lanes on the freeway. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1j5el5H221UjQzM_OkHlu5PtM3oJDc6cr"><p>Do you think that’s it? NO, our journey continued with a 20-minute walking transfer leg to catch another crazily crowded local bus. The conductor was hanging out of the bus for most of the time so that the bus could fit more people. So after two hours, we arrived Jockey Plaza. Cynthia told me this was normal for traveling in the peak hour, what a city life!</p><p>Jockey Plaza carries many U.S. and European brands and even the layout and design is very much like shopping centers in the U.S. Unless you need to re-stock your gears, you probably don’t need to go there.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=13xTuM7Axe8MNhEpcMVJsQDNF4OSGo_Xr"><p>Luckily there were several good outdoor brands, like Northface, Summon, Merrell and Patagonia etc. The prices were much higher compared to U.S…so I ended up with one of the cheapest choice for Merrell and paid approx.. 120 USD… The most expensive item I bought in South America. My options have to be with Gore-Tex and here I have one recommendation for all of you. Please pay the higher price for Gore-Tex products especially for your hiking shoes. You will not regret! </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Edo0obrxfckgYnN1Bs0Q5172BnQh7WYn"><h1 id="Life-in-Miraflores"><a href="#Life-in-Miraflores" class="headerlink" title="Life in Miraflores"></a>Life in Miraflores</h1><p>My second stay in Lima or maybe I should say in Miraflores made me feel like home. The Miraflores district is very very nice for living. I thought I could live there forever. One of the most important reason for this was that I found my beloved hostel chain brand <a href="https://www.selina.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Selina</a>! I highly recommend everyone to try it out. Selina has hostels all over the world and it is rapidly growing. For the moment, its main market is in South America and Central America.</p><h2 id="Mi-Amour-Selina"><a href="#Mi-Amour-Selina" class="headerlink" title="Mi Amour - Selina"></a>Mi Amour - Selina</h2><p>Here let me express my love for a hostel <a href="https://www.selina.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Selina</a>~ Selina Miraflores was the first Selina hostel I stayed and from day 1 I fell in love with Selina. From then on, for every city I passed, as long as there is Selina, I had no hesitation to stay there. So for my 4+ months travel, I believed I stayed in different Selina hostels for approximately 30 days! So what make it so special (observations made based on Selina in Lima, Arequipa, Cusco, La Paz, and Buenos Aires):</p><ul><li>All locations are always in trendy districts and walking distance to almost everything you need</li><li>All facilities are GREAT even with U.S. and European standard.</li><li>All rooms are clean, beds are comfy with curtains, showers are SUPER hot with sometimes too strong water pressure</li><li>Internets are always SUPER SUPER fast</li><li>Always equipped with GREAT common kitchens, nice café and bar</li><li>It offers very good co-work space in almost every Selina locations with an extra fee though. You may not believe, I have used the co-work spaces at four out of six Selina I have stayed. Decorations and space sizes may differ but they were all gorgeously designed. Trust me, you will love to work there.</li></ul><p>The best Selina hostel I stay is the one in Arequipa (I will have another section for Selina Arequipa) and the best co-work space is in Lima!</p><p>Just for a glance, Selina Miraflores café and breakfast: </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=10_31oq90SeszK-1qs8wA0UrSrZUWaX8L"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=12ANNEp41wHgryYBue2OkUUe6BFOo7GoE"><p>My favorite Selina Co-Work space in Lima. All co-work spaces came with a simple kitchen and this one even has a gym and a indoor spa pool?! </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1snFDFtfGJsYaESBd-OIRY17ZK2HZ8RrW"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1mENVL1peW17yHLjXDvD3j4-s4EcLPWs6"><h2 id="My-Daily-Routine-in-Miraflores"><a href="#My-Daily-Routine-in-Miraflores" class="headerlink" title="My Daily Routine in Miraflores"></a>My Daily Routine in Miraflores</h2><p>As said, Selina always has a GREAT common kitchen and just across the street there was a supermarket. So For most of the days, I cooked my own meals. My days started at 8 am with fresh juices and breakfast prepared in the common kitchen. Then I headed to the co-work space working on travel plans and my blog (yes, I did not upload lots of posts in real time, but I did try hard to do so). In the late afternoon, either I went for grocery shopping or walked around the parks, churches, stores. For most of the nights, Cynthia would come and we may have some evening tours in Lima. What a wonderful life! </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1pmUghdPzziXRYCVeu64GwNCvPOfyoKc_"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1fs1flPa0AWrktXVtVALIRlpWLDXM2tWZ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1FwIH9g8DqZvVhgSfIALQ_U9de2JBozSH"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1KtSlexJF-Iv88UTjYRunD-Ilo2VrMgh7"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1MnuKerK6nlqjrf-w4XbJqeX0ecnnYSZR"><h1 id="The-Food"><a href="#The-Food" class="headerlink" title="The Food"></a>The Food</h1><p>As I said, I cooked most of my own meals in Selina. Friends, Lima is famous for its award-wining and Michelin restaurants. Also, in my opinion, Peru has the best food in general. But remember, I was just a backpacker with limited budget and NO decent outfit for luxury restaurants. If you are interested in high-end restaurants, I believe you can easily find a long list from Google. If budget allows, you may want to try one or two. I heard that the average price per person can go up to 80-100 USD for dinner…</p><p>The one I can really recommend is <a href="http://restaurantecordano.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Restaurante Cordano</a> located near Plaza de Armas. I had the best beef tongue stew (38 soles) there and they also provide a long list of typical Peruvian dishes. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1jVLIaPmQ0LqNI1B54NsuCfM4lzg7hh9T"><p>Then some failures in trying not that cheap but not expensive Sushi restaurant. Do not go for cheap Sushi places at all in South America unless you want to have an adventure tasting ever known sushi rolls with ingredients in my opinion should never appear in sushi. I failed several times in all contraries I visited. But this Sushi restaurant has a very unique ordering system so that even you don’t know Spanish, there would not be any problem. You don’t even need to talk to your waitress. But look at their deserts menu, lemon pie sushi, chocolate sushi etc! This dinner was 51 soles for all-you-can-eat sushi.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1zBWhjNyq9iLBMSUxXZO1x_witGvfpF5I"><p>Then the tourist restaurant failure. Restaurant suggested by Cynthia was closed so we just went to some random restaurant nearby and turned out to be not that good. But the dishes we ordered were typical Peruvian food. I believe if you find the right restaurants, those two dishes should be very delicious.</p><p>Verde Arroz con Pollo (green rice with chicken) - 30 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1wyPTjwH9gaWOGjLQM5KQOaZ-Jy_R7pnh"><p>Jalea de Mariscos (Peruvian fried seafood) - 30 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1-va8ZUDKmns0-2JHgW2pk4ASkEqNcI1t"><p>Now time to show off my cooking technique!</p><p>Typical continental breakfast at Selina:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1DGpmyvtDZObm2WoyZKN0MydLEtWshUME"><p>Korean style breakfast with rice soup and fried egg:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ov0vd-JsnCy97YDdc-hBQp3y4n413-XN"><p>Dinner cooked for Cynthia - French Moules Marinieres</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=18ebGmNQRE110yMQa7UT2Dti-hbls9Vgn"><p>And Chinese pork and veggie stir-fry dinner for one:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Qa8vrIqRf47GVJZmKIz3z8MP3cP5xQD_"><h1 id="Log"><a href="#Log" class="headerlink" title="Log"></a>Log</h1><p>Lima second stay from September 21 to September 26, 2019.</p><p>Next stop: Arequipa (Flight to Arequipa at 12:50, Sep. 26, 2019)</p><p><em>This post was published at Phoenix on January 28, 2020.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Lima take 2! This time it made me feel like coming back home. OK, I have to admit I travel for nature, local people, and native cultures but every time I stopped by a large city, it made me smile! You will soon see my deep love for Santiago and Buenos Aires, and not that deep love for La Paz…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1wJ24LMhR-dtAHlkVo_qAUtAGsDA1U0_J&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Peru" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Peru/"/>
    
      <category term="Lima" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Lima/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Lagunas-N-Iquitos</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/d1a93c4c/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/d1a93c4c/</id>
    <published>2020-01-22T20:01:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-28T22:26:04.655Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Amazon dawn to Civilization…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=16uF8kK1kSdLf3PckuaHd1i4_I2YfOjxU"><a id="more"></a><h1 id="Lagunas"><a href="#Lagunas" class="headerlink" title="Lagunas"></a>Lagunas</h1><p>Lagunas is just a tiny village along the Amazon river (Huallaga River quickly joins the Maranon river in its downstream. As Wiki says, the Maranon was the origin name the river). Still, my partner argues that I did NOT visit the real Amazon which is in Brazil. Here I need to state that Amazon’s origin is near Arequipa, Peru although its main stem named Amazon is in Brazil. I may not visit the most well-known part of the Amazon river, but dear the little creek I went is part of Amazon! Also for the record, there was an unfortunate huge Amazon fire in 2019 mainly in Brazil. </p><p>Back to the village, Lagunas, it has a port and about 1000 meter paved main road and that’s all…No cars found in this tiny village, the main transport modes are tuk-tuk and motorcycles. </p><p>The only port:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1FFR6bNy2AdIWTHbqxKjFBZF8tM0QCIiD"><p>The only paved road:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1kH1VnTq2w50mVV5YcLqzLinwjjYDLHl7"><p>And then, the rest of the village looks like this:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=133ycpts_EYBOWxydx8O08OTHNtlzKjdy"><p>The electricity only runs from 5AM-12PM and 5PM-12AM every day. If you want to take a nap in the afternoon, well, good luck with the humidity and the hotness without even a fan. I did not see any AC in the village.</p><p>For this reason, when I was dropped off to my hostel at 5PM on my last day of my Amazon tour, I decided to take the mid-night speed boat to the neares city, Iquitos on the same night…I have to admit that I did not have any real shower except the ones in the rain during my 11-day tour. Using a mixture of limited Spanish vacabular I learnt on my tour and Google Translate, I was able to use one of the room just for a shower for only 5 soles! It was not a shower but triple showers and took almost an hour. </p><p>After the shower, I went to the port to purchase the 10-hr boat ticket to Nauta. Yes, there was no boat directly goes to Iquitos. All boats go until Nauta and from there you need to find a 2-hour bus ride to Iquitos! The lady kindly wrote down, the boat arrives at 12AM and I have to arrive the port half an hour in advance.</p><p>So in the dark night, I carried all my backpacks and walked 1.7km to the port at 11:30PM. There was nothing open and nobody around. Luckily, there was one streetlight on at the port! However, I was happy that I would be in a city really soon! Actually, I was wrong, it really took me a while until I was able to embrace the civilization. A few minutes later, there came a guy with huge backpack. It was my Amazon Jungle friend, Amouri who said hundreds goodbye to me since the first night we met. The most recent farewell was in front of my hostel in about 6 hours ago and he told me he would wait at the port for a cargo boat to Iquitos. Anyway, it felt much better to have an accompany most importantly a passenger with the same boat ticket. Here was nobody and no waiting area at all! At 12AM, the light went off. Oh yes, there is no electricity from 12-5AM. But we were used to this after the Amazon tour. We found tables which were used for selling small stuffs during the day, and lay comfortably on them next to each other under moonlight hoping that eventually our boat would come and planning whatif the boat would never come. After about one hour, there was some sounds on the river and here it came the boat to civilization! The boat was 90% full and had terrible smell but we were so happy to get on!</p><p>The speed boat, inside-out, ps there is a WC in the boat. However, I only smelt it not using it. I don’t have the courage even to get close to it! To be honest, the nature toillet is so much better than you can imagine! It has no smell at all and you just smell the fresh nature!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=13d07mpaKgU4b93GvdfVkOQH9dMZ4raND"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1ZuqaFTrX2l76z3P_cmsFzPnkuAj5JZqA"><p>But the views of Amazan is amazing at dawn!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=16uF8kK1kSdLf3PckuaHd1i4_I2YfOjxU"><p>After almost 11-hour later, we reached Nauta finally.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=16xNSOUeDvD915rFA9jFJg3YVJX3iT7IJ"><p>After getting up the steep muddy ramp, Amouri found us a tuk-tuk to bus terminal and from there we started our final 2-hour bus ride to Iquitos.</p><h1 id="Iquitos"><a href="#Iquitos" class="headerlink" title="Iquitos"></a>Iquitos</h1><p>Iquitos is the largest city in the world which has NO road access. One can only get there by boat or plane. We finally arrived the city! Amouri said final goodbye to me in front of his hostel in Iquitos. He already purchased his flight ticket to Arequipa for the next day while I decided to take a rest in Iquitos for couple of days. With this luxury vacation plan, I checked in a hotel for a private with AC, bathroom and hot water! I can tell you now since I am writing this blog back home, it was the only time I checked in a hotel during my 4+ months trip in South America. The cost of the hotel was only 35 USD per night. Of course, if you want something more luxury, there is a Hillton Double Tree in Iquitos. Remember, I said, it is a CITY!</p><p>What is special in Iquitos? The city is the gateway to the jungle lodges and tribal villages of the northern Amazon and famous for its <strong>ayahuasca</strong> centers. Ayahuasca, also known as the tea, the vine, and la purga, is the drink used for spiritual and religious purposes by ancient Amazonian tribes. Nowadays, ayahuasca is becoming very popular in Europe and U.S. as a psychological medicine for its claimed many benefits. Based on my research on Google, the ayahuasca ceremony involves drinking the ‘tea’ then waiting for symptoms like vomiting, diarrhea, feelings of euphoria, strong visual and aduitory hallucinations, mind-altering psychedelic effects, fear and paranoia. Many people and some scentific researches claims the ayahuasca leads to positive, long-term, life-altering changes and may benefit health - particularly brain health. This sounds too magical and its effects really scare me away (doesn’t it have similar effects as drugs, I mean the bad ones?). This is definetely not the type of things I wanted to try. But for anybody who is interested, you can start your own detailed research on this and I really met people came from Europe to Peru for 3 months solely for some treatments with ayahuasca.</p><p>OK, I was not here for more Amazon jungles nor the magical drink. Let’s see what else it has.</p><h2 id="Belen-Market-and-Its-Floating-Village"><a href="#Belen-Market-and-Its-Floating-Village" class="headerlink" title="Belen Market and Its Floating Village"></a>Belen Market and Its Floating Village</h2><p>I put Iquitos on my itineray only because from there I can fly back to Lima easily and would like to see what is a city without road access. With this said, I had NO list of places to visit before I came here. Amouri recommended me to check Belen market out. ‘It is the largest  open maket and has everything you may think of from the jungle’. OK, so I went the chaotic and colorful market.</p> <img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1lrY8a-uu0tn0WQWGpKAAtqJlI6Xha4V4"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=12Wz34U0m6ankNdaSEMmlSxl9vvcTk9Ma"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1DS9RYwbgi8CNWT4Duqwwfki7nXaOSNTC"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Ak30-JR8LV6FWMqnAcaz-ItyDo-T5K2W"><p>Belen market is huge and chaotic ! It spreads about 20 blocks but far from the U.S. or European open market standards. Thousands live in teh overcrowded, bouyant shanty town, facing conditions of extreme poverty without adequate access to clean water, sanitation, or electricity. Its floating village is far from romantic Venice, with stinky river and gabbage all around. It is cheap (20 soles) to hire a canoe and a guide for a 2-hour private tour. But I really had on interest to do so.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Bc0A0piCrn4ZZGQuuxOfBECWu4TiYe1F"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1kGDTi5vC4VRPf87UwUnbUpm_qwyGuoBZ"><h2 id="Public-Bus-in-Iquitos"><a href="#Public-Bus-in-Iquitos" class="headerlink" title="Public Bus in Iquitos"></a>Public Bus in Iquitos</h2><p>The public buses in Iquitos in my opinion is a must try. Remember the city has no road access? Due to the shipping cost, only the engines of the buses were shipped to the city but the body were built in Iquitios using wood! All buses are colorful and unique! </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1C-E7WmviVIcejv0JHgcU6Gh5S_CtcIYJ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=10nGIsBSrni31SCeQ9hVJ715HdVLPUm7k"><p>You can also investigate on how to close the windows. I was struggling with that until a kind lady sitting behind me showed me the trick :)</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1oBd5vE6bdFaT8WfjY7tr08Ho_zDHf09q"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1NB-nffCkzIKHkW5xRqYZ1mt78X-rf90v"><h2 id="The-City"><a href="#The-City" class="headerlink" title="The City"></a>The City</h2><p>Again, I didn’t go to many tourist spots but just wandered around the city. </p><h3 id="The-Iron-House-and-Plaza-de-Armas"><a href="#The-Iron-House-and-Plaza-de-Armas" class="headerlink" title="The Iron House and Plaza de Armas"></a>The Iron House and Plaza de Armas</h3><p>Built towards the end of the 19th century, this historically significant iron residence is a living testament to the wealth amassed during the region’s rubber boom. Said to be the first pre-fabricated house in the Americas, the building was designed in Europe (some believe by Gustav Eiffel), shipped to Peru, and carried through the jungle by hand, piece by piece. I don’t know why Peruvian people love Gustav Eiffel, but later I found his design is widely spread out in Peru. Before I came to Peru, probabaly the only thing I knew about him was the Eiffel Tower. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=18i-eHSlbZC1KgWThK-epQwdrXRjJdLEM"><p>Then another Plaza de Armas in Peru!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1QTsLhs1DMqTCqiw6sgjxdm-VeQbxFCQ3"><h3 id="Boulevard-Tarapaca"><a href="#Boulevard-Tarapaca" class="headerlink" title="Boulevard Tarapaca"></a>Boulevard Tarapaca</h3><p>This is a boulevard along the Amazon river with some of the best scenary in the city. Aside from that, there are many bars and restaurants for you to relax and chill there. Remember, you are in a tropical city so I suggest you go there after 5-6 pm.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=13MAeyRvaCbSjsF4_cuDV-TPAPj8cMNnJ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1Dhc4MeCHr1uUqz_3luHhQiubnEAnAUGd"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1WZEFkeiVoBTvCBrT63EY0zgQ0fyjcdJs"><p>Lastly, the local favorate bar la Norche and the view of the Amazon river bank:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1iToMA2OypkpJjD4I5Ie_-dtemDNXhuiq"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1OPP1Eq4n8ml1XZ1sOTwAHiygGkHJaWVe"><h1 id="Local-Food"><a href="#Local-Food" class="headerlink" title="Local Food"></a>Local Food</h1><p>After my South American trip, Peruvian food ranked No.1 for its taste and variety. Also, it is very cheap!</p><h2 id="Lagunas-1"><a href="#Lagunas-1" class="headerlink" title="Lagunas"></a>Lagunas</h2><p>Fried chicken with pasta and rice lunch, 6 soles with drink and a soup</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1aXmI98gPxcvkfbRoMtyMbIzMx7hbXfKZ"><p>Local dinner, 13 soles, BBQ fish, grilled chicken and fried rice</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1DPz4L8jGW761Lyvwl0a-DdP8mWHmxi0h"><p>The grill</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1nMKsOCCVZZfzduCO_QtJZRkD7eiEW7_I"><h2 id="Iquitos-1"><a href="#Iquitos-1" class="headerlink" title="Iquitos"></a>Iquitos</h2><p>Caviche and drinks, 17 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=19UavMMo_im1bGjItc3mRv3At7_79zMK5"><p>Peruvian Pork Chop with salad and drink, 22 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1hg2XiWr_Qf_8wF8O_FAGJlXpbeXJv5SU"><p>1/4 Grilled Chicken plate for 19.5 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1KY-6FUB1LaTatTNO_2bgm5IFoZ2yZDKS"><p>Fried XX Amazon Fish with soup and drinks for 17 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?id=1NOWPbtHRdTF88CwsrPSmCboEmI6em0HO"><h1 id="Log"><a href="#Log" class="headerlink" title="Log"></a>Log</h1><p>Lagunas stay from September 6 to September 17, 2019.</p><p>Iquitos stay from September 18 to September 20, 2019.</p><p>Next stop: Lima (Flight to Lima at 22:55, Sep. 20, 2019)</p><p><em>This post was published at Phoenix on January 24, 2020.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The Amazon dawn to Civilization…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?id=16uF8kK1kSdLf3PckuaHd1i4_I2YfOjxU&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Peru" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Peru/"/>
    
      <category term="Lagunas" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Lagunas/"/>
    
      <category term="Iquitos" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Iquitos/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo-Edit Blog on Multiple Computers</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/1bde756e/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/1bde756e/</id>
    <published>2020-01-14T18:51:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-16T22:22:30.979Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Procrastination…I admit that I was back to my sweet home last year to be exact at midnight December 24, 2019 after 4+ months adventure in South America. Then I was on real do-nothing vacation first for couple of days followed by researching and planning my next Africa trip. Finally, I am back to update my blog…still before I can do that, I need to move the work to my desktop. Hopefully, this works. Let’s check out the first push from the desk top!</p><a id="more"></a><h1 id="The-Need-for-Working-on-Multiple-PCs"><a href="#The-Need-for-Working-on-Multiple-PCs" class="headerlink" title="The Need for Working on Multiple PCs"></a>The Need for Working on Multiple PCs</h1><p>You may say I am listing the excuses for not updating my blog in real-time during my travel. However, it was really difficult to find time between all the extreme hiking trails,  planning for my next stop, a decent table to put my laptop and most important WIFI connections many times.  Even if all the above conditions were met, I was just exhausted but to lay on my bed to have some rests…</p><p>Now I am back to home for a short break. Before my next adventure to Africa, I am determined to complete my travel trajectories in South America. Yes, step one is to find myself a better working environment which is a good computer desk with large monitor and a decent hard disk storage space! Dear friend, one suggestion, do be allured by cheaper price for a small SDD drive, you may pay higher price later. I was stupid for that to order my ultra book with only 128G several years ago. What I was thinking about?! What’s worse is the monster Windows 10, it has system update all the time and requires 10+ G for that?! Enough! I am moving to my desktop for Hexo blog.</p><h1 id="Implementation"><a href="#Implementation" class="headerlink" title="Implementation"></a>Implementation</h1><p>Long story in short, I prepared my desktop so that I can publish Hexo blog from my desktop. </p><p><strong>Step 1: Add Branch to Your Blog Repository</strong>  </p><p>On the local PC, in my case, my Dell laptop, go to the blog folder and Git Bash there and do the following:</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"># Blog Initialization</span><br><span class="line">$ git init  </span><br><span class="line"># Add new branch (name: backup)</span><br><span class="line">$ git checkout -b backup  </span><br><span class="line"># add files in the working directory to the staging area</span><br><span class="line">$ git add .  </span><br><span class="line"># commit your files</span><br><span class="line">$ git commit -m &quot;commit message&quot;  </span><br><span class="line"># add remote repository</span><br><span class="line">$ git remote set-url https://github.com/yourname/yourname.github.io.git</span><br><span class="line"># push the local to remote</span><br><span class="line">$ git push origin backup</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p><strong>Step 2: Prepare New PC</strong></p><p>On the new computer, i.e. my desktop do the following:</p><p>2.1 Install Git</p><p>2.2 Install Nodejs</p><p>2.3 Prepare the Blog</p><ul><li>​      Create a new folder for hexoBlog </li><li>​      Git Bash and do the following:</li></ul><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"># clone hexo blog branch to this working folder</span><br><span class="line">$ git clone -b backup https://github.com/yourname/yourname.github.io.git</span><br><span class="line"># enter yourname.github.io folder</span><br><span class="line">$ cd yourname.github.io</span><br><span class="line"># install hexo</span><br><span class="line">$ npm install hexo --save</span><br><span class="line"># install hexo command mode</span><br><span class="line">$ npm install hexo-cli -g</span><br><span class="line"># install all dependencies (according to package.json, this will automatically install previously installed dependencies)</span><br><span class="line">$ npm install</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>2.4 Add SSH Key</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"># Generate SSH key</span><br><span class="line">$ ssh-keygen -t rsa -C &quot;youremail@example.com&quot;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Then go to the .ssh folder (default: C:\Users\yourUserName\.ssh), open “id_rsa.pub” and copy all the contents in this file.</p><p>Now go to Github.com and log in. Under ‘Settings’\‘SSH and GPG keys’ add the SSH key (the contents copied from id_rsa.pub)</p><p>2.5 Add Remote Repository</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ git remote set-url  https://github.com/yourname/yourname.github.io.git</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>2.6 Add your theme</p><p>In this case, my theme is <code>next</code>(<a href="https://github.com/theme-next/hexo-theme-next" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://github.com/theme-next/hexo-theme-next</a>)</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ git clone https://github.com/theme-next/hexo-theme-next themes/next</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>2.7 Test it out</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo clean</span><br><span class="line">$ hexo g -d</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>2.8 Push anything new to the backup branch</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ git add .</span><br><span class="line">$ git commit -m &quot;commit-message&quot;</span><br><span class="line">$ git push origin backup</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>The reference link is here:</p><p><a href="https://liziczh.com/hexo-multimachine.html" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://liziczh.com/hexo-multimachine.html</a></p><h1 id="Issues"><a href="#Issues" class="headerlink" title="Issues"></a>Issues</h1><p>As always, there are some issues every time I implement something here :{</p><h2 id="Issue-1-git-push-failed"><a href="#Issue-1-git-push-failed" class="headerlink" title="Issue 1: git push failed"></a>Issue 1: git push failed</h2><p>As listed in 2.8, I want to push my new posts to the repository branch, using <code>git push origin backup</code>, ended up with fatal error no repository found…</p><p>Reason: I am using SSH key</p><p>Solution: set-url differently</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ git remote set-url origin git@github.com:yourName/yourName.github.io.git</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h2 id="Issue-2-All-custom-theme-lost"><a href="#Issue-2-All-custom-theme-lost" class="headerlink" title="Issue 2:  All custom theme lost"></a>Issue 2:  All custom theme lost</h2><p>For some reasons, when I push local hexoBlog folder from my laptop, the <code>themes</code> folder was not pushed. That is why I need to install the theme again. However, I made several custom changes to this theme which were all lost…</p><p>Simple Solution: copy the entire <code>themes/next</code> folder to desktop. </p><p>Yes, there are several approaches to push the themes folder to the repository. I tried some but nothing worked. To save time, just do the stupid and quick way. Otherwise, I will never get to update the real travel blog…</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Procrastination…I admit that I was back to my sweet home last year to be exact at midnight December 24, 2019 after 4+ months adventure in South America. Then I was on real do-nothing vacation first for couple of days followed by researching and planning my next Africa trip. Finally, I am back to update my blog…still before I can do that, I need to move the work to my desktop. Hopefully, this works. Let’s check out the first push from the desk top!&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="nerdyNotes" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/nerdyNotes/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>myAmazonTour - English</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/764cde41/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/764cde41/</id>
    <published>2019-10-13T19:55:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.477Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HLlBDWfakOJJYLCrlP7Vwj0XTMFd5PJq"><a id="more"></a><p>OK, after almost a month, here is the post on the English version of my Amazon jungle tour. I have been busy hiking and touring in Arequipa and Cusco. Not to mention, making tourist plans and preparing all documents required for Bolivian visa application. I wish to complete blogs on Peru tour in Bolivia. Not sure which cities yet. Let’s wait and see.</p><p>I was in the jungle with my guide George, a canoe loaded with 12-day food, fruits, water and camping supplies for two of us. For the first 8 days, I did not even met a person who speaks English. Yes, none of the local people speak English! The good thing was that my Spanish improved drastically during the tour, especially food and animals in Spanish…   </p><h1 id="The-Amazon-Jungle"><a href="#The-Amazon-Jungle" class="headerlink" title="The Amazon Jungle?!"></a>The Amazon Jungle?!</h1><p>A picture worth a thousand words! </p><h2 id="The-Jungle-Plants"><a href="#The-Jungle-Plants" class="headerlink" title="The Jungle Plants"></a>The Jungle Plants</h2><p>It’s a jungle so there are thousands of plants along the river. During one jungle hiking, my guide George gave an hour and half pantomime to explain various medical plants. Things like diarrhea, headache, muscle pain, fever etc. can be healed with different plants. It seems that once you are in the jungle, you do not really need any medicines… This jungle cures everything!</p><p>However, I am not the expert in plants. All I know are renaco and palm trees. Anyway, the jungle show starts!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HLlBDWfakOJJYLCrlP7Vwj0XTMFd5PJq"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HBf5ZMPRdoK1qA8vwsSF76uPoc2J9KVD"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1lsu0LDblDHxKlkoDX0-S2dJXq9RMt_7a"><p>Now, it’s the beautiful renaco trees, a forest in the forest.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Z5SYCtMSAnie9_hUHPNliiBHjcuQpLSg"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1fnTjTdGD68cYwkuzcCbuD8SAvNSad0bA"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=16wYAo0MvB-S4QULkUdnvpwxmJLiQWtIo"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1KZykYwBMbm0-GKf3mt_HeI8RDdhr2lhI"><p>Here comes the palm trees…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1kG6ihEVzNRAFiiJRUR7eEwhgvsNshaRL"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1NADyRaQ5cctgNHZyFBTkh5lRrj5_1lCx"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=14MWRRmW11-U3NDlyu2GsW4DkeW1aIcZF"><p>Then the tree trunk artwork by the nature!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_fuvya8l2d7MjHXAm7tLDLzZtrhpT_Oh"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1A4RLcPYd4fHmeEYsdb3fy0t3EAsIauaA"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1B565xDXC1VYe6PxBjW_M82M--mrtaP9E"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1vRuivm63L2zvFtoRX00erqjXRKXygrvH"><p>The giant tree XXX blanco…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=14NDhFFZgzUucxcWfeN5AdcLqfC-j51eZ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1M0nOwj8QrvfWbvsdu0TtUTT_Hx0zsNuY"><p>Lastly, the Amazon wetland. To go there, you have to challenge yourself to do the 12-day tour otherwise you will not be able to reach the wetland. This is the heaven for gaza grande. There are thousands of this bird!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1udP0JwgSDOmufiS4FMO0JjyY8w_4emYw"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1vJATdbEFsctsFHVKtn2-dhCCQ9k2zY6J"><h2 id="Amazon-Jungle-Day-and-Night"><a href="#Amazon-Jungle-Day-and-Night" class="headerlink" title="Amazon Jungle - Day and Night"></a>Amazon Jungle - Day and Night</h2><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1QPSsZc3WA_OwnhYtRF7L_aCh8VQ9qkCx"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=12eA4tbBWQwyi4ImguLtwXBr9L_eaZJH-"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1aXEgl1YW95Ch9XnK_X5TVUrLeOV1oLTM"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1InMBOfOCymHDSZEW9DLytH1VDz4CDged"><h2 id="The-Jungle-Animals"><a href="#The-Jungle-Animals" class="headerlink" title="The Jungle Animals"></a>The Jungle Animals</h2><p>I have to mention that it is a jungle with wild animals and it is NOT a ZOO. Yes, there are lots of animals but they just flashed by. The list of animals I have seen and know their names:</p><ul><li>Thousands of birds, like gaza family, eagle family, mama viejia, papagallo, etc.</li><li>Various of money family. Yes, many types of them but I do not know who is who.</li><li>River dolphins. There are pink and grey river dolphins. At one lunchbreak, I observed a group of pink river dolphin hunting for fish for almost 2 hours!</li><li>Paiche, the king fish of the river! They can grow to 4 meters long and 250 kilograms in weight. However, other than the water splash, I have never seen the real king fish. Many times, George pointed out and said, ‘Look, that’s pachie!’ Me: ?!</li><li>Tapir. I was very lucky to watch two tapirs coming to river band to drink.</li><li>Giant otter. I am not sure if they are giant or not but they are very vocal!</li><li>Crocodile and caiman. Many many many of them! Not cute at all!</li><li>Various fishes from the Amazon river. These I have seen them clearly, since most of them were my meals. However, the locals have very limited ways of cooking the delicious fishes. The most common ways are boiling the fish, deep fried the fish, smoked fish and the salted fish. Hum, we Chinese may win over them in terms of cooking…</li></ul><p>Yes, again the pictures of animals. Please note that I only have a fixed 50mm lens and please try hard to find the animals in the photos. Only eagles and crocodiles are not afraid of our canoe…  </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1I4uG1N6FnyVVbLWcreZdKJBuvwxM8I73"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1gihxIbfYGg2pST8gx19gkXrRS4GjEg8V"><p>Now, the thousands of Gaza Grande in the wetland. Look at all the white dots in the picture! Finally, I was able to get one photo of Gaza Grande near one of our camping site later in my journey. It seemed that it lived around the camping site and not afraid of people.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1GFsZ7Wqsxq9eeauvg6oVXHU8raOFTh0_"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1j5A_L59vKj7L0-ZTiL49IeeD2Gqn5jPX"><p>This the the giant splash by paiche, use your imagination please！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1wCscF2k5ZoJ955MUj-IPAFMQUdgWG8Ro"><p>Then some photos with animals hard to find. Try your luck :)</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1tDzeat2MvBEbcVbMRnY9CvbddXdaCRh-"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1TrbkkIGR3GWWX7mngrSahc8Z7KndIORe"><p>Lastly, the nests of XXX bird…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1G5U_Tr-gpoK_lkR5N4dl0-MDSd7BqWV1"><h1 id="Lan-where-did-you-go"><a href="#Lan-where-did-you-go" class="headerlink" title="Lan, where did you go?!"></a>Lan, where did you go?!</h1><p>Where did I go?</p><p>Anwser: Pacaya Samiria! It located at northern Peru. The Pacaya Samiria reserve is one of the biggest protected territories in Peru and was <strong>established in 1982</strong>. For comparison, <strong>it’s about the size of Slovenia</strong>, and around half the size of Denmark, Sweden or the Netherlands. It protects various segments of the western Amazon basin covering <strong>more than 2 million hectares of land</strong>. Quite a bit of it stays unexplored. </p><p>There are several ways to enter Pacaya Samiria. The most popular entry is from Iquitos. I chose to entry from Lagunas where less tourists go and tour is cheaper there.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1jGIdiMvOTkNnegmeHf8QRh4CHgRVrzD-"><p>Entry from Lagunas is not very common and not many people know this village. During my 12-day stay, all tourists I met came from Europe and 90% of them came from France. Later I knew that this village was mentioned in a French tour guide book as the top 1 destination in Peru. I was the only Chinese on their check-in book and I browsed through the book only found 3 Americans and 1 Indian out of hundreds tourists entered the Pacaya Samiria…OK, my friends, I guess you don’t come for a reason, it is really really very basic and harsh conditions in terms of accommodation, meals and hygrine condition. </p><p>Look at the map, here I recorded the GPS locations for every stop along my jungle tour. Yes, even Google map does not have such information. And the river (or creek) does not appear on Google map no matter who you zoom in!</p><div class="iframe-container">  <iframe src="https://lanVoyager.github.io/amazonMap/index.html" allowfullscreen>  </iframe> </div><h1 id="My-Amazon-Jungle-Tour"><a href="#My-Amazon-Jungle-Tour" class="headerlink" title="My Amazon Jungle Tour"></a>My Amazon Jungle Tour</h1><h2 id="The-Extras"><a href="#The-Extras" class="headerlink" title="The Extras"></a>The Extras</h2><p>Besides the nature, let’s talk about some extra items of the tour:</p><ul><li>One river, one non-English speaking guide, one canoe loaded with 12-day food, water, and camping supplies</li><li>Harsh sun and sudden rain. What if it rains? There is only one solution, keeping canoeing until the next camping site! Or you are exposed under the harsh sunlight. </li><li>Mosquitos!!!!</li><li>Camping sites have NO walls but a roof only. You directly slept on a mattress inside a mosquito net on the floor.</li><li>No meat!!! Your major protein source come from eggs, turtle eggs and fishes. Very limited veggie and fruit supply… We brought 14 bottles of 3L water for drinking. But other than drinking, all water supplies come from the yellow muddy river, including cooking, dish washing, hand washing etc. The locals drink water from the river directly…</li><li>No restroom No toilets! Please use the nature!</li><li>No electricity and of course on WiFi. We usually went to sleep at 7-8pm and got up 5am or 6am at latest…</li></ul><p>Such and such…I was shocked at first. The first day, I took out my wet wipes to clean my hands before lunch. Two days later, I gave up all my disciplines and routines after I saw how food were cooked and dishes were washed.</p><p>Look at the picture below. The dishes were washed next to the boat in the muddy yellow water! Also the same location, people wash all ingredients, wash hands, wash cloths, take a shower and everything! Now I ask you a question, what is the meaning to clean your hands? You may be cleaner than anything. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1N6GW4Y1BwPRI-kw0DYAy9epz0ymeuTBJ"><p>So I developed my own <strong>River Concentration Formula</strong>:<br>$$<br>{\displaystyle \rho <em>{i}={\frac {m</em>{i}}{V}}.}<br>$$<br>where,</p><p>​            $m_{i}$ is the mass of a constituent of any thing I don’t like</p><p>​           ${\displaystyle \rho <em>{i}}$ is the mass concentration of $m</em>{i}$ divided by the volume of the mixture <strong>V</strong></p><p>We know <strong>V</strong> is the volume of Amazon river (yes, this small creek is only an tiny branch of Amazon river). Let ${V\to inf}$, yields ${\displaystyle \rho _{i}}$ $\to 0$.</p><p>With the above formula, everything is so clean as long as you dip it in the river! What a peace of mind! Actually, I perfectly healthy during the tour…not even got diarrhea. What a magic river!</p><p>Now, let’s talk about how meals were cooked. This is one of the best kitchen during the tour. Don’t you see it even has a countertop place for cutting foods?! Other camp sites may only have two big tree branches, you will see those later in this post.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1J7n5-ciI7Uo_FuGPG0sh_fV7jMdMQ5pB"><p>No walls but roof only cabanas…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1XHHuW1glYCwITc4pcMFLpFbVk5cW4Kzg"><p>My bedroom/bed directly on the floor…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1MWSWqolK_7T29hnRwBQi0ClPLHZyULwI"><p>The bread supply for 12-days. From time to time, we need to take them out, sort them and probably dry them a bit on the floor of course. See how clean we are!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1fHx-69DHDUig-0mGyy2Yw_mE_PML5R7s"><p>The mosquito disaster! Not sure why I am so attractive to mosquitos. I had long sleeve shirts and long pants covered with mosquito cloth (it is a real thing!) and almost took shower with mosquito repellent. But see this was what I got. I am the only victim…all locals and other tourists wore shorts and T-shirts and they only got a few bites…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=10A9RERTk_ZgzXNK-32jTitOuOF6zCvrW"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1QQCim2xxHSZ-YV5t8TOGulKCZw1z6geY"><p>Look at the sun burn on my arms. Again, with long sleeves all the time and sun screen every 2-3 hours. Also, I even had an umbrella on the canoe.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1N4-qxbVRphLgYdPl5VG0wTxO1Pox9fLe"><h2 id="The-Princess-on-Amazon"><a href="#The-Princess-on-Amazon" class="headerlink" title="The Princess on Amazon"></a>The Princess on Amazon</h2><p>We talked about the accommodation, travel mode, food, mosquitos and sun light. Besides those given hard constraints, my tour was actually a luxury tour compared to other tourists from Lagunas.</p><p>First of all, as the very few Asian solo female non-Spanish speaking tourist, the manager of the travel agency gave me an umbrella while preparing our supplies. I was not realized the usage and the value of the umbrella at first. But it was such a luxury item and I recommend everyone to bring one if you plan to do the canoe tour on Amazon. Later I found out that normally all tourists got one paddle. They need to help paddling under the sun, while I was under my umbrella laying on my canoe.</p><p>During the tour, everything was prepared by my dear guide George. No cooking, no dish washing, no loading/unloading, no nothing for me! </p><p>George can paddle 10+ hours a day, and sometimes if there was trees blocking our way, he just took out the machete to cut them. Off the canoe, he was on chopping the wood, preparing for meals and he can even caught fishes from the river. (please note, George has so many friends along the river. We do not need to catch fishes on our own. We exchange our food supplies with locals for fresh fishes and many other delicious stuffs.)</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1LJGdtXfmx2K7DGr5Aq2cDjUJfkyfxepV"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1q_r-jR1-pFHXMM4_UoC6lh5twJKrSIoV"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1VU-CatVS7xqaHZT56CDKuh0rJ1p5h6K5"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1czZ4b7T8z_wxou1STD75PbKBcV_U373m"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1GioDpNL9rlRBtJi36mRy0JpIjK4YmYiQ"><p>The maka (hammock), another luxury item, which George brought. I was the only tourist with maka prepared by the guide. Why it is important? Do you see any chairs at camping site? </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=13JRPprT1y5Payf6JFBDXSnLWLFx1lLua"><p>George and I were so popular on the river. Whenever we met the locals, they like us, especially me. The turtle eggs were given as gift by one of the locals. They are super delicious!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1uahcUQ_l7tKM6Aiz3--2Yw9XMdjaQV3e"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1JIdBcMAJOYCHaqJvT0cTr2sAy2uUt8EV"><p>Freshly caught red piranha (Spanish：pana roja) for dinner!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1RKaigdS7Xg06D5wFeadiscFoe73YSCSE"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1AiI6KLso6--ISjiDOpEPhH7nDOtKeT6B"><h2 id="Detailed-Itinerary"><a href="#Detailed-Itinerary" class="headerlink" title="Detailed Itinerary"></a>Detailed Itinerary</h2><p>The plan of the 12-day tour was four days go down the stream to reach the end of the camping site from Lagunas and spent one day at the wetland (Lago Cocha Pasto), and then seven days go up stream back to Lagunas. The actual itinerary was 11 days since we only spent six days out. I requested to get out one day early due to the mosquito bites.</p><h3 id="Day-1-9-7-2019-Alice’s-Adventure-in-Wonderland"><a href="#Day-1-9-7-2019-Alice’s-Adventure-in-Wonderland" class="headerlink" title="Day 1 (9/7/2019) - Alice’s Adventure in Wonderland"></a>Day 1 (9/7/2019) - Alice’s Adventure in Wonderland</h3><p>The manager (Miguel) and my guide George picked me up at my hostel and took me to the market for breakfast. After that, we went back to the office to load all of our supplies on a tuk tuk. Then it was a half and hour ride on the bumpy muddy unpaved road to the entrance of Pacaya Samiria.</p><p>Here comes George picking me up at the dock.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1CMdcg8UlEGKuMbj4RoOSuLdhY_sMzSoW"><p>The first day of the tour was the most exciting day! It was like entering Zootopia, every 5 to 10 minutes there was some animals showing off! </p><p>We started at 9:30am with one hour lunchbreak then we continue paddling until 6:30pm. This day we were on the canoe for almost 8 hours without encountering anybody on the river… Also, I did not realize the true value of the umbrella. It was on the canoe on its own.</p><h3 id="Day-2-9-8-2019-Marie-Antoinette"><a href="#Day-2-9-8-2019-Marie-Antoinette" class="headerlink" title="Day 2 (9/8/2019) - Marie Antoinette"></a>Day 2 (9/8/2019) - Marie Antoinette</h3><p>We went to sleep at around 8pm yesterday and at 5:30am George woke me up! We quickly packed everything and started off at 6:30am. The only luxury thing I did was brushing my teeth using bottled water. Yes, I refused to use the water from the river. </p><p>At 8am, we reached one camping site and George prepared me the breakfast. There we met 2 other groups of tourists from France of course. Neither of the guys speaks English. But we chatted in broken English, Spanish and French anyway during the breakfast. They started off before us. The guys took their paddle and started paddling under the sun! All of a sudden, I realized that I have one umbrella and I should start using it!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1CD64ByCFeTAIO2UimnvnvztiJwsiu9fR"><p>We left the camp site at 10am. At 1pm, we found there was a canoe on the river bank. Aha, it’s one of the French guy with his guide. They were having their lunch. George took me there and we had their leftover pasta. Free lunch!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_fMOxa0_3dxKZuGAJpiZihsgCQyv8liw"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=18VcY46lJWnIf1vqXGCGltj-XNPDkHqJt"><p>After the lunch break, we continued paddling for another hour and arrived at today’s camping site. The guide was George’s friend. So we had them, the French chef and his guide to cook our dinner for the day. What I was doing? I was relaxing on my hammock while they were preparing the dinner.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=105wFfVtuH2V0EXAR1nl4yFffggSSSqiY"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=13SzS207jRB8Aahub52DnRhlSIvxLucng"><p>The dinner was pasta again. But there were some veggies and 2 eggs in it. This day, I learnt one Spanish sentence: me gusta huevo! (I like eggs!) This is my only protein source for the past two days and many other days to come…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1bE0b0U9-TKPYE5vhq-USTjIg8oA2XpXY"><p>This day we were only on canoe for 7 hours and had 3 meals!</p><h3 id="Day-3-9-9-2019-Don-Quijote-and-Sancho"><a href="#Day-3-9-9-2019-Don-Quijote-and-Sancho" class="headerlink" title="Day 3  (9/9/2019) -  Don Quijote and Sancho"></a>Day 3  (9/9/2019) -  Don Quijote and Sancho</h3><p>Today’s breakfast was again prepared by our French chef and his guide. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1T3lZfBjudkRdb5Nm-7_pSzOyOjL9XAMs"><p>After our breakfast, I said goodbye to my French chef. He had 7-day tour and this camp site was his ending point, while we reached here in 2 days…Actually, this camping site is the last one for tourists. Most of the tourists joined for 3, 5, 7 days tour. I have 12-day tour and from this point, the river is mostly for the locals. The distance between each camping site is so far!!! From this day one, I had never met any tourists for the next 6 days. And we could only have 2 meals a day since there is NO camping sites for stopping.</p><p>We started off at 8am and it started raining in the afternoon. There was no stopping point for us to wait for the rain to stop. So we had to paddling in the raining for almost 1.5hrs until we reached the next camping site.</p><p>Our camping site with NO walls and wet cloths…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Ylcng1X3iZ-TLLNCqdTkbOCdYPODjHnk"><p>This is the ‘stairs’ of this camping site.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1dBK4yLr4p10bZkj3Fkr_dbV-EmseSjCt"><p>George was cooking the typical local meal for dinner, salted fish with platano.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=15fkDiSvaaNKBrn2ohpJe_ZExDYd25QSU"><p>In this cabana, the local uncle gave me a bag of turtle egg. I said to him me gusta huevo! However, the fish was VERY VERY VERY salty…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=18oSRNmp7oya54SUMQVlcHbKikHnqsUiW"><p>Day 3 on canoe for almost 7 hours with 1.5 hours in the rain. Only 2 meals for the day…</p><h3 id="Day-4-9-10-2019-Robinson-Crusoe"><a href="#Day-4-9-10-2019-Robinson-Crusoe" class="headerlink" title="Day 4 (9/10/2019) -  Robinson Crusoe"></a>Day 4 (9/10/2019) -  <em>Robinson Crusoe</em></h3><p>The next morning, there was another type of salty fish for breakfast. Locals wash the salty fish with platano peels and of course using water from the river.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1NUVJjDwWOpNaANeLKHhsAU2IQszqp-FT"><p>Different fish but the same very very very salty taste…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=198WbUltlVbZhm36xMRKHOc0m7NEyeZzg"><p>We were on the canoe again at 8:30am. Today’s weather was sunny. The jungle night was so humid and none of the wet cloth was dry after one night. So we put all the cloth on the canoe and let them dry under the harsh sunlight…</p><p>After 6.5hrs non-stop canoeing, we arrived our lunchbreak site at 3pm. Dear friends, have you seen any rice dishes in the past 3 days?! Due to survival needs, my Spanish improved drastically. I told George, I could not have platano or pasta or dry bread anymore. I need arroz (rice) and veggies.</p><p>Here I had my first rice dishes with pink river dolphin hunting performance!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1PAaMQ41hXhbhghMjZNIfC8CItG_3-n-q"><p>So do you think it is the end for today? No, it is not. After the lunch/dinner, we started again at 5pm! We paddled with sunset, then in the dark with torch and crocodiles. I thought we would never reach the next camping site but to spend the night on the canoe. So we paddled and paddled and paddled. All of a sudden, I was some light far away! That’s our camping site for the day! We arrived there at 7:30pm finally. When I arrived the site, I found there was a light! Yes, in this camping site there were a family of locals. They had solar panel! The wife offered me Peruvian coke and cookies! I lay down in the hammock with music, light, Amazon tobacco and coke. For a moment, I thought I was in heaven…</p><p>Today was the longest paddling day. We spent almost 12 hours on the canoe. But due to the electricity, we went to sleep at 10pm! Technologies change human’s life!</p><h3 id="Day-5-9-11-2019-Modern-Life"><a href="#Day-5-9-11-2019-Modern-Life" class="headerlink" title="Day 5 (9/11/2019) - Modern Life"></a>Day 5 (9/11/2019) - Modern Life</h3><p>Today’s plan was to visit Lago Cocha Pasto. We would not go any further. The breakfast was prepared by the local family. Look at this luxury plate. It’s fresh boiled fish with fried eggs and rice!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=142H7PtPE1PmtWyyH2IRYDRSYlThI_Ylf"><p>The family has four sons and they left for fishing at 5am. George and I started our lake tour at 8am. I asked how long will it take. He told me around 7 hours…So we paddled again. But luckily, we met the sons with two motor boat later in the river. They generously gave us one of their motor boat! With the breeze, we continued our trip happily!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=18joDjfxsx9_PADNrDpofb6gVjOxUBkvX"><p>At noon, we finally arrived the final destination of my 12-day tour, Lago Cocha Pasto! George told me of course in Spanish. For his entire guide career, only 3 girls reached this point. He said, ‘Lan, usted no eres un turista.’ (You are not a tourist). Of course, there was a cost for this praise. The tourist only need to spend 4 hours on average on the canoe and have 3 normal meals a day! Whereas, we need to paddle 7-8 hours and only 2 meals of local food a day!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1mon2ko0A91x4mTVYwsO3JV2nRSdfz6T0"><p>Thank you very much for the generous local family. Even with the motor boat, we spent 7 hours for the tour…</p><p>Once we returned back to the camping site, the family was back with tons of freshly caught fishes.</p><p>The red piranha</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1RKaigdS7Xg06D5wFeadiscFoe73YSCSE"><p>The catfish although I do not see anything from cat in those ugly fishes</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1syku1vBcTgJMa877DM6kwl209MqscC-w"><p>Of course, the salty fishes</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=149MWZdIa46WoRDupGDqgs8KKT53q9Z2R"><p>Then it was the time for re-charging my devices. Modern life! </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1w7rKAOHCPFrUzRXnQMs8ufKNfvg5CMDI"><p>The motor for the boat. The rich local family have 2 of them!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1hEY4q1F6i_o7nRycLNm9fithrcdE7jQh"><p>From the conversation, I learnt that the locals came here for protecting the hatching of the turtle eggs. Look at my Spanish level! I can have simple conversation now!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1GynFs5-F5HduyyIhTKSXFLxdaCr68WEK"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1jCRgW5pHhWO9y1uE0ig123_P4F687ohJ"><p>The family was busy all day and everybody had their own tasks.</p><p>The elder brother was netting the fish net after a day of fishing in the river.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1PEOhDaW9SvytQaSxiePCRbGGnatIimlC"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1O71JooFCvpTe5XPiv3ty6KttbFrAiXQQ"><p>The mom is in charge of house cleaning and cooking.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1UzwJMtnNoQMWWX0hJm3IkZ3RX310mIG0"><p>Even at night, the family was working on motor maintenance. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1CfvvBodkxfe-UuXAG19fxO5qkNNp-XHY"><p>The only happy and task free family member was the cute little girl of the family.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1KWG15DDqP0tugZz-ZzRD2MfXWdvlI6ZY"><p>Today, we only paddled 1.5 hours and then switched to motor boat. Finally, I had the red piranha!</p><h3 id="第六天Day-6-9-12-2019-Start-of-the-Return"><a href="#第六天Day-6-9-12-2019-Start-of-the-Return" class="headerlink" title="第六天Day 6 (9/12/2019) - Start of the Return"></a>第六天Day 6 (9/12/2019) - Start of the Return</h3><p>This was day of our return trip. Do you still remember that we paddled almost 12 hours to reach this site? George told me if I was willing to pay for 2 gallons of gas then we could ask one of his friend to use the motor boat to send us back for the longest day. Without any hesitation, I said si! So today’s task was a short paddle back to the lunchbreak site with pink river dolphin to meet his amigo. We took our time for breakfast and relaxed in the hammock until 10:30am.</p><p>Today’s breakfast was deep fried red piranha with platano.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1d6akyT035zx23bm4J60NwIGwCrlzkGiy"><p>We arrived the camping site very early at 2pm.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1uQpLI-ciS9CE5B28cXE8rVEdG-1MqAig"><p>Leaving the rich local family, this was what I got for dinner, pasta with egg…But George and his friend only had non-salted smoked chicken with boiled platano…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1egXVLSB7kngFv430SbGkNXcx1rGFcqLu"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1MaYJYLrWbi3fEjOuVKEwmRWtliunmggT"><p>The most relaxing day. We only paddled 3 hours but still with 2 meals…</p><h3 id="Day-7-9-13-2019-Motor-Boat-with-Rain"><a href="#Day-7-9-13-2019-Motor-Boat-with-Rain" class="headerlink" title="Day 7 (9/13/2019)  - Motor Boat with Rain"></a>Day 7 (9/13/2019)  - Motor Boat with Rain</h3><p>Our goal today was to ride the motor boat to reach the camping site. For man-powered paddling, it would take 12 hours. Simple breakfast with four turtle eggs and again the fried platano… </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Kp2wR-e2eKwh4JNxVczYGFyz58uaUsyh"><p>We started at 9:30am today with two guides! Look at George’s smiling face!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1sNlx2O7RRkpW-fuggmMGfqBHqI3_Jp7v"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1tPc0Lb9jYwHFfY7OzV4PiDXVO1UKxgof"><p>I had to say the 24 soles for the gas was well spent! In the afternoon, it started raining again until the night! Our motor broke, and we had to stop and fixing it for 45 minutes in the rain! It took us almost 5 hours with 1.5 hours in the rain to reach the camping site with the motor boat. Now you can ask me the question how often do I change my cloths? The answer is whenever it rains.</p><p>My long-term friend pasta with egg as for the dinner…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1oT_UVuzu9ZlBAj4-hCP2zJaJz9GWgWMx"><p>This is the amigo who sent us here using his motor boat!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1dYqxYhAfhShsnXquHvhcfqqawlAdSaN4"><p>This is the new local who resides at the camp site for the moment. He gave me lots of local tobacco :)</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1u4McqST9nxBIpl6ljAuKi1rDn0I-DPZj"><p>Why do I need to mention the new amigo? I was wondering on the street looking for local tobacco at the last night in Lagunas but could not find any stores. I met him on the street. We chatted in Spanish and as soon as he knew that I was looking for local tobacco, he called his brother. They took me on the tuk tuk and started our tobacco hunting on the bumpy unpaved road in the dark without streetlights. Finally, we arrived at some places. My amigo went off and came back with a big bag of tobacco only for 5 soles…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DY-2WfPHgxabdN4Oo9N0H0NyWBkuZ-8z"><h3 id="Day-8-9-14-2019-Continue-Paddling"><a href="#Day-8-9-14-2019-Continue-Paddling" class="headerlink" title="Day 8 (9/14/2019) - Continue Paddling"></a>Day 8 (9/14/2019) - Continue Paddling</h3><p>This day was another long paddling day. To avoid the sunlight, we quickly had some simple breakfast and started at 7:30am.</p><p>George told me if he paddle alone we would spend 10 hours until our camping site. So I decided to join the paddle. But as a princess, I told him I could not manage the giant paddle. I asked for the smallest or the kid paddle. Just to give you an idea about the paddle size, the biggest ones are for the guides, the medium ones are for the tourist and the smallest one is for me :) </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1VTFG-867VyqQKeuoVMqm2pDnnseWRT60"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_2ttsRHOgsmBzAfhWd_X2J4c4zDh0ZQG"><p>Even with the kid’s paddle, I only worked for the first 3 hours. Once the sun came out, I stopped paddling and it was the time for my umbrella. But with my help, we only spent 8 hours on the canoe!</p><p>Today’s meal was again pasta with eggs. </p><p>At this camp site, I met the first human being who speaks English! Amario, another French tourist! We happened to travel together for the rest of the tour.</p><p>The following picture was the dinner for the locals, boiled salted fish with boiled platano. I opted out for no dinner this day…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1lmHo22BEBypeFJ4585rPIdO7t1A6bxnN"><p>Today, I paddled for 3 hours and total canoe time was 8 hours!</p><h3 id="Day-9-9-15-2019-Here-Comes-the-Prince"><a href="#Day-9-9-15-2019-Here-Comes-the-Prince" class="headerlink" title="Day 9 (9/15/2019) - Here Comes the Prince"></a>Day 9 (9/15/2019) - Here Comes the Prince</h3><p>Today’s breakfast was special, the veggie pancake with fried platano!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1RrzZ2UMDcP4HYoJyiTGm8dJDgEbcvh4s"><p>After the breakfast, the locals at this camp site started to weaving the roof using huge palm tree leaves.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DIfjijJ2XaJoHEfAxpjkU3ax9GIPuAh4"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1hyzBx7m7XjeZh90YRKOdbKiztskJj902"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1nTIsbbz95wpj7pzjGLQwfwJPXsCt6cAi"><p>The final product and it is ready for the roof.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1zDc3MOMTYKVEoB_dwH5-dW51QAM9oDJp"><p>This day, we started at 9:30am and after 6 hours paddling we reached the camping site. We had pasta with egg AGAIN! At this camping site, I met the first non-French tourist, Leonardo from Italy and speaks English. He was on a 15-day Amazon tour with 2 guides one for cooking and one for paddling! He also brought his own tent and sleeping bag. The prince prove was made when he took out his moka pot and a jar of coffee! For the entire tour, I only had instant coffee. My prince generously offered me a cup of real coffee in the jungle. With the moka pot and his two guides, I called him prince. Of course, I also showed off my umbrella :)</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DSEDHBumC9JrlD4pA8gSX5rUKuNLr8HH"><p>Canoe time of the day was 6 hours.</p><h3 id="Day-10-9-16-2019-The-Romantic-Night-Paddling"><a href="#Day-10-9-16-2019-The-Romantic-Night-Paddling" class="headerlink" title="Day 10 (9/16/2019) - The Romantic Night Paddling"></a>Day 10 (9/16/2019) - The Romantic Night Paddling</h3><p>As our original plan of 12-day tour, today was a very relaxing day. We just need to paddle 2 hours to the next camping site and had our jungle walk there for the day.</p><p>On day 8, we returned back to the tourist area. Once we arrived today’s camping site at 11am, we met the largest tourist groups! Five tourist groups with 10 people and 6 guides! Finally, we had a diversity of tourists from Germany, Czech, the Basque country and of course France.</p><p>We had fresh caught fish by other guides together. See I told you, me and George never need to fishing ourselves.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1yzkFAsUhjocB0dMl3XqW1Pe-63CPcQJ9"><p>At 3pm, I changed my rubber boot and started my jungle walk. This is George with machete making the path through the thick jungle.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1St4jT34ijLlh7HX0_yNTpzddUfdS1wCb"><p>After 1.5 hour jungle tour, I was sweat inside out. Due to unconscious scratching at night, my mosquito bites have been bleeding for days. Looking at a cabana full of tourists, I decided to continue paddling tonight so that we could get out of the jungle one day in advance. Again, I talked to George in Spanish about my decision. He said si but explained me for 5 minutes that I would not get my money back for one day less. That was totally fine. There would not be anything new for the jungle tour. So he started cooking for dinner before our departure.</p><p>This was again the fish caught by other tour group. Deep fried fish for dinner!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=12m_NwTw268HlQHi6Hj8ibSkuAt6bDErq"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1sg16_MyeCKeBaV8NdVvb76PC9e9JYdIh"><p>So we departed at 6 pm in the dark. As George paddling alone, I was appreciating the starry sky of the south hampshire. Unfortunately, I was not able to find Crux. I also observed many crocodile/caiman at night and George gave me a performance of night fishing using harpoon.</p><p>After 3.5 hours paddling, we arrived the luxury camping site at 9:30pm. Upon arrival, there came a local guide, shouting Amiga!!! It’s Amouri’s guide! He took me to a semi-private bed room. Yes, it’s a bed room with bed. Actually, this camping site has walls, the best equipped restroom,  and 2-hour electricity supply at night. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1OaanEWtQC3dMCTxkE1kdcpLKILNDKFoZ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1jkDKSpTwQhR8QfsIDR80L8R6ln89CY73"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ZxpwwNdizmlPVuDExxtNO_NKZIejXRX4"><p>Amouri’s guide prepared me the hammock and turn on the radio. He told me to rest on the hammock in the night breeze with romantic music.</p><p>Today, we only paddled in total for 5 hours and had 3 meals. </p><h3 id="Day-11-9-17-2019-Escape-Amazon-Jungle"><a href="#Day-11-9-17-2019-Escape-Amazon-Jungle" class="headerlink" title="Day 11 (9/17/2019) - Escape Amazon Jungle"></a>Day 11 (9/17/2019) - Escape Amazon Jungle</h3><p>Last breakfast in a dinning room with real table and chairs with Amouri.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1wYBYT8Jcig_Q4aRPBwitlXH8-YB4rfzK"><p>Today was our last day and we need to paddle 7 hours to get to the entry point. George told me that we would not have time to cook lunch. So he (actually Amouri’s guide) would prepare the lunch at the camp site.</p><p>Here was the pre-cook lunch at one of the resting site with Amouri and his guide.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ECTmkRqPbS0a_ZnW47Idhw5Mx6p7ndGY"><p>No surprise, pasta with egg again…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=17DSI8xO_AwH3gTNPncrx9Hysn5zKhp0l"><p>Four of us started our last leg after the lunchbreak. Amouri was paddling while I just sat on the canoe under my umbrella. Look at the sunlight!!!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1hsrHDDrJlLdHrQ6SHbkyciibGgc752we"><p>Finally, we returned to the dock at Pacaya Samiria entrance at 4pm.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1tBsx2zgf4_NTERO21mToACuzNq6JBibk"><p>The tuk tuk was waiting to take us back to the village!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1oLtFowZ61SYX2Rau8G9wd65sp-0DqYGZ"><p>Yes, the above tuk tuk loaded with 5 adults and 2 kids together with 2 canoe supplies back on the unpaved road for half an hour. But I was very happy, it’s the way back to civilization!</p><p>I was dropped off at my hostel in Lagunas at 5pm. The completed my Amazon Jungle tour.</p><h1 id="Appendix-Amazon-Jungle-Tour-Info"><a href="#Appendix-Amazon-Jungle-Tour-Info" class="headerlink" title="Appendix - Amazon Jungle Tour Info."></a>Appendix - Amazon Jungle Tour Info.</h1><p>Amazon jungle covers many countries in South America. Even in Peru, you have several spots to take the Amazon tour from the northern part (Iquitos), the middle part or the southern part (near Cusco). I would like to share some information on Amazon Jungle tour in northern Peru</p><ul><li>For real princes and princesses, please take the <a href="https://www.delfinamazoncruises.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">luxury cruise</a> with 5-star service. For a 4 or 5 day tour, it costs 3000-5000 USD.</li><li>For those common tourists, you can go to Iquitos as your entry point for Amazon. There are lots of choices and you will stay in a lodge as your base to explore the Amazon jungle. Of course, there are also luxury lodges if you prefer. Here is an example for the <a href="https://treehouselodge.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">luxury lodge</a>. If my budget allows, I would love to stay there.</li><li>For those who want challenges, please come to Lagunas…</li></ul><h2 id="How-to-Get-to-Lagunas"><a href="#How-to-Get-to-Lagunas" class="headerlink" title="How to Get to Lagunas?"></a>How to Get to Lagunas?</h2><p>Lagunas is a village along the Amazon river and only accessible by boat. You can either start from Iquitos or Yurimaguas. There are two kinds of boats, the speed boat and the very slow with no fixed schedule cargo boat. Here is my route:</p><ul><li><p>Tarapoto - Yurimaguas: 2-hour Taxi，20 soles</p></li><li><p>Yurimaguas - Lagunas: 3-6 hours speed boat，40 soles (Cargo boat will take you 12+ hours from Yurimaguas. For those interested in cargo boat, you have to ask around at Yurimaguas harbor. There is no fixed schedule, so good luck!)</p></li></ul><h2 id="Which-Tour-Agency"><a href="#Which-Tour-Agency" class="headerlink" title="Which Tour Agency?"></a>Which Tour Agency?</h2><p>To enter Pacaya Samiria, you have to have a guide. There are several tour agency around. Based on my Google search, I had the <a href="http://www.peruselva.com/index.php/our-agency/huayruro-tours-lagunas" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Huayruro Tours</a>. If you choose this agency, they have an office in Yurimaguas at Hotel Rio Huallaga. There you can find the only people who speaks English in Yurimaguas and Lagunas. In my <a href="https://lanvoyager.github.io/posts/197148b0/">previous post</a>, I had detailed information this tour agency. Or if you are confident on your SpanishS, you can go directly to Lagunas to join the tour.</p><p>Regarding cost, I paid for 160 soles per day. But most of the tourists only pay 150 soles. You can use these two numbers as your benchmark as of 2019.</p><p>Lastly, there is NO ATM in Lagunas. Please get your cash ready in Yurimaguas or Iquitos.</p><h1 id="Log"><a href="#Log" class="headerlink" title="Log"></a>Log</h1><p>Lagunas stay from September 6 to September 17, 2019.</p><ul><li>Amazon Jungle Tour: September 7 to September 17, 2019</li></ul><p>Next stop: Iquitos (speed boat leaving Lagunas at 1:00am, September 18, 2019)</p><p>*This English post was published at Cusco on October 13, 2019. *</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=1HLlBDWfakOJJYLCrlP7Vwj0XTMFd5PJq&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Lagunas" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Lagunas/"/>
    
      <category term="Amazon Jungle" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Amazon-Jungle/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>myAmazonTour</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/f44d1f3a/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/f44d1f3a/</id>
    <published>2019-09-28T06:33:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.478Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HLlBDWfakOJJYLCrlP7Vwj0XTMFd5PJq"><a id="more"></a><p>鉴于我有限的英语词汇，亚马逊丛林之旅必须先写来篇中文，比较方便描述11天的丛林生活。蒋小岚同学到底去了哪里？过了什么样的生活？吃了点啥妖怪？挑战了什么生存极限？遇到了哪些人和事？同志们，说来话长啊！本篇将是一片很长很长很长的post…从Lima写到了Arequipa，当中经历了Typora抽风，文件遗失，电脑崩溃…感觉这篇blog的更新跟丛林游一样的艰难险阻！</p><h1 id="亚马逊丛林？！"><a href="#亚马逊丛林？！" class="headerlink" title="亚马逊丛林？！"></a>亚马逊丛林？！</h1><p>嗯，爱看照片的读者朋友们，话不多说，直接上照！</p><h2 id="植物群上场"><a href="#植物群上场" class="headerlink" title="植物群上场"></a>植物群上场</h2><p>恕我文化知识缺乏，那么大片林子，我只认识榕树和棕榈树。导游乔治哥带我去丛林里面走了一圈，用西班牙语和肢体语言给我介绍了各种各样的药用植物。一会捂肚子，一会摸头，然后还有砍手砍脚，发热发汗等等的，看起来一片林子包治百病！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HLlBDWfakOJJYLCrlP7Vwj0XTMFd5PJq"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HBf5ZMPRdoK1qA8vwsSF76uPoc2J9KVD"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1lsu0LDblDHxKlkoDX0-S2dJXq9RMt_7a"><p>现在向我们走来的是妖娆多姿的榕树们！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Z5SYCtMSAnie9_hUHPNliiBHjcuQpLSg"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1fnTjTdGD68cYwkuzcCbuD8SAvNSad0bA"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=16wYAo0MvB-S4QULkUdnvpwxmJLiQWtIo"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1KZykYwBMbm0-GKf3mt_HeI8RDdhr2lhI"><p>紧跟着的是只可远观不可亵玩的棕榈树队伍。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1kG6ihEVzNRAFiiJRUR7eEwhgvsNshaRL"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1NADyRaQ5cctgNHZyFBTkh5lRrj5_1lCx"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=14MWRRmW11-U3NDlyu2GsW4DkeW1aIcZF"><p>然后是随处可见的树干艺术们。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_fuvya8l2d7MjHXAm7tLDLzZtrhpT_Oh"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1A4RLcPYd4fHmeEYsdb3fy0t3EAsIauaA"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1B565xDXC1VYe6PxBjW_M82M--mrtaP9E"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1vRuivm63L2zvFtoRX00erqjXRKXygrvH"><p>压轴上场的是巨巨巨大的某某某blanco树先生！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=14NDhFFZgzUucxcWfeN5AdcLqfC-j51eZ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1M0nOwj8QrvfWbvsdu0TtUTT_Hx0zsNuY"><p>客串演出的亚马逊湿地图，这个一般不常见，除非你也想挑战亚马逊12天。这里是鸟类天堂，成千上百的gaza grande！然后据说地下有无数石油，目前处于储备状态，似乎一度也是经过开采的。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1udP0JwgSDOmufiS4FMO0JjyY8w_4emYw"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1vJATdbEFsctsFHVKtn2-dhCCQ9k2zY6J"><h2 id="丛林的日日夜夜剪影"><a href="#丛林的日日夜夜剪影" class="headerlink" title="丛林的日日夜夜剪影"></a>丛林的日日夜夜剪影</h2><p>在丛林度过的日出日落，风风雨雨。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1QPSsZc3WA_OwnhYtRF7L_aCh8VQ9qkCx"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=12eA4tbBWQwyi4ImguLtwXBr9L_eaZJH-"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1aXEgl1YW95Ch9XnK_X5TVUrLeOV1oLTM"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1InMBOfOCymHDSZEW9DLytH1VDz4CDged"><h2 id="神奇动物-大家来找茬"><a href="#神奇动物-大家来找茬" class="headerlink" title="神奇动物-大家来找茬"></a>神奇动物-大家来找茬</h2><p>有同学问我，看到神奇动物了么？我可以很负责任的告诉你们，看到不少。当然，野生动物跟动物园不一样，一般都是一闪而过。列一点看到动物吧。</p><ul><li>数不清的鸟类！知道名字的有gaza家族各类，各种鹰类，mama viejia，papagallo（鹦鹉）。如果下辈子投胎要做鹦鹉，感觉是亚马逊的明星鸟，先不说靓丽的羽毛吧，每次出现都是成双成对，大叫的飞过，也不怕天敌？</li><li>猴子家族，嗯，也有很多不同的猴子群，当然我是分不清谁是谁的，总之看到了不少。</li><li>亚马逊河豚，有粉红色的和灰色的淡水豚。在一天的午餐时间，观赏了粉色淡水豚家庭围捕鱼吃2小时，在那以后，凡是出现淡水豚我都很淡定。感觉有点审美疲劳了。</li><li>Paiche鱼。据说是亚马逊河中的国王，可以长达4m重250kg！你问我看到了没？没见过整鱼，就看过无数巨大的水花，乔治哥说看，那就是paiche！我：？！</li><li>貘（tapir），虽然一闪而过，就看到了半个身子，貘需要特别的运气才能看到哟！需要看貘的同志，请到Tarapoto动物园寻找。</li><li>巨獭（西班牙语lobo？）身子巨大不巨大我不清楚，嗓子是巨大的！</li><li>鳄鱼，无数无数，晚上手电筒一照，岸边一排黄色的眼睛，跟路灯似的，一点也不可爱！</li><li>亚马逊其他鱼类，这个看的很清楚，基本都被我吃了，包括臭名昭著的食人鱼。非常新鲜，可惜，当地人烹饪水平不高，只会水煮，盐腌，烟熏，最多就是油炸了，不如咱中华人民会吃，真是暴敛天物了！</li></ul><p>得，我得说一下我的照相机装备Fujiflim X100F配一个50mm定焦头，如果能被我拍到的动物，必须是非常非常近的。动物界看到船不害怕的也就丑丑的鳄鱼和酷帅的鹰类。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1I4uG1N6FnyVVbLWcreZdKJBuvwxM8I73"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1gihxIbfYGg2pST8gx19gkXrRS4GjEg8V"><p>湿地里面无数无数的Gaza Grande，那些白点都是！然后来一个Gaza的近照，这只似乎住在休息点，一点也不怕人。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1GFsZ7Wqsxq9eeauvg6oVXHU8raOFTh0_"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1j5A_L59vKj7L0-ZTiL49IeeD2Gqn5jPX"><p>然后是我见到的paiche水花，use your imagination please！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1wCscF2k5ZoJ955MUj-IPAFMQUdgWG8Ro"><p>其他基本属于大家来找茬的照片类型，请自行努力从照片里面找神奇动物哈。食用鱼类请在后面的亚马逊食物章节欣赏…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1tDzeat2MvBEbcVbMRnY9CvbddXdaCRh-"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1TrbkkIGR3GWWX7mngrSahc8Z7KndIORe"><p>最后是群居的bogan（一定是一个错误的西班牙语拼写哈）鸟。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1G5U_Tr-gpoK_lkR5N4dl0-MDSd7BqWV1"><h1 id="蒋小岚，去哪儿了？"><a href="#蒋小岚，去哪儿了？" class="headerlink" title="蒋小岚，去哪儿了？"></a>蒋小岚，去哪儿了？</h1><p>所以蒋小岚到底去了哪里？！</p><p>答案是：Pacaya Samiria！位于秘鲁北部的国内最大的自然保护区，她的覆盖面积将近2.1万平方公里，相当于斯洛伐尼亚大小！一般普通级游客会从Iquitos参加旅行团进入Pacaya Samiria。我是一般人么？当然不，怎么作怎么来啊。我选择了从Lagunas进入，一来是这条线比较小众，二来从Lagunas的旅行团非常的便宜！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1jGIdiMvOTkNnegmeHf8QRh4CHgRVrzD-"><p>这个地方并不是在中国甚至美国人民中熟知的地方，非常非常非常小众。在我的12天丛林Lagunas的逗留中，遇到的游客100%是来自欧洲，其中90%是法国人？！看，蒋小岚又一次给中国人民留名了！在他们丛林访客本上，唯一一个中国人！美国人大概有3个…中国人不来是有道理的，至少我感觉亲友团不会想去Lagunas看丛林，太太太苦了，非一般人能忍受的。当然，其中主要原因是我搞了12天（其实最后11天就出来了），一般游客3天，5天，或者7天的行程。来来来，看看我到底去世界的哪个角落。</p><div class="iframe-container">  <iframe src="https://lanVoyager.github.io/amazonMap/index.html" allowfullscreen>  </iframe> </div><h1 id="我的亚马逊丛林游"><a href="#我的亚马逊丛林游" class="headerlink" title="我的亚马逊丛林游"></a>我的亚马逊丛林游</h1><h2 id="丛林游体验附加项目"><a href="#丛林游体验附加项目" class="headerlink" title="丛林游体验附加项目"></a>丛林游体验附加项目</h2><p>除了看动物植物亚马逊风景，说说丛林游的其他项目吧：</p><ul><li>一条河，一个导游，一条满载着食物，水，床铺用品和行李的独木舟</li><li>风吹日晒雨淋。下雨咋办？当然继续划船啊，唯有抵达下一个休息点，不然整条河上是没有地方避雨的。心情还是很纠结的，不知道是晴天晒成人干好呢还是下雨凉爽冲凉好…</li><li>蚊子灾难！</li><li>住的家徒的连四壁都没有的cabana，拉个蚊帐睡地板。</li><li>蛋白质补充基本靠鸡蛋，龟蛋，蔬果更加是匮乏（我是天天看VC冲剂活着的），饮用水靠的是我们自己带的瓶装水。洗菜洗碗洗漱，全部是靠河水。嗯，时不时还用河水炖东西吃…没法子，已经是给我特殊照顾了，当地人直接舀起河水就直接喝。</li><li>没有厕所淋浴室哈，有需要找大自然。</li><li>没网没电，天一黑就准备睡觉（7点开准备，8点左右就躺下了）天一亮咱就开工，每天5-6点是一定开始准备早饭了…</li></ul><p>等等等等之类的，一开始真的难以接受，吃饭前我还用湿纸巾擦手，2天后，当你看到菜是如何烧的，碗是如何洗的以后，我就看穿了。定义了什么都是干净有机的，河水就是自来水等等理论以寻求心灵的平静。</p><p>如何洗碗？脚踩着泥地，然后就在船边上直接洗碗，当然生活用水和洗手洗菜也是同一个地方取水，我就问你洗手还有啥用？反正你吃的喝的和刀叉盘子也没有多干净。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1N6GW4Y1BwPRI-kw0DYAy9epz0ymeuTBJ"><p>再说说饭是咋烧的吧，这是条件比较好的一个土灶，还带料理台。其他情况还有地上直接来两个大树枝，直接生火做饭的…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1J7n5-ciI7Uo_FuGPG0sh_fV7jMdMQ5pB"><p>然后是家徒的连四壁都没有的茅草屋。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1XHHuW1glYCwITc4pcMFLpFbVk5cW4Kzg"><p>晚上铺上一个海绵垫子拉上蚊帐就这么睡觉。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1MWSWqolK_7T29hnRwBQi0ClPLHZyULwI"><p>12天的面包储备，时不时要拿出来晒晒，这个蛇皮袋平时用来装睡觉的海绵垫子，船上，泥土地或者木板地随便扔，我也是感谢上帝这样吃了都没拉肚子…第四天我就拒绝再吃面包干了…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1fHx-69DHDUig-0mGyy2Yw_mE_PML5R7s"><p>不知道为啥自己深受各国蚊子的喜爱。每天我都是长袖长裤还穿着蚊帐衣，晚上也睡蚊帐。起床睡前第一件事情就是喷防蚊液，我就差没用防蚊液洗澡了！其他各国游客，当地男女老少都赤膊，蚊子军团视而不见，估计中国血统最高贵吧。大家看看，我的受灾情况，真的是闻着落泪，见者伤心啊！不夸张地说全身蚊子包密度基本就是每平方厘米一个！后期抓破了好多包，一身的血洞洞，黏在衣服裤子上，脱衣服巨痛苦基本就是靠撕下来！而且气候湿热，每天都是一身潮湿，这些血洞洞们一直也好不了！要说亚马逊丛林我最最不能忍受的是什么，就是蚊子的攻击！其他我都可以忍！这也是为啥最后我提前一天逃离亚马逊，没法子啊，不然估计要死于失血过多！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=10A9RERTk_ZgzXNK-32jTitOuOF6zCvrW"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1QQCim2xxHSZ-YV5t8TOGulKCZw1z6geY"><p>暴晒…我也不算是特别怕太阳的亚洲女性吧，就算是在凤凰城，最多也就是带个帽子，时间长的话涂点防晒。看看，这11天我是有多黑！这还是每2小时补防晒霜，24小时长袖，坐船还撑伞的状态下哈。当然比起蚊子来说，太阳真的不算啥，怎么说变成黑人也比变成血人好对吧？当然我最后成了黑血人…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1N4-qxbVRphLgYdPl5VG0wTxO1Pox9fLe"><h2 id="亚马逊上的公主"><a href="#亚马逊上的公主" class="headerlink" title="亚马逊上的公主"></a>亚马逊上的公主</h2><p>虽说硬件软件设施真的是原始，蚊子和太阳也是凶残的不行，其实整个旅程小日子过得是很滋润的，至少比起其他平民游客，我过的是公主级别的旅行。</p><p>因为是不多的亚洲女生单独一个人游览，走前经理给我塞了一把伞！这把伞奠定了我在这条亚马逊支流上的公主地位！后来我发现，其他游客一般是发一把浆，要帮着划船，然后每天还要负责煮东西，装卸船和洗碗等等的。当你发现其他平民们或划着船或在太阳下暴晒，而自己是唯一的撑着伞躺着游船的贵族，不自觉的就感觉高人一等呢！</p><p>本公主，下船靠扶，背着个人小包就进cabana，乔治哥一个人卸船。然后乔治哥会帮我把吊床安装好，我就躺着休息，他准备饭食烧水啥的，然后我吃完是不洗碗的，why？我坚决不能踩泥地（我之前也没这么多公主病啊，其实就是懒得换鞋子然后洗鞋子）！为了这泥地，我也拒绝河里洗澡！早晚乔治哥会给我铺床然后收床再装船，然后继续扶着我上船，不要不要泥！当然什么样的游客就有什么样的导游，乔治哥在导游界也是一霸，要是在休息点遇到其他导游和游客，一般咱们就直接不做饭了，直接然其他团烧饭给我们吃。要是遇到休息点的当地人，用自带的饼干，零食，蔬果换人家的新鲜捕来的各种鱼类，当然也是其他人煮饭！还要一路问人家讨烟抽，回程我就是河上的当地人了，一般都这么打招呼，人家这么喊“Amiga！”，我这么回，“Amigo, Tabaco, por favor!” 其实除了不能忍受蚊子的攻击以外，渡过初期的心理震惊期以后，我还是非常享受整个旅程的。</p><p>看看我的导游，男神乔治哥，可以一天划船10+小时，遇到河上过不去的槛，无论是小树枝还是大树干，一路砍砍砍！下船劈柴，做饭，还能抓鱼（注意抓鱼乃是摆拍，咱们公主队从来不自己打鱼吃，吃的都是人家捕来的…）。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1LJGdtXfmx2K7DGr5Aq2cDjUJfkyfxepV"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1q_r-jR1-pFHXMM4_UoC6lh5twJKrSIoV"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1VU-CatVS7xqaHZT56CDKuh0rJ1p5h6K5"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1czZ4b7T8z_wxou1STD75PbKBcV_U373m"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1GioDpNL9rlRBtJi36mRy0JpIjK4YmYiQ"><p>看看公主的奢侈品，吊床，简直是旅行必备！你问我why？家徒的四壁都没，当然也不会有椅子啊，除了坐地上，吊床是唯一的选择。不得不说，本公主还是唯一个导游自带吊床的！其他游客除非自带吊床，不然您就歇歇地上躺着吧。本公主一般摇着吊床赏景放空，等待乔治哥投食…俯视地上或躺或坐的平民们。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=13JRPprT1y5Payf6JFBDXSnLWLFx1lLua"><p>公主吃的也是比一般人好。乔治哥好人缘，用着咱带的罐头饼干换了不少好吃的，看看这是公主亚马逊水龟蛋储备！最后一天我吃的时候，旁边其他游客非常羡慕的看着我。唉，我小气了一把，没跟人分享。没法子啊，作为蛋黄爱好者，这水龟蛋超好吃，似乎只有蛋黄几乎没有蛋白。软壳蛋，水一煮咬破蛋壳然后吸着吃，简直是人间美味！不要问我一次为什么吃4个，这不是比鸡蛋小很多么，再说作为公主就是要这么奢华的过日子！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1uahcUQ_l7tKM6Aiz3--2Yw9XMdjaQV3e"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1JIdBcMAJOYCHaqJvT0cTr2sAy2uUt8EV"><p>食人鱼餐，其他平民吃的是导游用跟绳子钓上来的小猫食人鱼，我吃的是成年鱼，当然是当地人用渔网抓的，这么一大盆，然后炖了配饭吃，有没有感觉到公主的资产？顺便说一下这种鱼的学名叫red piranha（西班牙语：pana roja），并不吃人哈，倒是咱吃它们。当天捕获，当天吃，肉质鲜美！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1RKaigdS7Xg06D5wFeadiscFoe73YSCSE"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1AiI6KLso6--ISjiDOpEPhH7nDOtKeT6B"><h2 id="详细行程"><a href="#详细行程" class="headerlink" title="详细行程"></a>详细行程</h2><p>所以我的详细行程到底是如何呢？原定是4天顺流划船抵达Lagunas段最后一个休息点，第五天游湖，然后7天逆流原路返回。回程我们就花了6天，最终是提前一天出了丛林。</p><h3 id="第一天（9-7-2019）-爱丽丝梦游仙境！"><a href="#第一天（9-7-2019）-爱丽丝梦游仙境！" class="headerlink" title="第一天（9/7/2019）- 爱丽丝梦游仙境！"></a>第一天（9/7/2019）- 爱丽丝梦游仙境！</h3><p>早上7点，旅行社经理带着导游乔治来旅馆接我去了市场吃早饭。吃饱喝足，我们回了办公室开始装载12天的补给品。然后坐着摩的在泥路上颠簸30分钟抵达Pacaya Samiria入口。</p><p>男神乔治哥，划着满载食物，水和行李的独木舟来码头接我！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1CMdcg8UlEGKuMbj4RoOSuLdhY_sMzSoW"><p>第一天真的什么都是新奇啊。可能那天特别幸运吧，一路划船，每几分钟就有动物鸟类或者鱼类出现，就跟到了Zootopia一样，应接不暇啊。这一天还看到了两只喝水的tapir！回程同一条河，一天也没见三两只动物。</p><p>这一天9：30开划的，当中午休了一小时，然后一直划啊划啊到天黑，6：30才到营地，天都黑了，晚饭就在烛光下吃了面包配茶。睡前去了一个有马桶但是靠河水手动舀水冲洗的简易厕所，带着头灯进去吧，马桶里面蹲着一只热带雨林色彩斑斓的蛙，灯光一照，我两四目相对，大脑想要尖叫，无奈本人神经系统缓慢，还没叫出来自己就跟自己说，安心，没啥哈，这就是雨林！于是淡定的用水把蛙蛙冲掉了…</p><p>第一天划了将近8小时，后来证明，这也不算啥哈！这一天，我们抵达了一般亚马逊5天游的终点…这天我还没有了解伞的重要性，一天都在暴晒中。这一天并没有遇到任何游客或者当地人。</p><h3 id="第二天（9-8-2019）-玛丽·安托瓦内特"><a href="#第二天（9-8-2019）-玛丽·安托瓦内特" class="headerlink" title="第二天（9/8/2019）- 玛丽·安托瓦内特"></a>第二天（9/8/2019）- 玛丽·安托瓦内特</h3><p>昨天8点没洗洗就睡了，一早5点半，乔治就叫我起床了！本公主拒绝去河边用河水刷牙，乔治哥很心疼的给了半杯饮用水…6：30装船完毕，我们又开划了！8点到达另外的营地，乔治哥开始砍柴生火做饭。在营地遇到了2个法国团，都是男生一起聊天等吃饭。等待过程中2团陆续出发了，我看着两个男生暴晒着太阳拿着船桨开划出去，突然暗自庆幸咱船上自带的伞！</p><p>这天早饭吃的是水煮香蕉加水煮鸡蛋配面包咖啡。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1CD64ByCFeTAIO2UimnvnvztiJwsiu9fR"><p>吃完休整一下，10点又出发了！1点在休息点发现之前早餐点遇到的其中一共法国团Benjamin和他的导游，二话不说，咱就去蹭饭啊，自己没煮，吃了其他团剩下的意面。早走有啥用？还不是给公主团做饭么！</p><p>午餐休息点穷的连房顶都没有，就一个树干…由于是蹭饭，连个蛋白质都没有，纯吃面。我当时就快哭了，这还让人活么？！一天鱼蛋肉都不发？！后期证明，这天以后公主团就开始一天2餐的生活了，你问我为啥？因为一路划船连个树干休息点都没有！根本不可能生火做饭，唯有前进前进，前进进！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_fMOxa0_3dxKZuGAJpiZihsgCQyv8liw"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=18VcY46lJWnIf1vqXGCGltj-XNPDkHqJt"><p>吃完，一起划了1小时到达当天过夜的营地。有人在，咱公主团就不干活了，看看我的法国厨子（法国厨子不喜欢拍照，尊重他的决定，没有法国厨子照片哈）和他的导游在忙碌的做晚饭。法国厨子煮着菠萝皮茶，烧好放糖给我端到吊床这里…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=105wFfVtuH2V0EXAR1nl4yFffggSSSqiY"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=13SzS207jRB8Aahub52DnRhlSIvxLucng"><p>晚饭还是意大利汤面，不过有不少蔬菜而且终于发给我2个鸡蛋！这天我学会了一句西班牙语，me gusta huevo! 我喜欢吃鸡蛋！我一直感觉自己处于营养不良的状态下，每天就靠自带的VC冲剂过日子！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1bE0b0U9-TKPYE5vhq-USTjIg8oA2XpXY"><p>本日划船只有7小时而且吃了3餐！</p><h3 id="第三天-（9-9-2019）-唐吉柯德与他的仆人桑丘"><a href="#第三天-（9-9-2019）-唐吉柯德与他的仆人桑丘" class="headerlink" title="第三天 （9/9/2019）- 唐吉柯德与他的仆人桑丘"></a>第三天 （9/9/2019）- 唐吉柯德与他的仆人桑丘</h3><p>早餐照例是法国厨子和他的导游负责准备。非常丰盛的炒杂蔬，炸香蕉和木薯配面包咖啡！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1T3lZfBjudkRdb5Nm-7_pSzOyOjL9XAMs"><p>吃完早饭，告别了我的法国厨子，他参加的是7天的团，这个营地就是他的终点了。公主团2天就抵达了7天团的终点，厉不厉害！这个营地是旅游团的终点。这之后的营地相隔都超级超级远，当中也没有休息点，一出发就没有回头路！在接下来的6天中，我再也没有遇到过任何游客…</p><p>我和乔治哥8点多开划，一上午都在河上暴晒中，下午开始转多云，我还暗自庆幸。1点多居然开始暴雨了，乔治哥一点也没停下避雨的意思（当然也没地方可以避雨），暴雨中我撑着伞，他划着船，一路在暴雨中前行了一个多小时，终于抵达了这天的营地。当中在浅滩停下了15分钟，不是为了避雨，实在是雨太大，船里积水严重，我们停下舀水出去…</p><p>湿衣服挂起来，第二天还是湿的！倒是干衣服一晚上要是放在外面都潮了。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Ylcng1X3iZ-TLLNCqdTkbOCdYPODjHnk"><p>这营地连个像样的梯子都没有。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1dBK4yLr4p10bZkj3Fkr_dbV-EmseSjCt"><p>晚饭吃的是据说当地人的标配，香蕉咸鱼一起水煮！盖上营地旁边现砍的香蕉叶，看起来是不是很诱人？这是我第一次在丛林里面吃鱼，兴奋的不行啊！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=15fkDiSvaaNKBrn2ohpJe_ZExDYd25QSU"><p>这里驻守的叔叔给了我们好大一包水龟蛋！因为淋了雨，公主有点感冒，晚上乔治哥还给我单独加了2个蛋！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=18oSRNmp7oya54SUMQVlcHbKikHnqsUiW"><p>好不好吃？鱼巨巨巨咸！我想着今天生病了，必须补充蛋白质啊，不然怎么跟病魔作斗争！于是配着面包干，努力的全部吃完了，还有，水煮香蕉真的真的不好吃！这天晚餐后，吃了一堆感冒药2袋VC，晚上穿着厚衣服盖着被子睡觉！</p><p>第三天不停歇的划船7小时不到，其中淋雨1个多小时，只吃了2餐…</p><h3 id="第四天（9-10-2019）-鲁滨逊漂流记"><a href="#第四天（9-10-2019）-鲁滨逊漂流记" class="headerlink" title="第四天（9/10/2019）- 鲁滨逊漂流记"></a>第四天（9/10/2019）- 鲁滨逊漂流记</h3><p>这天起来，换了一种咸鱼炖香蕉当早饭！看看，咸鱼用香蕉皮河水洗洗就开煮啦！提供水龟蛋的好心叔叔，当然还是要给我们公主团做饭的！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1NUVJjDwWOpNaANeLKHhsAU2IQszqp-FT"><p>不同的咸鱼一样的做法一样能齁死人的咸！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=198WbUltlVbZhm36xMRKHOc0m7NEyeZzg"><p>8：30咱们又整装出发啦！这天天气晴，我们把昨天淋湿的衣服摊在船上晒干。一路划啊划啊划，一路除了偶尔飞过的鸟或者水花什么都没有！经历6个半小时暴晒以后，于下午3点抵达营地。一路划船的时候，我就跟乔治哥要求，我要吃米饭，吃蔬菜和蛋白质！看看为着生存，我的西语进步神速，都会用西班牙语点菜了！</p><p>这个营地处于两河交汇处，是粉色淡水豚聚集地！吃着亚马逊第一顿米饭，观赏了粉红淡水豚一家画圈捕鱼的过程！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1PAaMQ41hXhbhghMjZNIfC8CItG_3-n-q"><p>同志们以为这天就这么圆满的画上了句号了吗？不，吃完乔治哥又开始装船准备出发了，这时都将近下午5点了！这是一种怎样的精神啊！一路观赏了亚马逊夕阳，然后开始带着头灯在黑暗中划船前行！一度我以为今晚是要在船上过夜了！终于，在晚上7点多，看到了远处的灯光！不是说亚马逊没电么？当我迈着麻木的腿走上今天的营地，发现了神物，一盏亮着的电灯！！！此处是一家当地人驻守，带着太阳能电池！！！我们一到，这家主人慷慨的提供了可乐，饼干，亚马逊烟草的卷烟！这家有男女主人，带着四个儿子一个女娃驻守。躺在吊床上，在灯光下，我想着这简直是天堂啊！这是Lagunas丛林线的终点了。</p><p>这天是丛林游划船最长的一天，加上粉红淡水豚驻点的一个多小时整休，我们将近花了12个小时才抵达营地！！！虽说我不划船，晚饭累的也吃不下东西了，随便喝了点热水吃了2个面包就算是晚饭了。当然由于此营地有灯，这天我们10点才睡觉，是不是科技改变人生！</p><h3 id="第五天（9-11-2019）-重生种田文"><a href="#第五天（9-11-2019）-重生种田文" class="headerlink" title="第五天（9/11/2019）- 重生种田文"></a>第五天（9/11/2019）- 重生种田文</h3><p>今天的计划是游览Lago Cocha Pasto，不再前进，继续住在这个营地。早餐异常丰盛，当然是人家当地人提供的。米饭，水煮鲜鱼，和2个炒鸡蛋！我已经跟乔治哥抱怨了咸鱼实在吃不了，据吃咸鱼！人家乔治哥说了，这家人每天出去打鱼，咱顿顿在这吃鲜鱼！美味的蛋白质们啊！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=142H7PtPE1PmtWyyH2IRYDRSYlThI_Ylf"><p>一早5点多，这家儿子们就出去下网捕鱼了。8点多，乔治哥带着我又开始划船了，我问了要多久啊，人答今天来回8小时！听到心里哇凉哇凉的。从主河道，我们划了连Google map都不显示的小河…一路无数的枯树枝拦路，乔治哥一路砍砍砍的过。1个多小时后，我们遇到了开着马达船的一家子。人家看着可怜的咱俩，慷慨的把马达船还给了我们！真是科技的力量，马达船真的不一样，看看，一路赶着鸟，吹着小风，惬意的不行！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=18joDjfxsx9_PADNrDpofb6gVjOxUBkvX"><p>换了雨鞋踏着泥滩，中午12点多，我们终于抵达了本次行程的最终点Lago Cocha Pasto！乔治哥感慨的说，“你不是一个游客！”在他的导游生涯中，包括我，只有3个女生抵达此地，当然我是唯一一个亚洲人。一般人都报3天，5天，7天团。此处应有掌声，这些都是乔治哥用西班牙语说的，看看我的西语水平！</p><p>可不是！我之前遇到的游客跟我说，一般平均一天划船4小时，吃丰盛的三餐！我呢，一天至少在这个独木舟上度过7小时，吃个2餐，一般还都吃当地人食物！要不是我西语进步神速，我还在吃水煮香蕉配咸鱼呢！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1mon2ko0A91x4mTVYwsO3JV2nRSdfz6T0"><p>万分感谢这家的慷慨的爸爸，就算开着马达船，我们也花了7小时，下午3点多才回到营地，如果我们人力划，估计不到天黑是回不来了。</p><p>到家以后，我照例往吊床上一趟，等饭吃。过了没多久，这家的男生们打鱼回来了。一盆盆的往家里搬鱼！</p><p>一盆食人鱼</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1RKaigdS7Xg06D5wFeadiscFoe73YSCSE"><p>一盆巨丑的鲶鱼</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1syku1vBcTgJMa877DM6kwl209MqscC-w"><p>当然也少不了某咸鱼</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=149MWZdIa46WoRDupGDqgs8KKT53q9Z2R"><p>然后热情的少爷们说是给我提供电源充电！太阳能电池和我的电子设备们！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1w7rKAOHCPFrUzRXnQMs8ufKNfvg5CMDI"><p>另外，这富有的家庭居然有2条马达船！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1hEY4q1F6i_o7nRycLNm9fithrcdE7jQh"><p>躺着跟着一家子聊天，得知每个营地驻守的当地人都是为了保护水龟蛋的孵化。每个营地都有孵化床，村子里派人来驻守，一般都是一个男生一个人住上10-15天，这一家子都来顺便捕鱼。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1GynFs5-F5HduyyIhTKSXFLxdaCr68WEK"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1jCRgW5pHhWO9y1uE0ig123_P4F687ohJ"><p>一家人都特别勤劳，一早起来到晚上吃完饭，一直在忙忙碌碌的干活。</p><p>整理渔网的大哥。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1PEOhDaW9SvytQaSxiePCRbGGnatIimlC"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1O71JooFCvpTe5XPiv3ty6KttbFrAiXQQ"><p>负责整理房间和做饭的妈妈。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1UzwJMtnNoQMWWX0hJm3IkZ3RX310mIG0"><p>夜晚一家子还在修理马达。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1CfvvBodkxfe-UuXAG19fxO5qkNNp-XHY"><p>唯一无忧无虑的大概就是这家的小妹了。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1KWG15DDqP0tugZz-ZzRD2MfXWdvlI6ZY"><p>摇着吊床，看着忙碌的一家子，开始臆想要是我不幸的困在亚马逊了，要想法子嫁给四个儿子中的一个，这样饿不死还能有科技产品不是！然后要带着一家子在村子里开个水煮鱼，烤鱼饭店奔赴小康生活啊！</p><p>这天划船1.5小时，游览湿地半小时，然后马达艇4小时。终于吃到了食人鱼！</p><h3 id="第六天（9-12-2019）-逆流返航"><a href="#第六天（9-12-2019）-逆流返航" class="headerlink" title="第六天（9/12/2019）- 逆流返航"></a>第六天（9/12/2019）- 逆流返航</h3><p>今天开始逆流返航。还记得第四天顺流划船11小时么，乔治哥跟我说，如果我同意，我们可以在粉红淡水豚出没的营地找他的朋友，花24soles买2加仑汽油让人家摩托艇托我们走！我一想也是，不然要两人暴晒至少12小时，划船走。于是我们愉快的决定，今天就去找Amigo去。这个营地离这很近，早餐悠闲的吃完炸食人鱼，然后躺在吊床上看看手机，10点半才慢悠悠的整装出发。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1d6akyT035zx23bm4J60NwIGwCrlzkGiy"><p>下午2点多就抵达营地了。这就是粉红豚聚集的住着摩托艇的Amigo家！比起前一家有吃有喝有太阳能的营地是不是看起来一平如洗？</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1uQpLI-ciS9CE5B28cXE8rVEdG-1MqAig"><p>晚上吃了意面和鸡蛋，这还是给公主特供的。乔治哥和Amigo吃水煮香蕉和不加盐的烟熏鸡肉…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1egXVLSB7kngFv430SbGkNXcx1rGFcqLu"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1MaYJYLrWbi3fEjOuVKEwmRWtliunmggT"><p>这天是最轻松的一天，只在船上划了2个半小时。当然，还是只吃了2餐…</p><h3 id="第七天（9-13-2019）-风雨兼程"><a href="#第七天（9-13-2019）-风雨兼程" class="headerlink" title="第七天（9/13/2019）- 风雨兼程"></a>第七天（9/13/2019）- 风雨兼程</h3><p>今天的目标是开着摩托艇去咸鱼营地！一早补充了4个水龟蛋和炸香蕉（我跟乔治哥说了，香蕉不爱吃，非要吃请帮我油炸），9点半开拔。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Kp2wR-e2eKwh4JNxVczYGFyz58uaUsyh"><p>今天公主有2个仆人！前面的Amigo负责掌舵，后面的乔治哥开船，看乔治哥笑的多欢乐！终于不必再划船了！看到后面拖着的空船了吗？Amigo把我们送到下一个营地还需要第二天继续开船回去…真是好人啊！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1sNlx2O7RRkpW-fuggmMGfqBHqI3_Jp7v"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1tPc0Lb9jYwHFfY7OzV4PiDXVO1UKxgof"><p>这回24soles花的太值了！下午居然又下起了大雨。不幸的是，我们的马达居然在暴雨中坏了！于是我们紧急靠岸，在暴雨中修船45分钟？！同志们要问了，我几天换洗一次衣服？告诉你们，看老天的命令！淋一次雨，就从里到外换一套！这天摩托艇都花了5个小时！当然包括中途修船。</p><p>每次到这个营地都下雨也是神了！今天的晚饭还是意面鸡蛋和水龟蛋…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1oT_UVuzu9ZlBAj4-hCP2zJaJz9GWgWMx"><p>来一个送我们回来Amigo的正面照！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1dYqxYhAfhShsnXquHvhcfqqawlAdSaN4"><p>另附新来的驻守营地的Amigo！这位兄弟分了好多烟给我。这里抽的是亚马逊烟叶卷的香烟。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1u4McqST9nxBIpl6ljAuKi1rDn0I-DPZj"><p>最后一晚我回Lagunas想买一点作为特产，街上怎么也找不到。正巧遇上这位兄弟，人二话不说，拉着我就上了他弟弟的摩的，跟我说我们现在是Familia了，一路突突突在没有路灯的泥地上到处穿行，到了一黑店，真的黑，连灯都不开，这兄弟下车，拍门，5soles帮我买了这么大一包！不得不说，我人缘超好啊！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DY-2WfPHgxabdN4Oo9N0H0NyWBkuZ-8z"><h3 id="第八天（9-14-2019）-继续逆流划划划"><a href="#第八天（9-14-2019）-继续逆流划划划" class="headerlink" title="第八天（9/14/2019）- 继续逆流划划划"></a>第八天（9/14/2019）- 继续逆流划划划</h3><p>这天还是任务艰巨的一天！为了避免暴晒时间，一早随便吃了点煎蛋和炸香蕉，7：30我跟乔治哥告别了摩托艇和香烟Amigos，顶着晨雾就出发了。</p><p>这天本公主也加入了划船的行列！不划不行啊，靠乔治哥要10小时才能抵达。我也只能拿起小浆努力划船啊！来比划一下独木舟的浆，最大的导游们用的，中等的是一般发给游客的，我跟乔治哥说，本公主力气小，能帮你划几下就不错了，请发个我最小的…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1VTFG-867VyqQKeuoVMqm2pDnnseWRT60"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_2ttsRHOgsmBzAfhWd_X2J4c4zDh0ZQG"><p>就拿着这个号称儿童浆，本公主也只划了3小时，还是划10分钟，休息5分钟的态度。太阳一出来，我就罢工了。跟乔治哥说，本公主晒不得太阳要撑伞了！当然这3小时的努力，还是很有成效的。下午3点多，只划了8小时多我们就抵达了营地。</p><p>这天这个营地来了一对当地人夫妇还遇到了神奇的法国人Amaori，就叫他阿毛吧。这娃是我8天来第一个遇到的会说英文的孩子，之前遇到的2个法国人只会说法语和西班牙语。一来阿毛就跟我炫耀他的导游简直是个厨子，每天像给10个人烧饭一样的给他投食，一餐他有2-3盘不同的吃的。我作为一个每天都在船上渡过，一般吃2餐的苦娃，一听就羡慕嫉妒的不行啊！在乔治哥给我准备晚饭的同时，阿毛到处忙，一会儿烧水，一会儿翻找食物。说是要吃下午茶了？！这过的是啥日子啊。</p><p>我吃完饭，就上吊床躺着了。阿毛是个平民，只能坐地上看书。一会他又来聊天了，说是他参加了7天团，明天就开始返程了，不过他打算明天凌晨1点开划，以便欣赏夜景。问我有没有这个夜划活动，我告诉他，咱经常白天也不能抵达营地，时不时要在晚上划船。6点多他就回蚊帐说是要早睡，明天可能见不到了，先跟我道别啦。</p><p>这时当地夫妇和道友们开始准备晚饭。乔治哥问我还吃不，我说刚才4点多才吃好，就喝个热茶吧。看看，就这当地特色的水煮鱼配水煮香蕉谁要吃啊？！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1lmHo22BEBypeFJ4585rPIdO7t1A6bxnN"><p>不过我还是很好奇阿毛的晚餐到底啥水平。一会人家都准备好晚饭开吃了，根本没给阿毛准备吃的！阿毛灰溜溜的出了蚊帐，拿了一个苹果和饼干喝着我的热水。我就问了，这就是你的晚饭啊？他答，我到前他才吃了一顿大餐，现在吃不下。我想那你下午还疯狂找吃的喝下午茶呢？！</p><p>一会我就问了，你晚上到底走不走啊？阿毛说不知道，等他导游吃完去问问。我准备洗洗睡了，他来了兴奋的说，导游说了晚上不走，现在带着他出去转一圈。所以这晚阿毛并没有跟我分开。</p><p>这天本公主亲自拿着儿童号的浆划船3小时，共计在船上渡过8个多小时！</p><h3 id="第九天（9-15-2019）-真正的王子出现！"><a href="#第九天（9-15-2019）-真正的王子出现！" class="headerlink" title="第九天（9/15/2019）- 真正的王子出现！"></a>第九天（9/15/2019）- 真正的王子出现！</h3><p>一早乔治哥也不知道是不是受了阿毛的刺激了，居然耗时巨久给我准备了蔬菜饼子配炸香蕉！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1RrzZ2UMDcP4HYoJyiTGm8dJDgEbcvh4s"><p>那么阿毛到底吃啥呢？也就是标配2个鸡蛋加炸香蕉！我都怀疑他是不是活在臆想中的王子生活中了，后期他还有更多故事！一吃完，阿毛团就开拔出发了，阿毛再一次跟我道别！</p><p>我们公主团休整。这时，当地夫妇开始制作茅屋屋顶了。叔叔一早去林子里砍了好多好多棕榈叶回来，阿姨就开始编织叶子，巨大的叶子。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DIfjijJ2XaJoHEfAxpjkU3ax9GIPuAh4"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1hyzBx7m7XjeZh90YRKOdbKiztskJj902"><p>编好的叶子，叔叔又从林子里收集了好多藤条，一个个的扎紧。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1nTIsbbz95wpj7pzjGLQwfwJPXsCt6cAi"><p>最后的成品是这样的，是不是还挺美的。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1zDc3MOMTYKVEoB_dwH5-dW51QAM9oDJp"><p>观赏完草棚制作，9点半我们也出发了。又是6小时不停歇的划船，下午3点半抵达营地。神奇的是，又见到阿毛了！老规矩，有其他团在的情况下，我团蹭饭吃。阿毛的导游勤勤恳恳的给我们又做了鸡蛋意面…谁说每顿吃个2-3盘不同餐点的呢？！</p><p>这里我遇到了本次出行的第一个非法国人的游客，来自意大利的李奥纳多！这位哥才是真正的王子殿下，人家参团15天，自带2个导游，一对夫妇。一个划船一个专职做饭！一船的各种蔬果储备丰富！王子殿下自带帐篷睡袋，人家不睡导游准备的蚊帐。他已经独自在南美旅行8个月了，一般都是自己背着20多公斤的装备独自在山区徒步十天半个月！吃完晚饭，王子殿下拿出了证明贵族身份的设备，自带的意式咖啡壶和一桶咖啡粉！！！慷慨的给我和阿毛都发了一杯。在此感谢王子殿下，之前我喝的全是咖啡水，根本谈不上咖啡！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DSEDHBumC9JrlD4pA8gSX5rUKuNLr8HH"><p>喝完咖啡，阿毛又出发了，按照7天团行程从昨天的营地的他3天回程，12天行程是4天回程。阿毛第三次跟我道别了。</p><p>本天乔治哥单独逆流划船6小时！</p><h3 id="第十天（9-16-2019）-浪漫的逃离亚马逊"><a href="#第十天（9-16-2019）-浪漫的逃离亚马逊" class="headerlink" title="第十天（9/16/2019）- 浪漫的逃离亚马逊"></a>第十天（9/16/2019）- 浪漫的逃离亚马逊</h3><p>按照我们12天的行程，今天开始我团可以悠闲的返程。早餐还是标配煎蛋加炸香蕉。9点多出发，轻松的于中午11点半抵达午餐和原定住宿的营地。</p><p>从遇到阿毛开始，我们又回到旅游区了。这天一到，营地已经驻扎了一家老小的当地人还有个2岁的男娃娃。我想今晚睡觉可要热闹了！哪知道，陆续又来了其他5个团！总计游客十人导游六人！！！小小的营地立刻满员，导游们只能在棚外休息…这次遇到了来自德国，法国，捷克和巴斯克自治区的游客。恕我无知，人跟我说 we come from the best country的时候，我想哪来的那么高傲的人，置我泱泱中华于何地？！搞了半天是the Basque county…一群人热热闹闹交流一行到底看到了多少动物。这些团都是4，5，6天团，听我说我是12天的，立马对我表示了崇拜。</p><p>当然有其他团的好处是，我们团又可以蹭饭啦！人家导游们来的时候抓了不少鱼，中午大家都吃了炖鱼！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1yzkFAsUhjocB0dMl3XqW1Pe-63CPcQJ9"><p>下午3点，乔治哥给我换了雨鞋拿着砍刀带我去丛林陆地游览。当然我全身装备完备，长裤长袖手套帽子和蚊帐衣！一路挥着砍刀前行，乔治哥是不是给我表演西班牙歌舞剧，用不同的肢体象声词语言给我介绍各种药用植物，还逼着我记录！我也不知道到底在本子上写了点啥，1个半小时后，似乎什么植物名字都没记住，只知道这片林子看来能治百病。密林中开到的乔治哥！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1St4jT34ijLlh7HX0_yNTpzddUfdS1wCb"><p>走完丛林出来，不夸张的说从内到外全身湿透！看着一屋子游客，突然觉得挺没意思的。于是我跟乔治哥说，是否可以提前一天出去？乔治哥用西班牙语跟我说了5分钟，主题就是提前可以但是经理不会给我退款，解释又解释了无数遍，确定我接受，他立马开始做晚饭，说是吃完就走。看这是他坑下的其他团的鱼，中午就腌好了，一早给我准备了晚饭。一炸就能吃！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=12m_NwTw268HlQHi6Hj8ibSkuAt6bDErq"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1sg16_MyeCKeBaV8NdVvb76PC9e9JYdIh"><p>晚上6点，公主团告别欧盟游客团，又开始了行程。就是么，一天才划船2个多小时根本不符合我团的精神！这天浪漫的跟乔治哥夜划，阿毛看看，要不要特别安排夜划！先是看了亚马逊的日落，紧接着观赏了一小时的南半球的星空！我一直也没找到南十字星，之前问了学识丰富的意大利王子，他说这里太靠近赤道而且有树林遮挡，要我等去智力阿根廷再找。然后到了鳄鱼出没去，手电筒一照，一排昏黄的鳄鱼眼睛！！！一会乔治哥又给我表演了鱼叉捕鱼！当然都是小猫鱼也不能吃，完全就是表演哈！当中我俩还分享了一根亚马逊卷烟，乔治哥说这种grande的卷烟就是用来分享的，我也是XX了。不过也不管了，开始我还坚持一人一瓶水分开喝，经常乔治哥也不管是拿瓶，随便拿起来就喝，我能说啥？！而且乔治哥负责做饭不是，经常要尝么。到第十天我已经抛弃了所有生活原则了！</p><p>夜划3个半小时，9点半我们抵达了本次行程的最后一个营地！刚到里面就冲出来一个导游，大叫Amiga！！！我定睛一看，这不是阿毛的导游么！阿毛导游热情的接待了我，把我安排进一个大床房，是的你没看错，一个有床的房间！！！这里是7天一下团必住2天的营地，唯一家里有墙，提供房间，床，设施最完全的卫生间，每晚6-8点还有电的奢华营地！当时我就想了，啥，这里还有这么高级的地方呢，我咋没住过？幸好我决定提前一天回，不然原定也不会在这里休息，乔治哥就是要培训我不走游客路！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1OaanEWtQC3dMCTxkE1kdcpLKILNDKFoZ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1jkDKSpTwQhR8QfsIDR80L8R6ln89CY73"><p>是的这就是本条河流最高级的厕所了，其他就不拍了，就是大自然啊。当然其实发现自然厕所也很好，至少人多的时候一点也没有味道。不信您试试去 :)</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ZxpwwNdizmlPVuDExxtNO_NKZIejXRX4"><p>安排完房间，阿毛导游立刻把吊床让给我然后拿出一个收音机放起了音乐，说躺歇歇罗曼提克一会。这天真的还挺浪漫的，看了星空，分享了香烟，然后听着歌吹着小风晃着吊床跟着当地朋友们聊天，是的我的西班牙语已经到可以简单会话的地步了。</p><p>这天总共其实也才划了5个半小时，其中3个小时是微风阵阵的夜划，吃了3餐。看来一般游客把时间都浪费在吃饭上了…</p><h3 id="第十一天（9-17-2019）-逃离亚马逊丛林"><a href="#第十一天（9-17-2019）-逃离亚马逊丛林" class="headerlink" title="第十一天（9/17/2019）- 逃离亚马逊丛林"></a>第十一天（9/17/2019）- 逃离亚马逊丛林</h3><p>一早阿毛起来看到我震惊了！我感觉他心里想着咋就摆脱不了我呢？一起在正经的有桌椅的餐厅吃了最后的早饭。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1wYBYT8Jcig_Q4aRPBwitlXH8-YB4rfzK"><p>这里我又要得意一把了，比阿毛多了炒蔬菜，哈哈哈，乔治哥好样的，没给本公主丢人！当中乔治哥问我了，今天要划7小时出去，午餐在这里做好，到点不烧了，就带着走。我说了，不吃也没事啊，直接划呗，反正我也习惯了。7小时算啥，11小时都划过！</p><p>不知道咋导游们怎么开的小会，阿毛导游后来做了午饭一吃完早饭就带着走了。阿毛同学第n次跟我道别。虽然我们一天出亚马逊，下一站都去Iquitos。阿毛的计划是做货船花3天去Iquitos，我没那么自虐一早决定坐当天晚上的快船直接离开。</p><p>今天算是个中程划船，而且是最后一天了，作为公主团，我们吃完早饭继续吊床悠闲的早休。9点半我们开始最后一天的旅程。下午1点，乔治哥跟我说5分钟就到午餐点了，河道一转弯，又看到阿毛和他的导游在泥地上坐着…我一到他就说，咱们等你们快2小时了！我也是醉了，这个休息点破的只有走10步就完的泥滩连个树枝都没有，阿毛居然看着蝴蝶在这里等了2小时！我们一到，咱就开饭了，看看这娃饿无奈的样子。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ECTmkRqPbS0a_ZnW47Idhw5Mx6p7ndGY"><p>不过阿毛还是很绅士的的，作为不能下泥地的公主，他赤着脚下河帮我拿饭。毫无意外的，又是亚马逊意大利面加一个白煮鸡蛋。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=17DSI8xO_AwH3gTNPncrx9Hysn5zKhp0l"><p>一众人吃完洗碗然后四人2船开始最后的3小时的航程。太阳下，我撑着伞，乔治哥开路，后面跟着努力划船的阿毛和他的导游！这娃很命苦啊！</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1hsrHDDrJlLdHrQ6SHbkyciibGgc752we"><p>下午4点我们终于抵达Pacaya Samiria的码头。一下船，我就踹着相机开始一顿狂拍。这时勤劳的阿毛，开始帮着卸船了。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1tBsx2zgf4_NTERO21mToACuzNq6JBibk"><p>我也不好意思一边站着不是，于是看是帮着把行李装上回城的摩的。这算是摩的中的豪华版了。</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1oLtFowZ61SYX2Rau8G9wd65sp-0DqYGZ"><p>一路又是泥地中颠簸着回村子里。真的，幸好我以前也没花钱在off road吉普车游玩。秘鲁各种jeep，taxi和摩的开的山路，土路，泥路根本比美国的off road更刺激！这一车要装2船的东西，5个成人，2个娃和一司机，娃娃们在回程中还能睡觉？！我得努力抓着铁杆，防止被颠出去！</p><p>下午5点，我终于回到了半文明的Lagunas村里的旅馆。至此，本次亚马逊丛林游完美的画上了句号。</p><h1 id="后记-如何参加亚马逊丛林游？"><a href="#后记-如何参加亚马逊丛林游？" class="headerlink" title="后记 - 如何参加亚马逊丛林游？"></a>后记 - 如何参加亚马逊丛林游？</h1><p>亚马逊丛林覆盖面巨大，可选择多个国家体验热带丛林游。在秘鲁也有好几个点，分别在北部，中部和南部（Cusco附近）。我只知道北部的几个雨林行程：</p><ul><li><p>真正的豌豆公主们，请选择<a href="https://www.delfinamazoncruises.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">奢华邮轮</a>。4到5天，3000到5000美金不等。全程热水空调，请自行Google哈。</p></li><li><p>不想自虐的同志们，可以考虑从Iquitos进入丛林。有很多选择，从普通丛林旅馆到5星都有哈。随便贴一个我自己比较喜欢的高档<a href="https://treehouselodge.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">丛林Lodge</a>，当然不在我的预算中。也有便宜的哈。</p></li><li><p>最后，想要挑战自己的真的勇士们，请到Lagunas来，体验真正的原始生活！</p></li></ul><h2 id="如何抵达Lagunas？"><a href="#如何抵达Lagunas？" class="headerlink" title="如何抵达Lagunas？"></a>如何抵达Lagunas？</h2><p>这个村子只能搭船到达。可选从Iquitos或者Yurimaguas搭船。船有2种，巨慢的只有吊床的货船，或者快船。我的行程是这样的：</p><p>Tarapoto - Yurimaguas: 2小时Taxi，20 soles</p><p>Yurimaguas - Lagunas: 3-6小时快船，40 soles （货船12小时以上哈！有兴趣的同学，可以在Yurimaguas的码头问讯。发船和抵达时间没有时间表，完全靠运气）</p><h2 id="如何报团？"><a href="#如何报团？" class="headerlink" title="如何报团？"></a>如何报团？</h2><p>Pacaya Samiria必须有导游带入，个人是不允许自行进入丛林的。网上有一些旅行公司，网评最好的是，<a href="http://www.peruselva.com/index.php/our-agency/huayruro-tours-lagunas" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Huayruro Tours</a>。如果选择这个公司，那么可以在Yurimaguas参团，他们在Hotel Rio Huallaga有个办公室，那里你可以找到唯一会说英语的某经理。具体情报团况详情，点击<a href="https://lanvoyager.github.io/posts/197148b0/">这里</a>。</p><p>价格么，我又一次付了高价，一般一天150 soles可以拿下，我付160 soles一天。不会说西班牙语就是吃亏。或者你也可以在Lagunas办公室参团。当然，在Lagunas没人会说英文的。</p><p>注意，Lagunas是没有ATM机的，请在Yurimaguas准备好现金。</p><h1 id="Log"><a href="#Log" class="headerlink" title="Log"></a>Log</h1><p>Lagunas stay from September 6 to September 17, 2019.</p><ul><li>Amazon Jungle Tour: Sepember 7 to September 17, 2019</li></ul><p>Next stop: Iquitos (speed boat leaving Lagunas at 1:00am, September 18, 2019)</p><p><em>This post was published at Arequipa on October 2, 2019. English version will be updated when I have time.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=1HLlBDWfakOJJYLCrlP7Vwj0XTMFd5PJq&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Lagunas" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Lagunas/"/>
    
      <category term="Amazon Jungle" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Amazon-Jungle/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tarapoto-N-Yurimaguas</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/197148b0/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/197148b0/</id>
    <published>2019-09-06T01:40:27.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.476Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1PiRGhgmuyRwhIJmPQzFXjbL_tjb-eUZI"><a id="more"></a><h1 id="Tarapoto"><a href="#Tarapoto" class="headerlink" title="Tarapoto"></a>Tarapoto</h1><p>It’s another unpleasent 8-hour overnight bus ride from Chachapoyas to Tarapoto. I arrived the city at 5:00am with complete darkness at the bus terminal. I was able to check in my hotel at around 6am. From the Andes highland, here I arrived at Peruvian rainforest region. The weather was hot and humid! My room has NO AC but only a fan…The only good news was finally I can wash my ‘black’ dirty ski jacket and ‘yellow’ muddy hiking pants (both are blue in their original color)! With only 8 soles, I was able to wash the jacket, the hiking pants, 3 T-shirts and 3 pairs of socks! After a shower, I changed to summer outfits with light-weight hiking pants and T-shirt! That was my cleanest moment of my South America Trip.</p><p>So I started my exploration of the city. First stop was the famous Plaza de Armas. Really, it was the worse plaza of all the Peruvian cities I visited so far. There was an information center located at the plaza. But really, there was not much to see around.</p><p><strong>Plaza de Armas of Tarapoto</strong></p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ooUlWnPyuukY09aYr8lfhFwPm5utm65V"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=12bFw13Xr67TkU4bbtFrXUl__hYnSq5TI"><p><strong>Tarapotor City</strong></p><p>The city was not very orgainzed and full of moto-taxis around!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1aokZLMGFD2AEOIlVrcUctcF0-30678vV"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1vTI7jKUtaUGnBIvfUleQ2xQFdmmBm8s7"><h2 id="Ukru-Center"><a href="#Ukru-Center" class="headerlink" title="Ukru Center"></a>Ukru Center</h2><p>Since there was not much to see and to do at the city, I decided to go to Ukru center. It’s a non-profit animal rescue center which was about 20-minute mototaxi away from the city. Before you continue, I do NOT recommend you go there. It is a really small center with about at most 15 species animals at most. A guide will take you for the tour but only speaks Spanish and the tour last at most 45 minutes. I don’t think it worth a visit. But if you decide to go, here is what to expect.</p><p>First pay for 20 soles for the moto taxi for round trip from the Plaza de Armas. The driver will wait you at the entrance. Then take around 20 minutes bumpy ride on a muddy road. Yes, it is UNPAVED as many other roads around Peruvian non-major cities. Not a surprise here. The problem was that day, the rain pouring down on us from the very begin of my tour to the center. So no wonder, I came back wet and muddy again! It was 2-hours after my shower and clean summer outfit change…</p><p>The driver and the muddy road condition:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1IXrBI5PlJgzcwMRa56Q1hDRTtkb9rZ80"><p>After paying 10 soles for the ticket, here are some sample animals at the center:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Q86QFwAOVWyPYmwZGsiaXNL0Faqr82zN"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1aeLjGcyDJsfofKK9lJcOC7vd8NMoTqTX"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1kdXnSNesSVOzHtgHPnR8qHtczFVA5N_V"><p>Oh, I forgot to mention, there were armies of mosquitoes, millions of them!!! Please be prepared for your battle with mosquitoes.</p><p><strong>Total cost: 30 soles (20 soles for moto taxi and 10 soles for the ticket)</strong></p><h2 id="Laguna-Azul"><a href="#Laguna-Azul" class="headerlink" title="Laguna Azul"></a>Laguna Azul</h2><p>The second day at Tarapoto, I went to the famous Laguna Azul (the blue lake) with a day tour. Yes, I was exhuasted at that time to go on my own. Remember my Gocta nightmare? Here was what I got from Gocta, my hiking shoes got broken and luckily I found a small shop to get temporal fix so that hopefully it will last to Lima again.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1W0AdaJT33GGUB8Rmihln9dBOxFSOEjCd"><p>Laguana Azul was recommended by many people if you can only go one spot around Tarapoto. So I went. However, it was again raining heavily on the day… But I think the place worth a visit if the weather was nice and there are severval luxury hotels around the lake, can be very romantic and relaxing vaction there. For me, it was just a tour and experience. I was alone and it was rainning heavily, what I could do there except getting myself all wet and then dry several times in the rain/sweat and in the sun…</p><p>To get there, you need to take about an hour drive on the paved road :) then you need a ferry to across Huallaga River.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1TIV_7D9I3iLwOM-mlAENlLoIAAJ2UfAG"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1B62KyI7KIrgjYcGh1cpmRh0PMHg1wI3O"><p>After the ferry, it is another 1-hour drive on the unpaved mountain muddy road again. But the views were amazing! </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1PiRGhgmuyRwhIJmPQzFXjbL_tjb-eUZI"><p>Finally, we hit the lake. Please note, this is a colored picture. Check out how heavy was the rain on that day!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DiJMfcZrSD-JcVGAdZbU18gj4VO56HtZ"><p>And some ‘colorful’ pictures of around Lagunas Azul:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1uRjwnukBCR_i5KKc14BW8jlqEcBb-K88"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1f04URkcmNKN1pkrB9B4yibx9IRNy8tf6"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1BTVYqbOzT835WGhwIgLoTugmF8vEds2R"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_YhLpVaT0tp5GjFk1SQppnVSZbdBYszb"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1mzII2KSPpiiBqMlqcbMBrqMlQd1fNT0L"><p><strong>Total Cost: 70 soles for the day tour including a 2-course lunch (if you plan to stay there, you can go to there on your own)</strong></p><h2 id="Food-in-Tarapoto"><a href="#Food-in-Tarapoto" class="headerlink" title="Food in Tarapoto"></a>Food in Tarapoto</h2><p>Food in Tarapoto is very cheap and tasted fine. I have been eating mostly at street stands with a indoor seating area with ONLY local people. Again, how far I could walk in the rain or with rain coming in the next few minutes?</p><p>Chicken Stew with Papaya Juice (no spanish name provided)</p><p>Cost: 7 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1h4_SRDkuYFvX2zW7_Ezy4KRzk4IcD0H7"><p>Beef Stew, grilled chicken and pork large intestine (no spanish name provided)</p><p>Cost: beef stew 7 soles, grilled chicken 2 soles and intestine 3 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1mfN-8HTYtpKQWK2jX9ARdJCyzx5-btjV"><p>Laguna Azul Lunch (special steamed lake fish wrapped in banana leaf) –&gt; very delicious!!!</p><p>Cost: included in the tour</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1SRpcNmuP3RFGNBBy17rwGScvruWXmAB-"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1fNONOOEJGbbdrvgnPQd3HPmdMLY9CNZ_"><p>Chicken Stew and grilled chicken  (no spanish name provided)</p><p>Cost: chicken stew 7 soles and grilled chicken 3.5 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1UgrydqndjMxGa5xlTbm7JvQSB3OKgEbq"><p>Continental Breakfast at my hotel</p><p>Cost: 7 soles</p><p>The piture was the original food provided. Then I asked for a refill of the papaya juice and extra bread…I don’t know why most Peruvian eat very few food (check out the pitures above, I normally order extra potein for my meal). The waitress had to go out to buy extra bread for me. Peruvian people, you really need to eat more to grow!!! To most of Peruvian people, they are only at my should or chest height…</p><p>To my dear mom, you are right! I am wasting food and cloth…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1aWr-TN__Y06vuQx5abwIUX2ihB9Deq5W"><h1 id="Yurimaguas"><a href="#Yurimaguas" class="headerlink" title="Yurimaguas"></a>Yurimaguas</h1><p>Yurimaguas is just a transfer point for me to go into Pacaya Samiria Amazon Reservation for the jungle tour.</p><h2 id="The-Ride-to-Yurimaguas"><a href="#The-Ride-to-Yurimaguas" class="headerlink" title="The Ride to Yurimaguas"></a>The Ride to Yurimaguas</h2><p>So far, I have taken several long and short rides in Peru already. This one was a special record. First, there is no scheduled bus to Yurimaguas. You just go to a taxi center and sign up there. The cost was 20 soles for the 2-hour drive. I went there at around 10:30am and luckily there was already another guy waiting to go inside the taxi. So I started waiting for the third passenger. After one hour, nobody came. I figuired out that the taxi driver needs 3 people to go and I started my chat with the Peruvian guy using Google Translate. He already waited for more than 3 hours?! So I typed ‘how about we both pay 30 soles and we can go now?‘’ He said ‘si!’. So we started happily until we arrived the moutain…</p><p>This ride was the <strong>ROLLER COASTER RIDE</strong>!!! I would like to thank god and my taxi driver for not killing me during the ride! I was both mentally and physically sick during the 2-hour ride and I have closed my eyes hundreds times…</p><p>To illustrate what route we took, please check this cruvy downhill mountian route:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1TfmrOGb6i4oechtY6bY5PsOHZDI_R7zW"><p>My taxi drive should consider to start his F1 career. He passed all the cars/moto-taix/trucks in front of us, at double yellow lines, at U-shaped downhill turns, at curvy uphill turns and any conditions as long as there is something in front! Nothing would stop him getting us to Yurimaguas! If the speed limit is 30kmh, he drove at 60-70kmh. For speed limits at 60kmh, his limit was 100-120kmh! Also, he had his lunch, answered phone calls and chatted with another Peruvian passenger.</p><p>The view along the moutain drive was gorgerous and you can smell all the fresh plants! Thank god, otherwise I may puke…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1lcLsqCjVYKIyNDYcCT8AUb9le_ku4j7Z"><p>There are several waterfalls to visit at Tarapoto. I saw at least 2-3 waterfall entrances along the way. With this view, I can imagine the waterfalls would be great! Now you may ask why did I visit any? Again, I was hurt by the Gocta waterfall. At this moment, I have NO interests in any of them. But I heard the hikes to those waterfalls in the rainforests are only 2-3 hours. I don’t know if that is for round trip. People told me it only took 2.5 hours to Gocta but I ended up with 7 hours including 1 hour horse ride back…</p><h2 id="The-Amazaon-Tour"><a href="#The-Amazaon-Tour" class="headerlink" title="The Amazaon Tour"></a>The Amazaon Tour</h2><p>I signed up with <a href="http://www.peruselva.com/index.php/our-agency/huayruro-tours-lagunas" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Huaruro Tours Lagunas</a>. They have an office at <a href="http://www.hotelriohuallaga.com.pe/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Hotel Rio Huallaga</a>, Yurimaguas. The hotel is probably the best hotel in Yurimaguas, with great location (next to Plaza de Armas and the river), a bar, a restaurant, conference rooms, rooms with AC etc. The manager (or owner of the hotel) also runs the tour agency here greeted me. He is the only one who speaks English. The Huaruro Tours’s main office is at Lagunas. You may do it at a cheaper price there. However, according to my understanding, nobody speaks English at Lagunas…</p><p>Orignally, I planned for a 7-day tour inside  Pacaya Samiria but I saw his map, if you spend 12 days you can cover everything inside. So I signed up for 12 days! With some negotiations, the final daily cost for the tour was lowered to 160 soles from 165 soles… The final total cost for this tour is 1920 soles including all meals, transport from Lagunas to/from and inside Pacaya Samiria, all stays, and one guide who only speaks Spanish for me. </p><p>I was planning to take the cargo slow boat to Lagunas for about 12-hour. The manager successfully persuaded me to take the 3-hour speed boat, which will depart at 6:00am tomorrow morning. Starting from September 6, I will be in the Amazaon jungle alone with a Spanish speaking local guide and a canoe. Of course, no WiFi for the entire 12 days. And for the first one or two nights, I may have 2 hours of electricity to charge my devices if I am lucky…Let’s see if I will successfully make it through and if it worth to stay for 12 days~ I will update my Amazon tour later.  The good news is, I can ask the guide to take me back at anytime without refund of course :)</p><h2 id="Yurimaguas-City"><a href="#Yurimaguas-City" class="headerlink" title="Yurimaguas City"></a>Yurimaguas City</h2><p>It is a port city and to my understanding, most tourists only come here for the boat to Lagunas or Iquitos. Also, I am going to only stay over one night and leaving tomorrow morning at 5am to Lagunas. So there are some pictures for my 1-hour breif walk around the city. Its Plaza de Armas is better than the one in Tarapoto with a sky blue colored church.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1qeUnAx0cUMAnK806aur4S5MzofIGEBPS"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Vta0vwGokUMGUFItmPlNgJ95Yotep9oU"><p>The port at the Huallaga River and my Cargo Boat! Sorry, I really wanted to take you to Lagunas…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1dcV1ub0qQcJ9EbPMlUqbzKckVQyozut1"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1wQIYtxth71XxXonAaXgsZCTPJLgdSQS6"><p>Some pitures of the city’s local streets and people:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1-oZXfXZnaS5gOHucWzsD91zE_nGMXfnx"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=10kXWt7mQifw1xwJmYC8vzvizwa8MLtWx"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1pYNsDbl6cZfgWVpCu7YDOl1g1yaj6vTU"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1zqNsYwltAkv-KnyJ0XzQw9KcxkGYvgu1"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1XjU9Tzq4pgB1hBtDUStMNHtvJU8BpCz6"><h1 id="Log"><a href="#Log" class="headerlink" title="Log"></a>Log</h1><p>Tarapoto stay from September 3 to September 5, 2019 </p><p>Yurimaguas stay from Setember 5 to Septermber 5, 2019</p><p>Next stop: Lagunas (speed boat leaving Yurimaguas at 6:00 am, Septermber 6, 2019)</p><p><strong>Lan is going to 12-day Amazon tour in Pacaya Samiria without WiFi and Electricity! Also my local guide will only speak Spanish! God bless me!!! If everything goes fine, I should be back to the civilized world on Septemer 17, 2019.</strong></p><p><em>This post was published at Yurimaguas, September 5, 2019.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=1PiRGhgmuyRwhIJmPQzFXjbL_tjb-eUZI&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Tarapoto" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Tarapoto/"/>
    
      <category term="Laguna Azul" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Laguna-Azul/"/>
    
      <category term="Urku Zoo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Urku-Zoo/"/>
    
      <category term="Yurimaguas" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Yurimaguas/"/>
    
      <category term="Amazon Tour" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Amazon-Tour/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Chachapoyas</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/fccd4861/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/fccd4861/</id>
    <published>2019-08-31T19:47:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.473Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1zyHjBjwZ9-sCVEe96bNWxlMfWOzb6Iv8"><a id="more"></a><h1 id="Kuelap"><a href="#Kuelap" class="headerlink" title="Kuelap"></a>Kuelap</h1><div class="note info">            <p>Kuélap was a walled settlement built by the people of the Chachapoyas culture in the 6th century AD. It is situated high atop a ridge overlooking the Utcubamba Valley below. The site is home to over 550 stone structures in total and may have had a population of over 300,000 people during its heyday. Now it is considered one of the most important ruins in all of the Americas, the home to many culturally significant artifacts. The walls are lined with many interesting geometric and linear designs, as well as its famous “zig zag” friezes which are highly representative of the site.</p>          </div><p>So I arrived Chachapoyas after a 12-hour overnight bus ride from Cajamarca at 6:30 am. I made it to my hostel El Dorado very close to the Plaza de Armas (yes, there is one Plaza de Armas in each city I visited in Peru) at 7am. Without any rests, I went out to the plaza and there are lots of tour agencies around. After some quick searches, I signed up for a day tour to Kuelap for 90 soles with English guide service. This was my first tour in my backpacking trip, the major reason for this was that it’s better that someone tell you what’s the history and stories behind the site and second I was exhausted  after the very unpleasant bus ride. I was the only foreigner in our group of about 20 people. Not many foreigners visit Northern Peru. Of course, if you only have 2-3 weeks of vacation, you hit the most famous sites like Machu Picchu. Also according to my guide, I was the first Chinese here this year. So I got the nick name as Panda. Really, several people came to me just to take a photo with me?! It was my first time to be asked to have photos with others.</p><p>Anyway, the tour started at 8:15am. We met at the tour angent’s office and walked to the parking lot to board the minivan to Neuvo Tingo. It’s about one hour drive in the mountain. From there, we took the cable car to Kuelap. Yes, I chose not to hike there! As my guide told me, all the infrastructures were invested by a French company. The infrastructure is AMAZING! The restroom was the cleanest public one so far during my visit and they have a cafe both in the cable car platform and on the top of the hill at the starting of the trail head.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1LSgDTiU6e9fd4Kjq7rqixKiWNLaN31HK"><p>The one at the top has fantastic view and it’s perfect for a cup of hot coffee in the chilly morning! However, if you are taking the tour, it’s impossible for you to take your time at anytime. I felt like a sheep being herded by the guide and rushed to walk along with him. I was the only foreigner and I had to walk with him at all times and ‘Please Lan, never walk in front me!’</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ubu7xMkjACz-5mGGcW29PtdJ_AA0Nd8-"><p>The cable car takes 8 people and took about 20 minutes. I took the ride with our guide and he explained many things along the ride which was very nice. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1yKXeWsB-WywGts5tO0L_5MHOA3ECztCd"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ZwvlajSJECna0EwaqKPxMaFQzifcIt3I"><p>Once you get to the top, there is a 30-minute hike uphill to the Kuelap site. Or you can pay 15 soles to rent a horse. I did walk to the site. Then, the fortress appeared.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1-ZP0GKaVZSWf-_2os0Sw9t7fUCFXGYwM"><p>We spent about 2 hours inside the Kuelap and stopped at several locations for the stories and histroy of the Kuelap. You can spend much longer and wait for the cword to pass by so that you can take better pictures. However, I did not have the luxury of taking my time. I was a panda and fully protected and herded by our guide. So below is my tourist pictures taken at Kuelap.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1qJ-eES2Qd_UtwGaNSPK1419HMGiYhQ46"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1w2LDBFy0OFwZ18YpuVHtvsFGhvpO5OBP"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=13zvSs7J10bEiB8e0bPIEjx0lzt0HD-13"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1zTuRT-8hhYVLXUBeIGWh-FWSnKp6r_8K"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1KbqOsr5uueQ6JaiuBEhkxv6cOHaFrDv3"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=10U1goA0uaiPKDoCOHzidISvZjUDRa7LK"><p>Here is some of the interesting things I learnt from my guide about the ancient Chachapoyas people.</p><ul><li>They live with their guinea pig inside the house (see the picture below, there is a curved small stone wall)</li><li>They bury dead people’s skeleton inside the house and live with them. The belief was the ‘dead’ people would protect them?! (see there is a hole in the center of the house)</li><li>Human sacrifice was found at the site.</li></ul><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=12LcKAhvXkFPLmjSYwM1jRhy10JcBtEG-"><p>Then from the guide, I learnt other interesting things in Peru:</p><ul><li>There are over 3,000 kinds of potato in Peru and you will need to spend your entire life time to taste all of them.</li><li>The average height of Peruvian male is 165cm and female is 160cm. I googled later, according to Wiki, the average female height is only 151cm! So most of the people I met are about to my shoulder’s height. Yes, the bump into my chest many times since I frequently stopped at interestions to look for directions to go next.</li></ul><p>All in all, I thought it was a good choice to go with the tour so that you can know more about the site. There is NO English signs inside! Unless you just want to walk around or do all your study online, you may consider to go with a tour. </p><h2 id="Independent-Tour-Cost"><a href="#Independent-Tour-Cost" class="headerlink" title="Independent Tour Cost:"></a>Independent Tour Cost:</h2><ul><li>bus to Neuvo Tingo: 7 soles one-way</li><li>cable car ticket: 20 soles round trip</li><li>entrance ticket: 20 soles</li></ul><p>So if you go on your own, it will cost you about 54 soles. The tour also include a lunch so you’d save 25 soles at most. </p><p><strong>IMPORTANT: Kuelap is closed every Monday and Peruvian holiday. The cable car closes at 4pm. Please check their website before you go if you decide to go on your own.</strong></p><h1 id="Virgen-Asunta-Fiestas"><a href="#Virgen-Asunta-Fiestas" class="headerlink" title="Virgen Asunta Fiestas"></a>Virgen Asunta Fiestas</h1><p>My first day (August 29, 2019) at Chachapoyas was exhausting, arriving at 6am then went to Kuelap for during the day. At night, I planned to sleep early. However, music was ON (my hostel was 30m away from the Plaza de Armas). So I went out to check what’s going on. Wow, there was a big event for Virgen Asunta festival. The Peruvian president was visiting the city also he went to Kuelap on the same day. Check out how Chachapoyas people celebrate with singing, dancing and fireworks! I also gave my first dancing performance in the public! I was dragged to the stage to dance with chicas with other people for 3 minutes!!!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HfAj6kZTKvJHcIe2sfG-cxwydR_GpWPr"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1d6GHUSXg5A3QkItKDRDDFK52fQNBykPy"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_P8Iy-3KgRThhzysLtNsMh9lkhjReqXd"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1OUvqyLXaAR2yUQjTr-VSjDXeyymADxGx"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1SrZ1AcobT2l5vDm7qXk5FS0zBwuwBlKJ"><p>It was a joyful night with friendly local people! </p><h1 id="Gocta-Waterfall"><a href="#Gocta-Waterfall" class="headerlink" title="Gocta Waterfall"></a>Gocta Waterfall</h1><p>Gocta waterfall is the second most popular sites in Chachapoyas. It is ranked 3-5 highest in the world and was discovered only recently 2002? Sounds amazing right? NO! My trip to there turned out to be a nightmare! I went there on my own and hiked 6 hours (16km) all alone in the mountain. The hike is NOT flat and at an altitude of approximately 2700m. On the entire trail, there is only one sign! It also rained twice in the afternoon. So I got myself wet to dry and wet again to dry while walking downhills on the slippery rocky and muddy trail. It was a strenuous hike at least to me. I started at 10am and at 4pm I finally met some local people with horses. I paid 20 soles for a horse to take me to the village. You know, the last mile is always the most expensive but the money was well spent! It even took the horse almost an hour to the village and 70% was uphill!!</p><p>I started from Sao Pablo and ended with Cocachimba. This route was suggested by a Peruvian couple I met on the minibus. They told me it was an easier route with much less uphill, which it was but only relatively easier.</p><p>On my way to the trailhead, I was still energetic to take pictures along the way. The second picture seems to be coffee beans. They have great organic Amazon coffee here in the region!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1OmMQp9vMWSHNxNbE0_CkbImnPRnKXYID"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=17vJvAriZYPngJtTuK8faYzMUhU32CJ31"><p>The only living creatures I met on the hike for the first couple of hours.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=11lvO-ekGyrDdkN6Vc29t4ylnOBmlqilt"><p>The views and the waterfall. Check it out and decide if the hike is worth it!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1zHS9pIPxugFpcl4Uc4jMFEPx6f7rUmdc"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_TYD9KRMppPH9sj6Ycu9c6FzBUJch1JC"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1qBEagvBL-SfVNrMDmYUyj2p84iWIHiFR"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1vKHVYH3CM19zwxGUZ1NzNH9d0NJ6Duir"><h2 id="Tips-and-Cost"><a href="#Tips-and-Cost" class="headerlink" title="Tips and Cost"></a>Tips and Cost</h2><p>My personal suggestion is do NOT go there unless you really love hiking! But if you decide to go, here are some tips.</p><p>The easier route is start from Sao Pablo (higher level) and get down to Cocachimba. However, Cocachimba is the common starting and ending point. The facilities there are more developed.</p><p><strong>Independent:</strong></p><p>Minibus: 5 soles to get to the intersection to either Cocachimba or Sao Pablo</p><p>Mototaxi: 5 soles per person to get to one of the village (if you are solo traveler and don’t want to wait, just pay 10 soles)</p><p>Gocta entrance ticket: 20 soles</p><p><strong>Tours:</strong></p><p>Day tour cost is 50 soles. But probably you will start and end at Cocachimba.</p><h1 id="Chachapoya-City-and-Food"><a href="#Chachapoya-City-and-Food" class="headerlink" title="Chachapoya City and Food"></a>Chachapoya City and Food</h1><p>In general, Chachapoya is really a chill city and good as a resting stop. You will find fine dining restaurants as well.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1hKqQ_W7Qr2DJc9bo2epHrvKkLTNm9bLl"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1zyHjBjwZ9-sCVEe96bNWxlMfWOzb6Iv8"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1kMW7tH8oKG1r3qqtMf5_dIXAFQn8Aht2"><p>There are events going on almost everyday during my stay! </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1hhOUekOKw2WlyOfC1bFFUt1lYLGX_BRz"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=15AH9ywN72hU9jszalOs4VtNl6XbXD7Xo"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=18akqk8yGwyr1_UkD0a7SnUMQ92Tz7bWD"><h2 id="The-Local-Food-and-Drink"><a href="#The-Local-Food-and-Drink" class="headerlink" title="The Local Food and Drink"></a>The Local Food and Drink</h2><p>The famous guinea pig! It’s very tender and taste good. With only one problem, there is not much meat!!!</p><p>Cost: 15 soles for 1/4 and 3 soles pineapple juice</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=16uBZJ5AHNU-Gvjzamo5EwndkF5tdpn2X"><p>One night out with a Peruvian guy (sorry, again I don’t know how to spell his name in Spanish) from Lima! He speaks little English, but there is no way to stop us from chatting. Yes, again, Google Translate. We were continuously chatting face to face with two mobile phones! One night, we went to El Botan one of the best restaurants in Chachapoyas. Check out their cocktail presentation! After that, we stopped by a bar to try Chcachapoyas special liquor made from sugar crane. Lan’s opion, not good. After the tasting, we continued with Peruvian beer only…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1BzUZ__y3KrF2eEGHGLiUIjwXM-IN0GpV"><p>Ceviche de Cecina de res al Maracuya (my entrée) and Eucalipto Amazonico (my cocktail made with pisco and amazon leaves very tasty!!!)</p><p>Cost: 25 soles for the ceviche and 14 soles for the cocktail</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1qgTYlH7qQXxTaw4PqR7PAuKY54fVYklE"><p>The rainbow: 20 soles for all below</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1aXKr3VjrVouKSvX1perto0xN4MdLWFM4"><p>Another upscale dinner alone (that was the date of Gocta)</p><p>I don’t remember what I ordered. The taste was just OK. </p><p>Cost: soup 14 soles, entree 25 soles and papaya juice 5 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DTyPOLg97EkGSGixAL6zGUKcadlS0gG7"><p>Sopa de Pollo</p><p>Cost: 12 soles with 3 soles for mixed juice</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1cJG3FdQI2VkWY67H-JbsqZvXa2ouRjQi"><p>Aguadito + Humita + Papaya Juice</p><p>Cost: 6.5 soles for all three </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1RXdGI095HIiDsszSNqh_f7ethVdWL2-s"><p>Lastly, morning organic Amazon coffee in my hostel balcony</p><p>Cost: FREE</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Fsrz3JnLetnZ0qlMPlfjFbjSYnESb3Xz"><h1 id="Log"><a href="#Log" class="headerlink" title="Log"></a>Log</h1><p>Chachapoya stay from August 29 to September 2, 2019.</p><p>Next stop: Tarapoto (bus leaving Chachapoyas at 8:30pm, Sep. 2, 2019)</p><p><em>This post was published at Chachapoyas on September 2, 2019.</em></p><div class="note info">            <p>Special thanks to HZ! Starting from this post, all photos will be resized and compressed for a better user experience and hopefully faster loading!</p>          </div>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=1zyHjBjwZ9-sCVEe96bNWxlMfWOzb6Iv8&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Peru" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Peru/"/>
    
      <category term="Chachapoyas" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Chachapoyas/"/>
    
      <category term="Kuelap" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Kuelap/"/>
    
      <category term="Gocta Waterfall" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Gocta-Waterfall/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>La Granja Porcon</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/cb2821a6/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/cb2821a6/</id>
    <published>2019-08-30T18:26:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.475Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1J7V1KolUMnxrVvMmWMGAMMust9hHrwqw"><a id="more"></a><p>Oh, La Granja Porcon, you made me felt like home! I escaped Cajamarca city after only one night stay. I really do not like Cajamarca city including the people there (at least the ones I met). Originally, I just planned to stay only for a night but ended up staying four days there! Every time, I went around people just smiled and greeted me. With my limited Spanish, I made friends with many local people! The very last morning, I said goodbye to my amigos and amigas. We hugged and they made me cried (yes, strong and tough as I am, cried a little secretly in their zoo alone)…I was so touched and they really treated me like their own family!</p><h1 id="The-Beautiful-La-Granja-Porcon-and-Their-Warm-Hearted-People"><a href="#The-Beautiful-La-Granja-Porcon-and-Their-Warm-Hearted-People" class="headerlink" title="The Beautiful La Granja Porcon and Their Warm-Hearted People"></a>The Beautiful La Granja Porcon and Their Warm-Hearted People</h1><p>Words are not enough to express my feelings of the farm and their people. You need to check it out on your own! Most people only go there for a day tour from Cajamarca. Most tourists arrive after 10am and leave before 5pm. If you stay at the farm, you own it outside the tourist period.</p><h2 id="The-Nature"><a href="#The-Nature" class="headerlink" title="The Nature"></a>The Nature</h2><p>The landscape and wild animals on saw on my hikes. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ywxjV5R4EnIIpCnIZ5EUI_VQeKM4KQ-5"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1RqKXrM8Zv4Qo4Ba33FqX5Qse_fTcRfFx"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1BufUMIr1kGL-srtkd9pPCtrk_KIIYAuA"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1NM4StH6G73F0PyTypAvmccfRbTUpO9VL"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=17I4IEdMAjCes6s9p8lIx_korW7DvkXjm"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1qV0Qo7lior3GijSd0btsgh1RYGLl0VXf"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Y9FOeyREgtJX_G6H3cqH5yUBwwVBdV0s"><h2 id="Their-People-Mi-Amigas-and-Amigos"><a href="#Their-People-Mi-Amigas-and-Amigos" class="headerlink" title="Their People - Mi Amigas and Amigos"></a>Their People - Mi Amigas and Amigos</h2><p>The hostel keeper and my tour guide (sorry, I don’t know how to spell her Spanish name). She filled my wood supplies for the fire place, cleaned the room, rushed to my room and pulled me out of my bed for hiking tours, and hugged me almost everyday.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1dXfUHBCPkMVkiLwU7E0PQSEhm4h5Jxjr"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=12hL1daMoJZc3ZphZLYqRAUNCT3wM7Lfx"><p>The waitress at the restaurant. She fed me every meal and sent me pieces of paper in Spanish every time we met. The last piece of message paper I received was back to my middle school days. So warm and we communicated via paper and Google translate. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=13aCtEnWPVlp4wq9Ux5oUCGzv7y7GqHYA"><p>The Dairy Store Keeper - greeted me every morning for my breakfast supplies. Oh, the farm is famous for their dairy product in Peru!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1qgl8SJ8qJxtwjvonToMlvdP5cd4UkRfF"><p>The Variety Store Keeper - my daily water provider. I visited her store 2-3 times a day.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1wQX5DpWIYIKwwMSoRyFf0uR5jaUQyrgD"><p>The Uncle at Parking Lot - he directed me to everywhere although sometimes I was still at lost. Totally my bad! Mi poquito Español…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1c0Ak6Bi4VkW0oMssgizL_J9VwpTmO9T2"><p><strong>Pedro - The manager of the farm</strong></p><p>He is such a great person! No matter of what you need, find him and he will help you at all his best. He organized my hostel (took me visited all four hostels located in the farm before I decided which one to stay), helped me joined the day hike (8-Hour Hike!) and dairy farm visit with a group of middle school students from Lima. The last day, I met him to say goodbye and he was worried me getting back to Cajamarca. He put me in a car of Peru Ministry of Agriculture and sent me back to the city for free. </p><p>You can find him at his office in the farm’s main square. Since he is very busy and running around helping locals and visitors, if he is not at the office, just ask anybody in the main square and people will help you locate him. </p><p><strong>Note: if you don’t speak Spanish, bring Google Translate. The farm also has free WiFi around the main square!</strong></p><h2 id="The-Dairy-Farm"><a href="#The-Dairy-Farm" class="headerlink" title="The Dairy Farm"></a>The Dairy Farm</h2><p>It is about an hour hiking to the dairy farm. But it is totally worth it! I guess if you only go there for a day tour, you may not make it. I had my first milking experience there, amazing!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1p3q6YCvrIo-iIUA3IC4J8iDXRjaFIPTg"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1G1n5NerM2CZrNL5U1mthTriePV5XTLrT"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1eq2GjN6-WmY-S4OtPQPT5WHIfcDTG7Zc"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1OeYj-72q08VqG-9hZqz-SsTKiosBlAvT"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1qWs_2qMGGewkHFp1NtrxgC4KkX9W8xke"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1XOkfssZP7Eq8LZjM1YdNawm5UlCU7bQD"><h2 id="Their-Zoo"><a href="#Their-Zoo" class="headerlink" title="Their Zoo"></a>Their Zoo</h2><p>Yes, they have a zoo. The entrance fee to the farm is only 7 soles and including the zoo and most of the places for visit at the farm. The zoo is quite big and with many interesting animals.</p><p>The first thing I do each morning before my breakfast was take a walk in the zoo alone without any tourists. The animals were all active and run to the fence to say hola! I one-finger petted one of the lions every day. Not suggest you to do this, maybe dangers :)</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1sBZlL5r4aXyrwCHn14OxyUC6Fv6dXfdr"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1P-tz-cXkTrVy8iBs2wIeIbv1aDCxdGFd"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1CaMihcKCKclZyec21zygyVh5CyfoMXCe"><h2 id="The-Fishery"><a href="#The-Fishery" class="headerlink" title="The Fishery"></a>The Fishery</h2><p>Their trouts are so delicious! You can go fishing and prepare for your own dinner. Again, probably not for a day tour.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DxYei0xL4BSq02XMos-DENh-oiQj0OdJ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1gvKvtof_ISDbMJ-lD_81zC3HYC37uPDn"><h1 id="My-Experience-at-the-Farm"><a href="#My-Experience-at-the-Farm" class="headerlink" title="My Experience at the Farm"></a>My Experience at the Farm</h1><p>My original plan was just to relax at the farm. You know it, have a cup of coffee in the morning, update my blog in my room in front of the breathtaking view of the Andes. Then take a nap in the afternoon. </p><p>The very next day  morning upon arrival, I was taking my daily morning wondering around relaxingly before the tourists arrive. Pedro caught me on the road. I took out my phone and opened Google translate. He typed ‘They are going to the Inca bridge and come with me!’. Who are they and where is Inca bridge? Without any clues, I got into his car and I went back to the main square. He made several calls and typed in my Google Translate ‘They are having breakfast and we meet here at 9am’. So I went to the dairy store and bought some bread and had one cup of coffee at the restaurant. At 9am, I got back in his car with my hostel keeper and guide. He typed again ‘Do you have snacks and water for the road?’ I showed him my 500ml water supply from the variety store and 3 mini left over bread. So we started. At that time, I didn’t know what I signed up for… There is a bridge located about 1km away from the main squire. However, the drive took 20min into the mountain! Then there was a group of kids, he dropped me off. So I joined the day hike with a group of twelve-year-old chicos and chicas with three teachers. Again, nobody speaks fluent English. We started our hike at 9:30 am. We walked through the rocky roads, grass lands, muddy paths, creeks, spotted vicunas, alpacas, llams, variety of Cajamarca birds… Along the way, I finally learnt how to count one to ten in Spanish and picked up some Spanish words taught by the kids. In exchange, I taught them Chinese.</p><p>The hike ended at 5:30pm without lunch! During the hike, I was wondering if I could ever made it to the destination. It was mountains after mountains, grass land without a path, muddy and rocky roads after muddy and rocky roads…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Dyrs5B5I79TaQLMBf3GXS8zafTRTUgsN"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=15JzwjpxgryIhSY83K8EEP1s_kArQES-9"><p>I was so jealous of this lady having a horse along the endless roads.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1S5ZR77ijf5CLiNdoNMqC81_YhGUX7nrn"><p>Using my very limited Spanish, I asked how far away are we from the end. My guide told me a little more. After one hour, we are still in the middle of nowhere! Then I asked again, finally, one of the teacher told me about 15 minutes! Another hour later, I was at the top of the highest view point of the farm. There I saw the main square, miles and miles away?! Do you know how desperate I was at that time?! When I arrived, everybody clapped! Then we turned back to the way we came! Another 45 minutes later, I met the rest of the group. Only 1/3 of us made it to the top! The rest of the group just waited and rested in the turn point! What was why I received the clapping! Oh my, if I ever knew!!! I must started to learn Spanish as soon as possible.</p><p>The heroes and heroines who made to the top!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1gYR_hL3v0PbCJSLmfh638WjeaRW92UgQ"><p>See how far is my casa from the view point!!!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=147MBBG6KMSbeAhmpsOmPM5wFS4z0vOqr"><p>We finally made it to the group hostel! I only had a very small breakfast and 500ml water for the hiking. I was starving and exhausted. There we had our dinner together. Such a small plate and no meat. Only trout was available! I was dreaming of ordering two entrees at the restaurant… No I know why Peruvians are so small in figure! People you need to eat more!!!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1A1gN92HqC4L4UxhhsrVpgwpqXRypD9vj"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=15njvJfAJLaDC_k6PbDzuJZuQCFdITamt"><p>The day after the hiking, my entire body was souring and aching. I was determined to have a rest day and definitely not walking at all! After the morning walk in the zoo, I rented a horse! See how smart I was! After an hour horse riding, I was not getting very far and my butt hurts…So I returned to the main square had my lunch and went back to my hostel to have a nap. At around 3pm, my amiga rushed in and pulled me out for a tour. Based on her body language, I understood that we were going to the dairy farm. So I got up and arrived the main square. There I saw the kids group! Oh my god! Bad feelings again!!! Yes, it turned out to be a 3.5 hour hiking for the round trip to and from the dairy farm and pine tree nursery…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HaGeEhPMy2bb0Vm_HmyOE_AXaSi4cftb"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1elNoW_xJXy6Pksnomnz52LUiTavZXnN8"><h1 id="How-to-Get-to-Granja-Porcon-and-the-Cost"><a href="#How-to-Get-to-Granja-Porcon-and-the-Cost" class="headerlink" title="How to Get to Granja Porcon and the Cost"></a>How to Get to Granja Porcon and the Cost</h1><p>From Cajamarca, you can take a taxi (50 soles) or a bus to Sao Pablo (5 soles). It is about an hour drive. I paid 10 soles and you know why I don’t like the Cajamarca people and this is only one unpleasant case of several I encountered. The bus will drop you off at the entrance of the farm. Then you need to walk about 5km to the main square. Of course, you can wait and there maybe taxis passing by. I was picked up by a pick-up truck. Sitting on the trunk of it, I had a 15 minute bumpy and dusty ride. But it’s for free. See how nice are the people there.</p><p>The entrance ticket is 7 soles. I stayed at one of hostel for a shared dorm for 20 soles a night there. However, I was the only one in the entire hostel!!! Very peaceful with wood burning fire place every night and beautiful views of Andes! There are five hostels in the farm and definitely you can find one you like!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1w4h1fYXyEeENjKrRF8scMoXo7c8gEp_V"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1EBDgW8z3gIKkmlXidQG8kexhbNG6U9Bg"><p>The food I had at the farm!</p><p>The grand plate of Granja Porcorn with 1/4 guinea pig. Enough for two but friends you know me well! I had it all alone!</p><p>Cost: 35 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1yd4MStYRO0YwA2IA_opkYZJ934llS5NO"><p>The Wild Mushroom Plate with passion fruit juice</p><p>Cost: 17 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1sECWGU8jHtNlDCHNe9BR1G8KxmYw-Mfe"><p>One of my breakfast - yes they put hot water in the coffee cup and coffee in the milk cup?! Also I brought the raspberry jam (2 soles) and the bread (1 soles) from the dairy store.</p><p>Cost: 9 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1mPuxEwvf-gT8kKMnfPXhyVmWq8sgTNtv"><p>The Trout (This is after the 8-hour hike…too small for me)</p><p>Cost: 12 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1QfOYIXsvn5UK7YspMTq5kkUg_UwLCpkN"><p>The Granja Porcon Yought</p><p>Cost: 5 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=18BVrtTfbqmZaxXq9iQXI377FvyN9OAt3"><p>My first Coke Zero in South America. Yes, it is a rare find!</p><p>Cost: 2.5 soles</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1YhTc41po3gdeGa-cbfDk8he5328iLM6b"><p>*<em>My total cost for 4 days is less than 200 soles including the tips! *</em></p><h1 id="A-Few-Words-for-Cajamarca"><a href="#A-Few-Words-for-Cajamarca" class="headerlink" title="A Few Words for Cajamarca"></a>A Few Words for Cajamarca</h1><p>Yes, I don’t like you. But to be fair, here is some words for you…</p><p>Cajamarca is 1-hour by flight or 18-hour by bus from Lima. I took the bus with EXCLUCIVA. It offers luxury bus with 180° reclining seats each with LCD monitors, GPS system, host, WC, speed controller (90 km/h) and  with dinner and breakfast service. The ticket is 120 soles and the ride was pleasant.</p><p>I did not go for the popular tourist spot. If you are interested for those, you can easily found them online. I only walked around the Plaza de Armas and the Bano del Inca (the hot spring). I only stayed for a day there.</p><h2 id="Cajamarca-City-Center"><a href="#Cajamarca-City-Center" class="headerlink" title="Cajamarca City Center"></a>Cajamarca City Center</h2><p>Some photos just for the record.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1koXIbwE4IMIxPz4O9dG4XJNoaGHZLNxL"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1BQGyEC9Nd7czQ-o7OttHe5oYrYbFjFbv"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1iRImek_ZtbCyqDWU0WnGF8EFnr9y7ui0"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Dg-JuFQlVAJiuuLQZLox0Kbs-m_A8xsf"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1gKZFS9D8rX9bxFOvEngo6BIY_jDsaVDu"><h2 id="The-Bano-del-Inca"><a href="#The-Bano-del-Inca" class="headerlink" title="The Bano del Inca"></a>The Bano del Inca</h2><p>Ok, this place worth a visit! However, I got there too late and the message service was not offered anymore. They closes at 7:30pm and probably after 5pm, there is no message offered. They also have rooms for 60 soles! You can consider to stay there.</p><p>Cost: 20 soles for a private bathing room, 6 soles for public pool and 20 soles for 30-minute message. For visit ticket, it’s only 3 soles.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1a2mbw1wJDLH100r4bLVwBW88JnZXu8nG"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=15Xuv8OhVusqEBkhY4EsiCbDg536TFHKm"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1iAkPAam9yvvxcM2s0q-HKaG0AePIoqDJ"><h1 id="Log"><a href="#Log" class="headerlink" title="Log"></a>Log</h1><p>Cajamarca stay from August 24 to August 28, 2019 </p><ul><li>La Granja Porcon stay: August 25 to August 28, 2019</li></ul><p>Next stop: Chachapoyas (bus leaving Cajamarca at 6:00pm, August 28, 2019)</p><p><em>This post was published at Chachapoyas on August 30, 2019.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=1J7V1KolUMnxrVvMmWMGAMMust9hHrwqw&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Peru" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Peru/"/>
    
      <category term="La Granja Porcon" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/La-Granja-Porcon/"/>
    
      <category term="Cajamarca" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Cajamarca/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>centralLimaDistrict</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/df50ebdf/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/df50ebdf/</id>
    <published>2019-08-23T20:21:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.476Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1XL4pjHCzua90eYxEIHw4JKeCAMOV0Yz3"><a id="more"></a><p>After almost 24 hours door-to-door multi-mode transportation, I arrived <a href="https://www.1900hostel.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">1900 Backpackers Hostel</a> at 11:30 pm, August 20, 2019, Lima time.</p><p>First image of Lima is lively or very noisy and super busy with impatient drivers and pedestrians…even at midnight, the city is ALIVE! I was born and raised up in Shanghai, China with 25+ millions of people but still it’s a little bit too much. Yes, blame me for 10+ years staying abroad in the countryside.</p><p>Back to the topic, let me show you central Lima through my camera. I will return to Lima once I finish the northern Peru trip. By that time, I will stay in the famous Miraflores district. So Lima to be continued…</p><div class="note info">            <p>This blog started on August 23, 2019 in Lima, Peru. As usual, it was not published on time as planned. Tonight is August 26, 2019, I am in La Granja Porcon, Cajamarca, Peru writing this delayed blog.</p><p>Lastly, I am aware of the weird orientation of some of the pictures. Those photos were taken by my cell phone. This is due to the EXIF (exchangeable image file format) information for orientation that is set ton the images by the phone’s digital camera. Please bear with me for a while, when I have time, all pictures will be fixed. </p>          </div><h1 id="The-Scope-of-This-Post"><a href="#The-Scope-of-This-Post" class="headerlink" title="The Scope of This Post"></a>The Scope of This Post</h1><p>All of my experience and pictures are bounded in the following geographic area, all by foot. I don’t really remember which routes were taken but roughly within the polygon. The second day I discovered that my Suunto watch actually records my GPS location. Later, I will probably be able to share the exact route each day.</p><p> <strong>IMPORTANT: I really want to thank <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.here.app.maps&hl=en_US" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">HERE WeGo</a>!!! I highly recommend everybody to down it. It’s free and offers offline map and navigation is SUPER!!!</strong></p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1WbCL1DD2x89sqU0YyE_RdUrgaKUS0Eg_"><h1 id="Useful-Information"><a href="#Useful-Information" class="headerlink" title="Useful Information"></a>Useful Information</h1><h2 id="ATM-Fee-and-Maximum-Allowed-Amount"><a href="#ATM-Fee-and-Maximum-Allowed-Amount" class="headerlink" title="ATM Fee and Maximum Allowed Amount"></a>ATM Fee and Maximum Allowed Amount</h2><ul><li>BCP: max 700 soles with 13.5 soles ATM fee</li><li>BBVA: max 400 soles with 25 soles ATM fee</li><li>multiRED: I heard max is 400 soles with NO ATM fee. However, I didn’t find it on my first day. Will update later…</li></ul><h2 id="Yellow-Fever-Vaccinate-amp-International-Certificate"><a href="#Yellow-Fever-Vaccinate-amp-International-Certificate" class="headerlink" title="Yellow Fever Vaccinate &amp; International Certificate"></a>Yellow Fever Vaccinate &amp; International Certificate</h2><p>First, yellow fever vaccinate is NOT required in Peru. It is only suggested to take it if you are visiting Amazon region. But Bolivia requires the yellow fever certificate for entry. Also, it takes 10 days to activate the vaccinate. Another option is to take it Cusco, Peru. </p><p>If you are super concerned of getting yellow fever vaccinate in Peru, just take it in your home country. </p><p>Here are my options:</p><ul><li>Phoenix, AZ, USA: $275</li><li>Lima International Airport: 145 soles (it’s open 24/7 and located around gate 11 and 12 it the arrival hall)</li><li>National Institute of Child Health (Instituto Nacional de Salud Del Nino): 30 soles</li></ul><p>I took it at the Instituto Nacional de Salud Del Nino and only paid 30 soles. The location is just about 20 minute walking distance from my hostel. However, the reception told me try Hospital Nacional Arzobispo Loayza. I do NOT speak Spanish and I did it on my first morning in South America in a HUGE city and traffic mode was WALKING. I obtained information and directions from hospital receptions, guards and practice nurses at  Hospital Nacional Arzobispo Loayza and the nurse told me that you can get free yellow fever vaccinate at 8am every Thursday but only Instituto Nacional de Salud Del Nino provides the international certificate. But anyway, I made it! I was very proud of myself.</p><h2 id="Useful-Apps"><a href="#Useful-Apps" class="headerlink" title="Useful Apps"></a>Useful Apps</h2><p>Navigation: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.here.app.maps&hl=en_US" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Here WeGo</a></p><p>Translator: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.translate&hl=en_US" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Google Translate</a></p><p>Both of them offer OFFLINE version and work perfectly!!! Yes, I do not have SIM card and all my digital devices rely 100% on WiFi connection. With these two, I made it for yellow fever vaccinate of course my cute face and body language helped a little bit :)</p><h1 id="The-Colors-of-Lima"><a href="#The-Colors-of-Lima" class="headerlink" title="The Colors of Lima"></a>The Colors of Lima</h1><p>Beautified pictures first. Here are the tourist pictures I took around the central Lima District. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1-_VuHfbH7m3AT1eXFq-jI5b9_AdpMSEt"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1fRrcGVSVmI2dqlprV3lU7zcBhJjD3kFs"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1XL4pjHCzua90eYxEIHw4JKeCAMOV0Yz3"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HKQCIjfCyhwqeM1BsIigJNWXrulnfcKc"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1F1dIIj4fci_ZI6Yjv7JY4QgIILmp7Cn1"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1zzZWiLn6Aqhv1xVS4miYNrkXdc2_lPbU"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=10huGfJYBril7GmAVzl4Y228N864gABa1"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1yFoyZwyfK0yz95LCnHliR4EwgfET8zJQ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1F9we9MTHfwtiJIJqCuQ5SBV5fvomDGUx"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1L2YI3BC0JM-vkiW2dyr1Hl0MuFWSv1TE"><h1 id="Samples-of-Peruvian-Food-and-Drinks"><a href="#Samples-of-Peruvian-Food-and-Drinks" class="headerlink" title="Samples of Peruvian Food and Drinks"></a>Samples of Peruvian Food and Drinks</h1><h2 id="The-Peruvian-Food"><a href="#The-Peruvian-Food" class="headerlink" title="The Peruvian Food"></a>The Peruvian Food</h2><p><strong>1900 Backpackers Hostel Free Breakfast</strong></p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1-ECaoi9qeKmdyZc8u_tg8cHzFj5Z1O5q"><p><strong>Ceviche</strong> (in a street ceviche bar which can only hold max. 8pp)</p><p>Cost: 9 soles</p><p>It’s just ok. But seems to be a local hit.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1sSBodbP313fFP9IMGMgG4SsUFfVm8Su-"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Fll3Zsi14eXhtktxW8LfGnElCuP0dzBP"><p><strong>Lomo Saltado</strong> (upscale downtown restaurant) –&gt; delicious!</p><p>Cost: 36 soles</p><p>OK, I have to say I was a little bit embarrassed to sit in the restaurant with my dirty and loose outdoor gears…next to me, there were a couple. Yes, they were dating and fully prepared…Food and atmosphere were good and they accept credit card!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Xk2AX7P5h-63a05LJmK6iDEh13a8PWkv"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1jmuwdIQox4k9iDSiHaBVG4PK9MRyRjkD"><p><strong>Grilled Beef Heart (Anticuchos)</strong>  –&gt; so far the BEST!</p><p>Cost: 5 soles for two</p><p>Look at this. It’s an art! This street stand offers three plastic chairs for the customers. Before me, two ladies were already waiting for their order and they spoke Spanish to me. Although I didn’t know what they were talking about but must be it’s really delicious and you should try this! So I ordered dos and paid cinco soles all done by body language!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=11BfNkLchuOEgzntMJLaxN5ZdcTnJ4chk"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1vZXajXU-umePUKG3npd1VIU_1B2i_kqz"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1TRcfrdQhIopBRMIKxa-ZmzxOVfDcKv-5"><p><strong>Peruvian Mariscos Rice and Carapulcra Con Sopa Seca</strong> </p><p>Mariscos Rice: 15 soles</p><p>Carapulcra Con Sopa Seca: 3 soles in the picture below. Purchased on the street in the back trunk of an SUV…and friends, it’s noodle for detailed information please google it! I really don’t know what is in it other than the noodle…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1tMNgWVl2iaGc3lB0weOsAPukiG8XE_Ea"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1d8miENPMrVCXn_tzUcm71oaF5CpQLWdd"><p><strong>Quail Eggs (street food)</strong></p><p>Cost: 1 soles for 5 eggs. That night it seemed that I only had crabs (the rice and noodle) so I thought I need to have some protein for the day :0</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1H8yKr1ZFoG57t9asb7N3fCC4hUVp-EiY"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1hDw0V9h-7azbb0fMAlI3OeCVbN7-kn3h"><p><strong>Chifa</strong> –&gt; surprisingly good</p><p>Cost: 18 soles</p><p>Peruvian Chinese food is very popular in Lima and they call it Chifa. It’s everywhere on the street. I had to try it. Ok, I didn’t know what I ordered. Yes, it’s Chinese food but with Peruvian fusion. It’s probably mixed meat and seafood stir fried with some special source. But it turned out to be good better than random Chinese food in the U.S. but I waited about an hour from making the order for the plate to come…too long for the wait. I looked around, everybody was waiting for the food patiently…maybe it’s normal for Chifa to take this long?</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=11g8bV6c0w66gLeB02quB60disH3JMV0r"><h2 id="The-Peruvian-Drinks"><a href="#The-Peruvian-Drinks" class="headerlink" title="The Peruvian Drinks"></a>The Peruvian Drinks</h2><p><strong>Pilsen Callao</strong></p><p>My favorite Peruvian beer with light and crisp taste!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1-YOQIhPHZLPuvWN0jrtJG_KiyB6rZ2dV"><p><strong>Pisco Sour</strong></p><p>Google Keyword: Pisco!!!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1-TVvsij1nwYmkfhSZnQ1QWQIRV7IB8T-"><p><strong>Cusquena</strong></p><p>Not my type but may fit others. Actually it’s a very popular beer with wheaty taste.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1464mlX_ieI7cOm7BNztYJozNTpW-KZ7D"><p><strong>Inca Kola</strong></p><p>I believe it’s the national soda! However, you are NOT cola at all!!! I, Lan, being a loyal coke drinker for 23+yrs, I can tell you are far from COKE!!! Not for me, dear COKE ZERO you are still my love for life!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1gipiLQeH9fnhBoAh_Yl3XYtCslLhNIvP"><h1 id="Personal-Favorites-in-Lima"><a href="#Personal-Favorites-in-Lima" class="headerlink" title="Personal Favorites in Lima"></a>Personal Favorites in Lima</h1><p>I had my two highlights of my brief three days’ stay at Lima.</p><h2 id="Hospital-Nacional-Arzobispo-Loayza"><a href="#Hospital-Nacional-Arzobispo-Loayza" class="headerlink" title="Hospital Nacional Arzobispo Loayza"></a>Hospital Nacional Arzobispo Loayza</h2><p>This hospital was the first option recommended by my hostel reception for yellow fever vaccinate. So I bravely stepped out the hostel into the busy Lima downtown area with a printed map from the hostel (the hospital was not even ON the map!!!) the very next morning upon my arrival. </p><p>I was very excited, the first outing to South America! And after about an hour, I arrived my destination. Again, thank you Here App!</p><p><strong>Google Keyword: Hospital Nacional Arzobispo Loayza</strong> (it was founded in 1549!!!!)</p><p>Below is the how it looked from the outside. You can google for better photos. It really look very beautiful.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1mpS7UBDJbpcaVgUBHrH92yNRdFsUnuy7"><p>Then once enter the main entrance, there was the information center. I wrote down the yellow fever vaccinate in Spanish on paper. The reception wrote me back 2 sentences, of course in Spanish. Then I started my journey in the maze. Here is what you would once you step out the main building…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=14bOb18J6asuNYd2VT6_ID0tZt7Jl-ebD"><p>So I returned back to the main building. Look at this, it’s impossible to me to figure where I should go. And even worse, I didn’t know where to go with 2 sentences in Spanish!!! </p><p>I was luckily found several medical students. We communicated with incomplete sentences mixed with English, Spanish and sometimes Mandarin words…With their lead, we passed one historical building, followed by a palm tree lined alley (the cafeteria were on one side of this alley, oh my god, it smelled soooo GOOD!) then there appeared building 7. The only word I knew from the two sentences were 7. The medical students kindly left me in front of the building and told me to go to the 2nd floor. Once I entered the room, I figured out that I have arrived maternal and child health department…</p><p>The nurse greeted me with a smile! I showed her my piece of paper then we started our conversion via Google Translate! She told me the hospital name to go for internal certificate. All in all, it’s a wonderful experience! Hopefully, you can tell how beautiful the hospital is from my photos or just Google it!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1GuCodujnIc5a5JfwHari0KSyaAt4xMLZ"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=13DkLGbxnQHgPFxATe6RIhVszCTH7Yebk"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1xlBwScVrbr0jy5qBYST3mZBCJp3ERWeO"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1BKf5YdXdQh-1NZQn24uxbHUjBQMTLQsM"><h2 id="The-Street-Food-and-The-Street-Market-in-Lima"><a href="#The-Street-Food-and-The-Street-Market-in-Lima" class="headerlink" title="The Street Food and The Street Market in Lima"></a>The Street Food and The Street Market in Lima</h2><p>I believe these are where locals hit, with very lively surroundings. That’s really life in Lima! Thanks to Here WeGo app for the n-th times in this post, you navigated me through non-tourist alleys (some people may think it’s dangers and it did looked scary but nothing bad happened at least in the day time)…</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1LkS75LJalSuGvBaWqIs4_ET70Gshw8jD"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1eVy1w7G0VdNNQmarWBxN--Xkb1e5RmLE"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1-3KrEzlaHLppf40v7VKSrbaNW7LOdJLT"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DHmDkxKqOfnnhhxWdYl45yYcppDykhR5"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1dJdoUH6DoXDoQ7q5TBAkm6EOVpCzm22H"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DaP26ECu9YWe8RZqSv_hsYy3bx_jKHI5"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=13jZI9d6akZ6J_BK4BEaOeqNyJbwYiRGT"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1kCpewiXa0qznpHJZD5OOCvWPwyXsxbTS"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1nxVS3SAxmy_hy8Hfgh3HYhweJEAdMD2K"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1YbS96gvE7rv9ZvN_tN26EcLb1JI10zZz"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1rTBb7i4mWHKMWXoAwlXYyeGT5DRa3u1d"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1xmkMEXvZmkENTK54-DiOtdulUY2kSWKh"><p>Now the scary streets lead to the amazing food stands and markets. It’s within 1-2miles around central lima district (Plaza de Armas). I just took the non-tourist streets really there was only me as the foreigner! I didn’t see any other compared the a street full of tourists around the Plaza de Armas.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1BqsuhrsSvLa2UpciSJ-D3CdoFjZIs6HA"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1_i3hk1h1dRzh8ejXV0t-nBFOtPlh4wgn"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=18r29o7ykeQtQtxGHQ2EgeFLF4pOV-x4W"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1DOur48_kAPjb7ebanmk6NeD_qGEBd1zy"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1i2Xk2mvZEl8-IpxpuPxJ8r17zROlYrza"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1rHfldDP_HhINyrMfewr3CCjBqdbZiNJx"><p>Finally, I arrived China Town! The market is next to China Town.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1uzKndzK-nKz9SYedt_O-tHq4e0yhclWx"><font color="red"><p><strong>WARNING: Unpleasant photos were taken from the seafood market and meat market! You can close this post if you don’t want to see the dead animal bodies.</strong></p></font><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1P2QxB-DXbcfF1wTYFeHfMzMnqiOsSL6w"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=197AxAj5nsEitPtEvHKSoz6Jb4UinDWkE"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ObzvVlGmzsOv5lwvoOm4jWPbRPd53Epg"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1M4eEA50uNIzpQfxEbItLr_NqxN7y9oIF"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1yJvMz7LDZPpiCS2cAmh5ugpQhOoCIiT4"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=13VDO9IgumljLv4nRYcgXA3bA5_CtuCbh"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=10x-hqUeqCwzs9stvIJEX1bnUE4ypmqMM"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1cAvIYJ_1TNpl_2xfRgFJVnCzJ1j0U0sR"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1BfjOvPqQJ2ylO9tJ7Nzg6163NjWJssT3"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HOpfOVKBDDIDg5S2aH6qYX9HA5SV6Wsu"><h1 id="Log"><a href="#Log" class="headerlink" title="Log"></a>Log</h1><p>First Lima stay from August 20 to August 23, 2019 </p><p>Next stop: Cajamarca (bus leaving Lima at 6:00pm, August 23, 2019)</p><p><em>This post was published at La Granja Porcon on August 26, 2019.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=1XL4pjHCzua90eYxEIHw4JKeCAMOV0Yz3&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Peru" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Peru/"/>
    
      <category term="Lima" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Lima/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>packingList</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/8193c9a6/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/8193c9a6/</id>
    <published>2019-08-22T01:07:47.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.478Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The packing list for my South America voyager. The preparation and shopping started back in May 2019 and part of the gears were purchased from China. Although the backpacks seem to be small from the picutures, the total weight of the two backpacks are 25kg! I am packing way too much backup stuff, which I believe account for about 8kg waste or not so critical stuff. Anyway, reviews of the gears will be updated as the voyager continues.</p><a id="more"></a><div class="note info">            <p>Maiden Voyager Day 1 (08-20-2019) @Fort Lauderdale Airport.</p><p>My first flight route:</p><ul><li>Phoenix - Dallas: 1:47am - 6:01am</li><li>Dallas - Fort Lauderdale: 6:38am - 10:32am</li><li>Fort Lauderdale - Lima, Peru: 5:20pm - 10:03pm</li></ul><p>I spent 4+hrs writing 2.5 posts (this one with the Firestore post and the sections on asset links in HexoTips) at Fort Lauderdale airport. It’s really a good way to kill time and keep you awake! OK, by finishing this post, I have documented almost all key features for Hexo Development and the packing list for my trip. I completed everything in the U.S although with some delays as initially planned. But that’s it. This completes post completes all my preparation for lanVoyager in 2019!</p><p>Now, let’s start sailing…</p>          </div><span class="lanComment"><p>The post was completed on August 20 at Fort Lauderdale Airport. However, due to some technical issues, it was not successfully pushed onto github. </p><p>Publish Date: August 21, 2019</p><p>Publish Location: Lima, Peru</p></span><p>The final painful packing process took almost 6 hours on August 18, 2019. So the final two backpacks with a crossbody ‘invisible’ bag (I stuffed it so big now it is definetly visible). Total weight is about 25kg for all three bags.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HdekyANaIr56EpraeNX6wbzEBXEVySBe" class="gallery"><p> The crossbody bag:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1HRdFf_bR-r4M9RVU0ZP2lFO7bdSePdaO" class="full-image"><h1 id="The-Osprey-Fairpoint-70L"><a href="#The-Osprey-Fairpoint-70L" class="headerlink" title="The Osprey Fairpoint 70L"></a>The Osprey Fairpoint 70L</h1><p>This checked bag weights about 15kg including the bag itself.</p><p>Major Stuff:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1lDAR0gfhpXWuGqJew-bBQcN2swnLxyDx"><p><strong>Clothing</strong> </p><p>(I know it’s not lightweight packing, but really all these only account for 3 packing tubes in the picutre above):</p><ul><li>6 cotton T-shirt</li><li>2 hiking pants</li><li>1 convertable hiking pants</li><li>2 shorts</li><li>2 sweater</li><li>1 sweater pant (long)</li><li>1 legging (long)</li><li>1 light-weight sun protective jacket</li><li>2 quick-dry long sleeve shirts</li><li>7 underwears</li><li>7 socks</li><li>2 sport bras</li><li>1 swimming suit</li><li>1 thermal pant</li></ul><p>Plus, I wore winter ski jacket (can’t fit in the pack!), and Northface hiking shoe.</p><p><strong>Misc</strong></p><ul><li>1 pair of Keen sandals</li><li>1 pair of slippers</li><li>cable and charger bag (including a adapter plug for over 120+ contries, small tools like nail clippers, etc.)</li><li>10L waterproof bag</li><li>waterproof bag for camera</li><li>a hat</li><li>the extra bag of <a href="https://www.rei.com/product/867754/boreas-bootlegger-modular-pack-system" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Boreas Bootlegger Modular Pack System</a></li></ul><p><strong>Toiletry</strong> (This category I can say I did pack light!)</p><ul><li>1 shower bar</li><li>1 toothbrush &amp; tooth paste</li><li>1 portable-size facial cleanser</li><li>1 moisture lotion</li></ul><p><strong>Extras</strong></p><p>Note: I do think that you may not need the following stuff</p><ul><li>sunscreen (maybe too much. One big bottle and one smaller tube with 3 scrub bars in each bag…)</li><li>bug repellent (same here maybe too much…)</li><li>medicine bag (again lots of different medicine. The essential ones are allegeric pills and VC. Family just feels insecure without me carrying various types medicine for all possible illness they can think of..)</li><li><a href="https://www.rei.com/product/850427/cocoon-silk-mummy-liner?sku=8504270002&store=56&cm_mmc=PLA_Google_LIA%7C404_195857%7C8504270002%7Cnone%7C0f807a18-8860-47f4-8069-3c139f0beb1b%7Cpla-347097913619&lsft=cm_mmc:PLA_Google_LIA%7C404_195857%7C8504270002%7Cnone%7C0f807a18-8860-47f4-8069-3c139f0beb1b&kclid=0f807a18-8860-47f4-8069-3c139f0beb1b&gclid=CjwKCAjwtO7qBRBQEiwAl5WC2z9g28naPryl8AxfChQNU-QCD_oNdeC9aIpdEzutfWtVsaHW9tSoeBoCZMEQAvD_BwE" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">silk liner</a> (I don’t think everybody needs this. Just for my peace of mind staying at Hostels but I may decide not to use them after exhausting days for the actual trip)</li><li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lixada-Repellent-Ultra-fine-Protective-Gardening/dp/B01I5AX9UO?source=ps-sl-shoppingads-lpcontext&psc=1" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">mosquito suit</a> (I don’t know you guys but I am SUPER attractive to mosquito probably just because I am delicious to their taste…)</li><li>Wet wipes, tissues, and lipbalms (way too much but by bring 2~3 months’ supply I feel secured…)</li></ul><h1 id="Boreas-Bootlegger-The-Carry-On"><a href="#Boreas-Bootlegger-The-Carry-On" class="headerlink" title="Boreas Bootlegger - The Carry-On"></a>Boreas Bootlegger - The Carry-On</h1><p>This carry-on weights about 9kg including the bag itself…</p><p><strong>Essentials:</strong></p><ul><li>An inflatable H-shape neck pillow (really good)</li><li>charges and cables for the airport</li><li>sunglasses</li></ul><p><strong>Electronics</strong></p><ul><li><p>camera</p></li><li><p>laptop</p></li><li><p>mouse</p></li><li><p>watch</p></li><li><p>powerbank (20000mAh)</p></li><li><p>head lamp</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1YwMiJMGoj4V9N7VPIm2tFWeo51Y5qkN0"></li></ul><p><strong>Extras:</strong></p><ul><li>Lonely Planet- South America on A Shoestring over 800 pages book! I think it weights about 1lb.</li><li>A thermal 40fl water bottle another 1lb</li><li>The protection carrying box for the valuables. This box weights at 1.5kg…</li></ul><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1QzUXkddDxbtgvKE8Kkmcq6Oon22feekX"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1x-XUeeoH6A28Uy9k8V_jVLORgpKAS812"><p><strong>Miscs:</strong></p><ul><li>backup everything I said that I over packed (medicine, sunscreen, wet wipes, tissues etc…)</li></ul><h1 id="The-Crossbody-Bag"><a href="#The-Crossbody-Bag" class="headerlink" title="The Crossbody Bag"></a>The Crossbody Bag</h1><p><strong>Essentials:</strong></p><ul><li>eye mask</li><li>travel earplugs</li><li>cell phone</li><li>a pen</li><li>a small note book</li><li>a pair of earbug for music &amp; phone calls</li></ul><p><strong>Miscs:</strong></p><ul><li>backup everything I said that I over packed (medicine, sunscreen, wet wipes, tissues etc…)</li></ul><h1 id="An-Idea-of-How-Many-Cables-amp-Chargers-Are-Needed"><a href="#An-Idea-of-How-Many-Cables-amp-Chargers-Are-Needed" class="headerlink" title="An Idea of How Many Cables &amp; Chargers Are Needed"></a>An Idea of How Many Cables &amp; Chargers Are Needed</h1><p>This is everything at charging station. Note the outlet extention plug is not packed. Everthing else are packed!!!</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1t4G77sgGatEVDij8kjYdfkrc-4dmlA91">]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The packing list for my South America voyager. The preparation and shopping started back in May 2019 and part of the gears were purchased from China. Although the backpacks seem to be small from the picutures, the total weight of the two backpacks are 25kg! I am packing way too much backup stuff, which I believe account for about 8kg waste or not so critical stuff. Anyway, reviews of the gears will be updated as the voyager continues.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Logbook</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/9602864c/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/9602864c/</id>
    <published>2019-08-16T09:01:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-31T20:08:34.136Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><audio src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/5sn1l3afpltsxgw/Dreams%20-%20Cranberries.mp3?raw=1"></audio></p><div class="player">  <img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/cjd0kmrdn3o8noz/cranberriesPic.jpg?raw=1">  <div class="info">    <div class="name">Dreams</div>    <div class="singer">The Cranberries</div>  </div>  <div class="btns">    <div class="iconfont play-pause icon-play"></div>    <div class="iconfont next icon-next"></div>  </div>  <div class="progress">  </div></div><br><br><div class="note info">            <p>Name of Ship: Lan30s</p><p>Call Sign: lanVoyager.github.io</p><p>Home Port: Phoenix, AZ</p><p>Hull Identification Number (HIN): CN-SHx-99999-Ix-8x</p><p>Date of First Entry: 08-16-2019</p><p>Date of Maiden Voyage: 0:50AM, 08-20-2019</p>          </div><p><em>Date of Publish: 08-16-2019</em></p><p>Captain has no clear direction of the voyager. The objective function here is to maximize personal utility function (yet to be defined if it’s ever possible) subject to allocated budget, time and captain’s physical conditions. Or maybe it’s a feasibility problem without a clearly defined objective function? OK, let’s stop here. I have already received enough complaints about the boring contents of this blog from ALL of my test readers…</p><p><strong>After northern Peru (the dense marks), location marks only indicate possible major stops along the route.</strong> At the date of publish, captain has a one-way flight ticket and 3 nights hostel reservation in Lima, Peru.</p><div class="iframe-container">  <iframe src="https://lanVoyager.github.io/myLeafMap/index.html" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><h1 id="The-Voyager-Map"><a href="#The-Voyager-Map" class="headerlink" title="The Voyager Map"></a>The Voyager Map</h1><p>The actual route will be updated in real-time with some delays…</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;audio src=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/5sn1l3afpltsxgw/Dreams%20-%20Cranberries.mp3?raw=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;player&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;h
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="logbook" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/logbook/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo - Add View Count based on FireBase</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/2ef3ae62/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/2ef3ae62/</id>
    <published>2019-08-15T04:24:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.475Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To be dynamic, or not to be dynamic? That is the question. As a novice in this web/blog field, I even did NOT know the question exists. Static site was just chosen based on the GOOGLE search keyword ‘How to create a personal blog’ when I started this blog. As a person knows some DTA stuff, let’s add some dynamic favor to this static site using Firestore by Google Cloud!</p><a id="more"></a><p><del>Day 35 with Hexo…</del></p><p>Maiden Voyager Day 1 (08-20-2019) @Fort Lauderdale Airport. See how I like this dynamic feature! I am writing this after 8 hours air-transportation since 0:50AM today! </p><p>The goal here is to display view counts (clicks on each of the post) in real time. How fancy, now it looks like some keywords in my dissertation. This requires dynamic, user interactive and probably a database to store the counts which are not built to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Static_web_page" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">static site</a>. To add this feature, we will deploy Firestore by Goolge Cloud service. Of course, there are many other similar services. For Chinese readers, there are lots of available resources online. Just Baidu it. After so many failures and denials by Chinese websites/services, I didn’t even bother to try those.</p><h1 id="The-Approach"><a href="#The-Approach" class="headerlink" title="The Approach"></a>The Approach</h1><p>Step 1: On <a href="https://firebase.google.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Firebase</a>, create an account and a new project.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Xta3itrjiiTeeono-WJz6k7u28lLUCnA"><p>Step 2: Create a database</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1Y7JaKSfcDuS3HyZNC-ALUUCEjqXV4Z8r"><p>Step 3: modify <code>.\themes\next\\_config.yml</code></p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="attr">firestore:</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  enable:</span> <span class="literal">true</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  collection:</span> <span class="string">yourDatabaseName</span> <span class="comment"># Required, a string collection name to access firestore database</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  apiKey:</span> <span class="string">seePic</span> <span class="comment"># Required</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  projectId:</span> <span class="string">seePic</span> <span class="comment"># Required</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  bluebird:</span> <span class="literal">false</span> <span class="comment"># Enable this if you want to include bluebird 3.5.1 (core version) Promise polyfill</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1ugehD7bSPqvJCfSrm2eF5_KJHRkP4RKd"><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1LvyDVOUBD6IzNCo7oCugmvA38qW036Wp"><p>Step 4: Go back to Firebase console, enter <strong>Rules</strong> in <strong>Database</strong> section and slightly modify the code, and then <strong>Publish</strong> it.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1kg2YYcmpopzNeXlmqj4EZdH1h1o3rGqU"><p>Note: <a href="https://github.com/theme-next" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Hexo NexT</a> theme version should be above <code>v5.1.3</code>, otherwise you may encounter the issue that count numbers appear on index page. <a href="https://github.com/iissnan/hexo-theme-next/pull/1984" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Bug#1984</a> is fixed <a href="https://github.com/iissnan/hexo-theme-next/commit/3d4cccd048fd95bd7b5b10ac51c9180ea5341721" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><p>Step 5: Deploy and you will find view icon with ‘view count’ in real time on your blog. Also, you can check the database in Firebase to for the real-time count data. As Lan being in the ‘static world’, this feature is REALLY COOL for the first time I implemented probably a week ago. I was very proud of myself. It was not a trivial task and I spent sometime Goolging for the solution to add view count and finally reside on Fi. The n-th time complaint, still a lot easier than the trial to connect mainland China which is still a failure as of today!<img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1NQYX3wa-OLWGs04ql1npEnJj6yEhlrqS"> </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1b66I5KFpDIzG7v5JJw2P4-QbkHJLRip0"><h1 id="Cosmetic-Issue"><a href="#Cosmetic-Issue" class="headerlink" title="Cosmetic Issue"></a>Cosmetic Issue</h1><p>There is a minor issue with ‘Abstract’ and ‘View Icon’.</p><p>If the <a href="https://lanvoyager.github.io/posts/a6eb593f">abstract</a> was added by adding ‘description’ in the front-matter. The location of view icon in the post page (if you click ‘MORE’) will be placed after the abstract. </p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1fV4B8Lo-gb_YD7B9mpfEsW2f2JQWTq4x"><p>To avoid this, use <code>&lt;!-- more --&gt;</code>  to add your abstract!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;To be dynamic, or not to be dynamic? That is the question. As a novice in this web/blog field, I even did NOT know the question exists. Static site was just chosen based on the GOOGLE search keyword ‘How to create a personal blog’ when I started this blog. As a person knows some DTA stuff, let’s add some dynamic favor to this static site using Firestore by Google Cloud!&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="nerdyNotes" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/nerdyNotes/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo - Add Word Count</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/3f6d8e38/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/3f6d8e38/</id>
    <published>2019-08-14T05:43:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.475Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Showing word counts and reading time initially seemed to be a fancy feature.  Easy to implement but may cause the title block a little bit too congested. Actually, tonight I also added view count via Google Firebase, which is pretty cool feature! This will be documented tomorrow night…it’s getting really late or you can say early at the moment.</p><a id="more"></a><p>Day 34 with Hexo.</p><p>Goal: Add word count &amp; reading time. <strong>Please note, the stats displayed by the plugin is only ESTIMATES, not actual data…</strong></p><h1 id="Google-Review"><a href="#Google-Review" class="headerlink" title="Google Review"></a>Google Review</h1><p>My current theme <code>nexT</code> version is v7.2.0 and it supports <code>hexo-symbols-count-time</code> plugin. Previously, <code>hexo-wordcount</code> was a very popular plugin for this feature. Since the theme _config.yml and post.swig have embedded hexo-symbols-count-time. This post will describe how to enable this plugin.</p><h1 id="Implementation"><a href="#Implementation" class="headerlink" title="Implementation"></a>Implementation</h1><p>Step 1: Install plugin</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">npm install hexo-symbols-count-time --save</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 2: check the theme <code>_config.yml</code> in yourBlog\themes\next\ folder</p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="attr">symbols_count_time:</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  separated_meta:</span> <span class="literal">true</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  item_text_post:</span> <span class="literal">true</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  item_text_total:</span> <span class="literal">true</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  awl:</span> <span class="number">4</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  wpm:</span> <span class="number">275</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 3: if you want you can edit the <code>post.swig</code> in yourBlog\themes\next\layout\ folder. (I changed the labelForWordCountEst &amp; labelForTimeEst)</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br><span class="line">16</span><br><span class="line">17</span><br><span class="line">18</span><br><span class="line">19</span><br><span class="line">20</span><br><span class="line">21</span><br><span class="line">22</span><br><span class="line">23</span><br><span class="line">24</span><br><span class="line">25</span><br><span class="line">26</span><br><span class="line">27</span><br><span class="line">28</span><br><span class="line">29</span><br><span class="line">30</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">&#123;% raw %&#125;</span><br><span class="line">          &#123;% if theme.symbols_count_time.separated_meta %&#125;&lt;br/&gt;&#123;% endif %&#125;</span><br><span class="line">          &#123;% if config.symbols_count_time.symbols %&#125;</span><br><span class="line">            &lt;span class=&quot;post-meta-item&quot;&gt;</span><br><span class="line">              &lt;span class=&quot;post-meta-item-icon&quot;&gt;</span><br><span class="line">                &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-file-word-o&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</span><br><span class="line">              &lt;/span&gt;</span><br><span class="line">              &#123;% if theme.symbols_count_time.item_text_post %&#125;</span><br><span class="line">               &lt;span class=&quot;post-meta-item-text&quot;&gt;labelForWordCountEst:&lt;/span&gt;</span><br><span class="line">              &#123;% endif %&#125;</span><br><span class="line">              &lt;span title=&quot;&#123;&#123; __(&apos;symbols_count_time.count&apos;) &#125;&#125;&quot;&gt;&#123;#</span><br><span class="line">              #&#125;&#123;&#123; symbolsCount(post) &#125;&#125;&#123;#</span><br><span class="line">            #&#125;&lt;/span&gt;</span><br><span class="line">            &lt;/span&gt;</span><br><span class="line">          &#123;% endif %&#125;</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">          &#123;% if config.symbols_count_time.time %&#125;</span><br><span class="line">            &lt;span class=&quot;post-meta-item&quot;&gt;</span><br><span class="line">              &lt;span class=&quot;post-meta-item-icon&quot;&gt;</span><br><span class="line">                &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-clock-o&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</span><br><span class="line">              &lt;/span&gt;</span><br><span class="line">              &#123;% if theme.symbols_count_time.item_text_post %&#125;</span><br><span class="line">                 &lt;span class=&quot;post-meta-item-text&quot;&gt;labelForTimeEst &amp;asymp;&lt;/span&gt;</span><br><span class="line">              &#123;% endif %&#125;</span><br><span class="line">              &lt;span title=&quot;&#123;&#123; __(&apos;symbols_count_time.time&apos;) &#125;&#125;&quot;&gt;&#123;#</span><br><span class="line">              #&#125;&#123;&#123; symbolsTime(post, theme.symbols_count_time.awl, theme.symbols_count_time.wpm, __(&apos;symbols_count_time.time_minutes&apos;)) &#125;&#125;&#123;#</span><br><span class="line">            #&#125;&lt;/span&gt;</span><br><span class="line">            &lt;/span&gt;</span><br><span class="line">          &#123;% endif %&#125;</span><br><span class="line">&#123;% endraw %&#125;`</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 4: Deploy. You will find the word count &amp; time estimate.</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1b62Us98lrOQQbGX61DpThmiLidaJFG7i"><h1 id="Some-Nerdy-Complaints"><a href="#Some-Nerdy-Complaints" class="headerlink" title="Some Nerdy Complaints"></a>Some Nerdy Complaints</h1><p>According to hexo-symbols-count-time’s document on github (<a href="https://github.com/theme-next/hexo-symbols-count-time" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">here</a>). The word count is an estimated number.</p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="attr">symbols_count_time:</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  separated_meta:</span> <span class="literal">true</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  item_text_post:</span> <span class="literal">true</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  item_text_total:</span> <span class="literal">false</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  awl:</span> <span class="number">4</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  wpm:</span> <span class="number">275</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  suffix:</span> <span class="string">mins.</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>where,</p><p>awl: Average Word Length (chars count in word). Default: <code>4</code>. You can check this <a href="https://charactercounttool.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><ul><li>CN ≈ <code>2</code></li><li>EN ≈ <code>5</code></li><li>RU ≈ <code>6</code></li></ul><p>wpm: Words Per Minute. Default: <code>275</code>. You can check this <a href="https://wordcounter.net/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">here</a>.</p><ul><li>Slow ≈ <code>200</code></li><li>Normal ≈ <code>275</code></li><li>Fast ≈ <code>350</code></li></ul><p><strong>Note for Chinese users:</strong> because in Chinese language average word length about <code>~1.5</code> and if you at most cases write posts in Chinese (without mixed English), recommended to set <code>awl</code> to <code>2</code> and <code>wpm</code> to <code>300</code>.<br>But if you usualy mix your posts with English, <code>awl</code> to <code>4</code> and <code>wpm</code> to <code>275</code> will be nice.</p><span class="lanComment"><p>Lan: I actually compared its word count with counts from WORD. The estimate on the lower side is much far off (~5 times higher than actual for words under 10). But as the actual number of words increases, the estimation error tends to decrease to an acceptable range. Or maybe my default awl=4 is not a good choice. OK, no rigorous numerical tests on this yet. If I getting too bored, I will do some tests on it. Later in another country and hopefully during the day…For the moment, we just need to know it’s estimated. BTW, why counting word is difficult? I thought it’s an easy task from an NON-EXPERT view. On the other hand, reading time is a tough number to get. </p></span><p>OK, again I ended this post with the celebration of Day 35…I did much more than adding one plugin LAST night. Nerdy posts will be continued…</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Showing word counts and reading time initially seemed to be a fancy feature.  Easy to implement but may cause the title block a little bit too congested. Actually, tonight I also added view count via Google Firebase, which is pretty cool feature! This will be documented tomorrow night…it’s getting really late or you can say early at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="nerdyNotes" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/nerdyNotes/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo - Add Audio Player</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/cc037a0/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/cc037a0/</id>
    <published>2019-08-01T09:45:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.473Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A MUST READ ARTICLE. It discusses adding js files as audio player with customerized CSS. I think with these two skills, you can implement anything on Hexo blog. With an exception to reaching users from mainland China, though it’s not a technical issue…</p><a id="more"></a><p>Day 22 with Hexo: In the past 7 days, I have been struggling with non-technical issues with my blog. Trying to make this blog accessible to mainland China and of course the rest of the world seems to be <strong>MISSION IMPOSSIBLE</strong>. NO politics here, but it is really hard and time consuming meaninglessly!!! The popular cloud services like GoogleDrive, OneDrive, Dropbox etc. are blocked in China. Fine, I can use Chinese cloud service. I found a Chinese cloud service based in Shanghai China with good online reviews. To my surprise, in order to register an account, you need a Chinese mobile phone number which is now commonly required for most of Chinese websites. I can still find a way around it through my freinds in China, right? Then the second step is asking you to upload front and back pictures of your CHINESE NATIONAL ID?!?! I had to say <strong>I SURRENDER</strong> at this step. </p><p>To my friends and family in China,</p><blockquote><p>I reach to you<br>I know you can feel it too<br>We’d make it through</p><p>I SURRENDER by Celine Dion</p></blockquote><p>No pictures and songs for you.</p><p>At the moment of writing this post, the following are tried and failed:</p><ul><li>Google Drive, OneDrive and Dropbox are all blocked in China. </li><li>Baidu pan stopped providing the public share external link. </li><li>Weibo by Sina was used by many Chinese bloggers as their image hosting site. After 7 years, it stopped this service in late April, 2019. Thank you, I don’t even need to try the painful registration process.</li><li>Qiniu, hey, I was rejected as its customer. No comments here…</li></ul><p>I may find a way later. But let’s move on!</p><h1 id="Theme-Song-of-Today"><a href="#Theme-Song-of-Today" class="headerlink" title="Theme Song of Today"></a>Theme Song of Today</h1><p>It’s another sad failure of my Hexo journey. Maybe it’s my problem but I can’t make the popular Hexo audio plugin (<a href="https://github.com/MoePlayer/hexo-tag-aplayer" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">hexo-tag-aplayer</a>) working on my blog. No wonder of course, it does not support my Dropbox link for songs and most of popular Chinese music websites do NOT work overseas. And I don’t want use local assests since Github has limited page limits. OK, yes, you can also blame that I am using FREE services now. I guess MONEY can solve most of my problems.</p><p>So my audio player looks something below:</p><p><audio src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/r1w1kp6gex00xfa/Celine%20Dion%20-%20I%20SURRENDER.mp3?raw=1"></audio></p><div class="player">  <img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/eti5rkje5bh33s5/2019-08-01_0545.png?raw=1">  <div class="info">    <div class="name">I Surrender</div>    <div class="singer">Celine Dion</div>  </div>  <div class="btns">    <div class="iconfont play-pause icon-play"></div>    <div class="iconfont next icon-next"></div>  </div>  <div class="progress">  </div></div>  <div class="progress">  </div><h1 id="Another-Uncommon-Hexo-Approach"><a href="#Another-Uncommon-Hexo-Approach" class="headerlink" title="Another Uncommon Hexo Approach"></a>Another Uncommon Hexo Approach</h1><p>Simpliest appraoch for audio player is just use the HTML <audio> to directly ebmed your mp3 on the webpage. Below is the basic audio player generated by one line of <a href="https://www.w3schools.com/html/html5_audio.asp" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">script</a>.</audio></p><p><audio controls>   <source src="yourMP3 URL" type="audio/mpeg">Your browser does not support the audio element.</audio><br> <code>iframe</code> can be another option as well.</p><p>With some googling, the one adpoted here is a customerized audio player I found online with very little changes of the CSS. So it will envolve adding customerized CSS &amp; JavaScript under HEXO. The scripts can be found <a href="https://codepen.io/anon/pen/MNevgq" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">here</a>. </p><p>Step 1: Prepare the CSS in Hexo. For the content, copy and paste from the above script link into your new CSS file to be used. In terms of adding CSS under Hexo, please refer to the process described in my previous post on <a href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/ddb3530">LeafLet Map</a>.</p><p>Step 2: Add JavaScript to Hexo</p><p>2.1 copy paste the content of the source script and save it as yourAudioPlayer.js under <code>yourBlog\themes\next\source\js</code></p><figure class="highlight javascript"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br><span class="line">16</span><br><span class="line">17</span><br><span class="line">18</span><br><span class="line">19</span><br><span class="line">20</span><br><span class="line">21</span><br><span class="line">22</span><br><span class="line">23</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$(</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span>(<span class="params"></span>)</span>&#123;</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="keyword">var</span> aud = $(<span class="string">'audio'</span>)[<span class="number">0</span>];</span><br><span class="line">  $(<span class="string">'.play-pause'</span>).on(<span class="string">'click'</span>, <span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span>(<span class="params"></span>)</span>&#123;</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="keyword">if</span> (aud.paused) &#123;</span><br><span class="line">    aud.play();</span><br><span class="line">    $(<span class="string">'.play-pause'</span>).removeClass(<span class="string">'icon-play'</span>);</span><br><span class="line">    $(<span class="string">'.play-pause'</span>).addClass(<span class="string">'icon-stop'</span>);</span><br><span class="line">  &#125;</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="keyword">else</span> &#123;</span><br><span class="line">    aud.pause();</span><br><span class="line">    $(<span class="string">'.play-pause'</span>).removeClass(<span class="string">'icon-stop'</span>);</span><br><span class="line">    $(<span class="string">'.play-pause'</span>).addClass(<span class="string">'icon-play'</span>);</span><br><span class="line">  &#125;</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">&#125;)</span><br><span class="line">  $(<span class="string">'.next'</span>).on(<span class="string">'click'</span>, <span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span>(<span class="params"></span>)</span>&#123;</span><br><span class="line">  aud.src = <span class="string">'another audio source'</span>;</span><br><span class="line">&#125;)</span><br><span class="line">  aud.ontimeupdate = <span class="function"><span class="keyword">function</span>(<span class="params"></span>)</span>&#123;</span><br><span class="line">    $(<span class="string">'.progress'</span>).css(<span class="string">'width'</span>, aud.currentTime / aud.duration * <span class="number">100</span> + <span class="string">'%'</span>)</span><br><span class="line">  &#125;</span><br><span class="line">&#125;)</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>2.2 Open <code>_layout.swig</code> from the <code>yourBlog\themes\next\layout</code></p><figure class="highlight html"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">script</span> <span class="attr">type</span>=<span class="string">"text/javascript"</span> <span class="attr">src</span>=<span class="string">"/js/lanAudioPlayer.js"</span>&gt;</span><span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">script</span>&gt;</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>2.3 Add the song &amp; player in the post (markdown)</p><figure class="highlight html"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">audio</span> <span class="attr">src</span>= <span class="string">'yourMP3 URL'</span>&gt;</span><span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">audio</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">div</span> <span class="attr">class</span>=<span class="string">'player'</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">img</span> <span class="attr">src</span>=<span class="string">'the ablum pic --&gt; Optional'</span>/&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">div</span> <span class="attr">class</span>=<span class="string">'info'</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">div</span> <span class="attr">class</span>=<span class="string">'name'</span>&gt;</span>Name of the Song<span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">div</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">div</span> <span class="attr">class</span>=<span class="string">'singer'</span>&gt;</span>Singer<span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">div</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">div</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">div</span> <span class="attr">class</span>=<span class="string">'btns'</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">div</span> <span class="attr">class</span>=<span class="string">"iconfont play-pause icon-play"</span>&gt;</span><span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">div</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">    <span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">div</span> <span class="attr">class</span>=<span class="string">"iconfont next icon-next"</span>&gt;</span><span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">div</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">div</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">div</span> <span class="attr">class</span>=<span class="string">'progress'</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">div</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">div</span>&gt;</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>2.4 Deploy and Enjoy the music</p><h1 id="Summary"><a href="#Summary" class="headerlink" title="Summary"></a>Summary</h1><p>Looking back at how I implemented the audio player, it is actually fairly simple. However, I felt it really took a long time for me to add this feature. What I can say is that probably 5% of the time was spent on learning and try-N-Error scripting and the rest of the time were mostly wasted on meaningless issues of connecting China and the world based on FREE services.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;A MUST READ ARTICLE. It discusses adding js files as audio player with customerized CSS. I think with these two skills, you can implement anything on Hexo blog. With an exception to reaching users from mainland China, though it’s not a technical issue…&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="nerdyNotes" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/nerdyNotes/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo - Add Customized Leaflet Map</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/ddb3530/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/ddb3530/</id>
    <published>2019-07-25T05:51:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.474Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tips &amp; steps to add Leaflet map to Hexo. This also discusses how to add html file &amp; javascript to Hexo Blog!</p><a id="more"></a><p>Day 15 with Hexo…</p><p>Lots of things have happened over the past 6 days. On July 20, 2019, I went to my first US Major League Baseball game (Diamondbacks vs Brewers). We lost the game but it was very dramatic which deserves a standalone post on it (probably, I will not write a post on it). Also, July 22, 2019, first monsoon followed by dust storm hit Phoenix. We lost the power in my neighborhood that night. NO AC and temperature was about 33C (95F).  And of course, gym, endless house cleaning &amp; errands etc. kept me busy.</p><h1 id="My-Initial-Travel-Plan-to-South-America"><a href="#My-Initial-Travel-Plan-to-South-America" class="headerlink" title="My Initial Travel Plan to South America"></a>My Initial Travel Plan to South America</h1><p>I have added several places I would like to visit for my South America trip. This is just for demonstration purpose. Actually I don’t have any fixed itineraries yet. Also, it only has very basic features. Hopefully, I will continue working on the javascript to add more interactive features &amp; information on my trip.</p><div class="iframe-container">  <iframe src="https://lanVoyager.github.io/myLeafMap/index.html" allowfullscreen></iframe></div><h1 id="An-Uncommon-Hexo-Approach"><a href="#An-Uncommon-Hexo-Approach" class="headerlink" title="An Uncommon Hexo Approach"></a>An Uncommon Hexo Approach</h1><p>Ok, yes, Hexo has a plugin (<a href="https://github.com/ender74/hexo-tag-leaflet" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">hexo-tag-leaflet</a>). I have to admit probably I am not smart enough to use it plus many other plugins (like the audio player which I will discuss it in another post). Fast forward to the conclusion, after hours of trail-and-error, to be accurate, mostly errors, I gave up on the plugin and decided to just use HTML &amp; JAVASCRIPT for this map. Assume you know how that is done. This section, we will only focus on how to add the HTML &amp; JAVASCRIPT of the map to HEXO.</p><p>Short answer is to use <code>iframe</code> to embed your HTML. Sounds simple, right? NO!!! At least, I was not the lucky person. So the long answer is the following:</p><p>Step 1: Have your leaflet map ready in HTML &amp; Javascript. My structure for the demo map is the following:</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">|-----myLeafMap</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">   |----index.html</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">   |----main.js </span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">   |----geoData (where the geoJson data is stored)</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 2: Put the above folder (myLeafMap) under {yourBlog}\source</p><p>Step 3: Add the iframe in the MarkDown (the post where you want to display the map)</p><figure class="highlight html"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">iframe</span> <span class="attr">src</span>=<span class="string">"https://yourGithubID.github.io/myLeafMap/index.html"</span> <span class="attr">width</span>=<span class="string">"700"</span> <span class="attr">height</span>=<span class="string">"800"</span>&gt;</span><span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">iframe</span>&gt;</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p><strong>Important:</strong> include <code>https://</code> when you provide the URL for the HTML. I was lazy and omitted that since I was manually typing them. This is a bloody error which I spent hours to figure out why it was not working. </p><p><em>The issue:</em> </p><p>The map will display on the landing page but if you click the post, you will encounter 404 page (resource not found).</p><p><em>The reason:</em></p><p><del>It’s due to HEXO’s dir structure. If you don’t provide complete URL, it looks for the files in relative path which is  yourPost/yourGithubID.github.io/myLeafMap/index.html. However, if you follow Step 3, when you deploy, everything is under public folder. Many users reported difficulties to upload local imgages. That is mainly due to Hexo’s understanding of dir structures. A common solution is to use <code>asset</code> folder (<a href="https://hexo.io/docs/asset-folders.html" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://hexo.io/docs/asset-folders.html</a>).</del></p><span class="lanComment"><p>Correction on August 1, 2019: I should not blame HEXO structure. The issue is more related to absolute path vs. relative path in HTML. If the complete URL is not provided, HTML thinks it’s relative path and that’s the reason why it would try to find the embedded leaflet scripts under the post folder when the post page is opened. </p></span><p><em>The solution:</em></p><p>Tried several things and decided the best is just use your URL hosted in github as in Step 3. Just remember to include <code>https://</code></p><p>Step 4: Deploy and Wish You Success!!!</p><h1 id="Further-Advanced-Improvements"><a href="#Further-Advanced-Improvements" class="headerlink" title="Further Advanced Improvements"></a>Further Advanced Improvements</h1><p>Yes, the map is up &amp; working. But not perfectly. We want to make the map (iframe) to be automatically re-size depends on the device your reader is using. Otherwise, it just looks ugly.</p><p>OK to do it, we will move on to a new era of HEXO. Once I succeeded this task, I believed that I have the freedom of customizing most of the items I want on this blog. Also, please check out my post on audio player there I plan to add customized JS file. With these two, we can do anything in the way we want! I believe I can say goodbye to most of the HEXO plugins very soon.</p><p>So how? The trick is to add customized CSS file for iframe, actually the iframe container. Don’t challenge my knowledge in HTML. I believe we can’t change iframe.</p><p>The example is based on <code>next</code> theme.</p><p>Step 1: Create a new folder say <code>_myCSS</code>under <code>{yourBlog}\themes\next\source\css</code></p><p>Step 2: Create a new file say <code>newCSS.styl</code> and use the following code. (Refer: <a href="https://benmarshall.me/responsive-iframes/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://benmarshall.me/responsive-iframes/</a>)</p><figure class="highlight stylus"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br><span class="line">14</span><br><span class="line">15</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="selector-class">.iframe-container</span> &#123;</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="attribute">overflow</span>: hidden;</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="comment">// Calculated from the aspect ration of the content (in case of 16:9 it is 9/16= 0.5625)</span></span><br><span class="line">  <span class="attribute">padding-top</span>: <span class="number">56.25%</span>;</span><br><span class="line">  <span class="attribute">position</span>: relative;</span><br><span class="line">&#125;</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="selector-class">.iframe-container</span> <span class="selector-tag">iframe</span> &#123;</span><br><span class="line">   <span class="attribute">border</span>: <span class="number">0</span>;</span><br><span class="line">   <span class="attribute">height</span>: <span class="number">100%</span>;</span><br><span class="line">   <span class="attribute">left</span>: <span class="number">0</span>;</span><br><span class="line">   <span class="attribute">position</span>: absolute;</span><br><span class="line">   <span class="attribute">top</span>: <span class="number">0</span>;</span><br><span class="line">   <span class="attribute">width</span>: <span class="number">100%</span>;</span><br><span class="line">&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 3: Add the new CSS to the theme. Go to <code>{yourBlog}\themes\next\source\css</code>and open <code>main.styl</code>. Add the following:</p><figure class="highlight stylus"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment">// Newly Defined CSS</span></span><br><span class="line"> @import <span class="string">"_myCSS/newCSS"</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 4: Deploy &amp; test it out on your PC, iPAD and/or smart phone!</p><h1 id="Another-Step-Further"><a href="#Another-Step-Further" class="headerlink" title="Another Step Further"></a>Another Step Further</h1><p>Now, you understand why it took me so long to write this post…</p><p>Yes, the map (iframe) on your blog is responsive to the viewer (device). But the Leaflet map is NOT. Or at least, my initial leaflet map was not viewer responsive. I set it to fit my computer screen with fixed zoom level and center location. But your frame size changes. So you may see something like this:</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/j0zfcirr1me8dmo/wrongMapZoom.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333"><p>What we want is no matter where the blog is read, when the map is loaded it will display entire itineraries (show all geojson locations). To make this work, we will change the HTML.</p><p>Here is the official leaflet tutorial on this. It is pretty straightforward to follow. Yes, only the HEXO world is complex to me. </p><p><a href="https://leafletjs.com/examples/mobile/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://leafletjs.com/examples/mobile/</a></p><p>END of this post and let’s celebrate Day 16 with Hexo. Another long night of working…</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Tips &amp;amp; steps to add Leaflet map to Hexo. This also discusses how to add html file &amp;amp; javascript to Hexo Blog!&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="nerdyNotes" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/nerdyNotes/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo - Add RSS</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/252dd1fe/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/252dd1fe/</id>
    <published>2019-07-19T03:38:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.474Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another feature for my imaginary readers :)</p><a id="more"></a><p>Day 9 with Hexo. Yes, I took a night off yesterday.</p><h1 id="An-Intro-to-RSS"><a href="#An-Intro-to-RSS" class="headerlink" title="An Intro to RSS"></a>An Intro to RSS</h1><blockquote><p><strong>RSS</strong> (originally <strong>RDF Site Summary</strong>; later, two competing approaches emerged, which used the backronyms  <strong>Rich Site Summary</strong> and <strong>Really Simple Syndication</strong> respectively) is a type of web feed which allows users and applications to access updates to websites in a standardized, computer-readable format.</p></blockquote><p>Long story in short, it’s sort of a ‘subscription’ to a website. In our case, if you hit the ‘RSS’ button of this blog, whenever a new post is up, you will recieve the content in your RSS reader. So the information comes to you instead of you checking for it. Wait, we are in 2019, an era of <code>BIG DATA, AI, MACHINE LEARNING, DEEP LEARNING</code> with all these fancy names. The data and storage units now come with terabyte, petabyte, exabyte, zettabyte and yottabyte. We already have all the stories/ads ‘machine picked’ for us from our Facebook page, WeChat app, Google Story etc. And also, I don’t know you guys, I sometimes hit the ‘subscribe button’ &amp; provide my shopping email account for weekly ads, which I am very regret doing this. My email acount is full of promotion emails and it’s REALLY DIFICULT to unsubscribe them. First, the ‘unsubcribe’ link is so difficult to find in the email. Second, some websites say ‘It will take about 10 business days for us to remove you from our list.’ ╯﹏╰ And the worst thing is, I am still receiving them!!!</p><p>So why RSS?</p><ul><li>It’s active selection. You choose to what to follow.</li><li>You don’t provide your email account. No spam and you don’t even receive a notification email.</li><li>Unsubcription is just a click of button. </li><li>Honestly, it’s a new ‘old’ thing to me and after my quick research, it seems to be cool on my blog. I know my potential readers will be counted in bytes. It’s for your convenience. </li></ul><h1 id="Add-RSS-to-Hexo-Blog"><a href="#Add-RSS-to-Hexo-Blog" class="headerlink" title="Add RSS to Hexo Blog"></a>Add RSS to Hexo Blog</h1><p>Step 1: install the RSS plugin</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">npm install hexo-generator-feed --save</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 2: setup in blog _config.yml:</p><figure class="highlight yml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="attr">Plugins:</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="bullet">-</span> <span class="string">hexo-generator-feed</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">feed:</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  type:</span> <span class="string">atom</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  path:</span> <span class="string">atom.xml</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  limit:</span> <span class="number">20</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>For acceptable args, please refer to its github page:</p><p><a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo-generator-feed" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://github.com/hexojs/hexo-generator-feed</a></p><p>Step 3: setup in theme _config.yml:</p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="comment"># hexo-generator-feed required for rss support. Leave rss as blank to use site's feed link.</span></span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="comment"># Set rss to false to disable feed link. Set rss to specific value if you have burned your feed already.</span></span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">rss:</span> <span class="string">/atom.xml</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 4: deploy Hexo blog</p><p>The RSS icon can be found on the side navbar.</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/g8d0kpqn2lneq2x/rss1.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333"><h1 id="Subscription-amp-RSS-Reader"><a href="#Subscription-amp-RSS-Reader" class="headerlink" title="Subscription &amp; RSS Reader"></a>Subscription &amp; RSS Reader</h1><p>Now, we have ‘RSS’ feature enabled on my blog. In order to use it, you need to have some RSS reader.</p><p>For Chrome Users, I recommend <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/rss-feed-reader/pnjaodmkngahhkoihejjehlcdlnohgmp/related?hl=en" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">RSS Feed Reader</a> extension. This is what you will see when a new feed comes, pretty neat.</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/5jhznejen2anogw/rss2.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333"><p>Enjoy reading! It’s a short Day 9 <o></o></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Another feature for my imaginary readers :)&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="nerdyNotes" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/nerdyNotes/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo - Add Site Map</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/9a962e6d/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/9a962e6d/</id>
    <published>2019-07-17T06:41:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.472Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Float up to the top in Google search! Yes, only Google not Baidu the second largest search engine in the world.</p><a id="more"></a><h1 id="Why-Sitemap"><a href="#Why-Sitemap" class="headerlink" title="Why Sitemap"></a>Why Sitemap</h1><p>Day 7 with Hexo, another task done.</p><p>Goal: add sitemap for search engines</p><p>Why: I just realized today, to let search engines, like Google, to find your blog, you need to create a sitemap.</p><p>Lan’s Complain: I failed to add my sitemap to dear Baidu.com (Chinese alternative to Google). I don’t have a Baidu account and it requires Chinese phone number for registration. This is one of the hundreds trails failed during this Hexo development project. How difficult to be a Chinese aboard?! I don’t mention the time wasted try different plugins and services.</p><h1 id="Sitemap-Creation"><a href="#Sitemap-Creation" class="headerlink" title="Sitemap Creation"></a>Sitemap Creation</h1><p>This is the easy part. The time consuming part will follow in the next section. </p><p>Step 1: install the plug-in </p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">npm install hexo-generator-sitemap --save</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 2: setup sitemap in blog _conf.yml. Add the following:</p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="attr">sitemap:</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">path:</span> <span class="string">sitemap.xml</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 3: generation</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">hexo g</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 4: check <code>public</code> folder and you should see <code>sitemap.xml</code></p><h1 id="Submit-Sitemap-to-Google"><a href="#Submit-Sitemap-to-Google" class="headerlink" title="Submit Sitemap to Google"></a>Submit Sitemap to Google</h1><p>Go to Google Search Console and login with your Google account. </p><p>Step 1: Add Property</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/mvn7lzh6yahwosu/site1.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333"><p>Step 2: Verification File</p><p>Lan: here I chose <code>HTML Tag</code></p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/gxen5skvfjen2bj/site2.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333"><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/4e0wv2a2f6grjlv/site3.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333"><p>Step 3: Add Verification Code</p><p>Go to theme_name\layout_partial\head\head.swig and add the HTML tag:</p><meta charset="UTF-8"><meta http-equiv="X-UA-Compatible" content="IE=edge"><meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1, maximum-scale=2"><meta name="theme-color" content><meta name="google-site-verification" content="yourVerificatoinCodeFromStep2">Step 4: Deploy your Hexo blog and Google Search Console will show <p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/0vqk3xf6tp73t9u/site_4.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333">Step 5: Submit sitemap</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/anrd7nrkky7qhpu/site5.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333"><p>Step 6: Click URL inspection. Important: Wait Patiently! </p><p>Lan: It took me approximately 1 hour until I saw the following picture. I did lots of research to figure out why I encountered nth failure today during this very long hour…instead I suggest you just relax and maybe go to bed. Miracle will happen tomorrow morning when you get up fresh. </p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/d3o7nimeb4u21us/site6.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333"><p>Step 7: You are on Google finally! Let me celebrate my 8th Day with Hexo…</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/as4q5ql73cva5wi/site7.png?raw=1" width="500" height="333">]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Float up to the top in Google search! Yes, only Google not Baidu the second largest search engine in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="nerdyNotes" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/nerdyNotes/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hexo - Add Gitalk Comment</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/66a6d538/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/66a6d538/</id>
    <published>2019-07-17T05:09:17.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.472Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A simple instruction on how to add Gitalk but lengthy discussion on why I selected Gitalk and some further issues with this plugin after implementation.</p><a id="more"></a><h1 id="The-Comment-Plug-In"><a href="#The-Comment-Plug-In" class="headerlink" title="The Comment Plug-In"></a>The Comment Plug-In</h1><p>Today is my day 7 with Hexo. Goal is to add comment feature here. </p><p>My requirements:</p><ul><li>Simple and elegant</li><li>Easy to manage</li><li>Allow <strong>Anonymous</strong> comments</li><li>FREE</li></ul><p>As always, let’s begin with some google search to find the popular ones. </p><ul><li><a href="https://github.com/imsun/gitment" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Gitment</a>: no maintenance anymore –&gt; OUT</li><li><a href="https://www.livere.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">LiveRe</a>: a Korean plug-in; it allows people to login with most popular social media account or just use email to comment. Sorry, don’t like its appearance –&gt; OUT</li><li><a href="https://www.hypercomments.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">hypercomment</a>: it has everything I wanted but it’s not a free plug-in –&gt; OUT</li><li><strong><a href="https://github.com/gitalk/gitalk" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Gitalk</a></strong>: only problem is that it requires a Github account. –&gt; CHOOSEN as of today</li><li><a href="https://valine.js.org/en/index.html" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Valine</a>: after implemented Gitalk, checked Valine and it seems good. –&gt; will test in the future</li></ul><span class="lanComment"> <p>Updated on August 2, 2019:</p><ul><li>Valine: it requires to have a <a href="https://leancloud.cn/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">LeanCloud</a> account. Surprisingly, it accepts international phone number for account registration. However, after successfully proved I am a human via image verification more than 5 times, the website refused to send me verification code to my US number. Fine, you are OUT!</li><li><a href="https://disqus.com/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Disqus</a>: I just don’t like your appearance. Sorry, OUT!</li></ul><p>To conclude, Gitalk is the final winner here! </p></span><h1 id="Gitalk-Implementation"><a href="#Gitalk-Implementation" class="headerlink" title="Gitalk Implementation"></a>Gitalk Implementation</h1><p>Step 1: Register Application on Github</p><p><a href="https://github.com/settings/applications/new" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://github.com/settings/applications/new</a></p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/bsf7apqj5squnbk/token.png?raw=1"><p>Step 2: Obtain Client ID &amp; Client Secret</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/s/jx0sskx73342rai/clientID.png?raw=1"><p>Step 3: I created a new repo to store all the comments. You can skip this step.</p><p>Step 4: Gitalk setup</p><p>It’s really easy with <code>next</code> theme. At the time of writing this post, my <code>next</code> version is v7.2.0. It comes with all the specifications for Gitalk. So there is no need to change several swig files as one would find from Google search. To implement Gitalk, one just need to change the <code>theme</code> _config.yml as follows:</p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="attr">gitalk:</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  enable:</span> <span class="string">ture</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  github_id:</span> <span class="string">lanVoyager</span> <span class="comment"># GitHub repo owner</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  repo:</span> <span class="string">gitalkHexoComment</span> <span class="comment"># Repository name to store issues</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  client_id:</span> <span class="string">obtained</span> <span class="string">from</span> <span class="string">Step</span> <span class="number">2</span> <span class="comment"># GitHub Application Client ID</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  client_secret:</span> <span class="string">obtained</span> <span class="string">from</span> <span class="string">Step</span> <span class="number">2</span> <span class="comment"># GitHub Application Client Secret</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  admin_user:</span> <span class="string">lanVoyager</span> <span class="comment"># GitHub repo owner and collaborators, only these guys can initialize gitHub issues</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  distraction_free_mode:</span> <span class="literal">true</span> <span class="comment"># Facebook-like distraction free mode</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  language:</span> <span class="string">[en,</span> <span class="string">zh-CN]</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 5: Blog deployment </p><h1 id="Gitalk-Initialization"><a href="#Gitalk-Initialization" class="headerlink" title="Gitalk Initialization"></a>Gitalk Initialization</h1><p>Another issue with Gitalk after implementation?!</p><p>It require admin to initialize the comment blocks for each and every post?!?! The good news is that you only need to initialize once and then for each newly pushed post, you have to manually initialize it. Just click it and login your Github.</p><p>There is scripts available online which does initialization automatically. I have decided postpone further time &amp; efforts investing into Gitalk. I may switch to Valine. Yes, Valine you are welcome to fail me in other ways. But not today! </p><h1 id="Gitalk-Comment-Count-in-Title-Block"><a href="#Gitalk-Comment-Count-in-Title-Block" class="headerlink" title="Gitalk Comment Count in Title Block"></a>Gitalk Comment Count in Title Block</h1><p>Added on August 14, 2019</p><p>I don’t like to have a pair of ‘critical’ eyes and being picky here. However, I just found that the comment count icon under the title block does not show ACURATE comment counts under each post with Gitalk. Yesterday, I complained about the word count estimates provided by <code>hexo-symbols-count-time</code>(here) and the very next day, another complain on inaccurate count for comments…Yes, I just can’t withstand BAD data and those things made my soul itching…</p><p>Here is the problem:</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1c3YACtDJmX7Wn_mFh5y6G6UJfXLO0Wdp"><h2 id="Quick-Google-Results"><a href="#Quick-Google-Results" class="headerlink" title="Quick Google Results"></a><strong>Quick Google Results</strong></h2><p>I maybe wrong, but it seems that at the moment (8/14/2019), Gitalk does not provide <code>nexT</code> comment counts. Basically, the two values are not linked. I believe that there is a way to correct it. However, I don’t have the time to dig it out. For now, the comment count will be removed.</p><p>FYI, <code>nexT</code> v7.2.0 comment counts seem to be working with (refer to post.swig):</p><ul><li>facebook_comments</li><li>disqus</li><li>valine</li><li>changyan</li></ul><h2 id="How-to-Remove-Comment-Icon"><a href="#How-to-Remove-Comment-Icon" class="headerlink" title="How to Remove Comment Icon"></a><strong>How to Remove Comment Icon</strong></h2><p>This can be changed in <code>post.swig</code> (.\themes\next\layout\_marco). Search for <code>if post.comments</code> and remove the entire block.</p><span class="lanComment"><p>For my own record, the backup file with the original comment block is named as post_08142019.swig.</p></span>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;A simple instruction on how to add Gitalk but lengthy discussion on why I selected Gitalk and some further issues with this plugin after implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="nerdyNotes" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/nerdyNotes/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>hexoTips</title>
    <link href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/a6eb593f/"/>
    <id>https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/a6eb593f/</id>
    <published>2019-07-16T04:56:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-01-14T18:24:25.477Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is just my study note archiving useful tricks &amp; tips for Hexo blog development. Another boring technical post.</p><a id="more"></a><h1 id="Adding-Abstract-on-The-Landing-Page"><a href="#Adding-Abstract-on-The-Landing-Page" class="headerlink" title="Adding Abstract on The Landing Page"></a>Adding Abstract on The Landing Page</h1><p>Goal: only post the abstract on the landing page with a link to access the full page.</p><p><strong>Approach 1</strong>: Add description into the front-matter of the markdown file</p><figure class="highlight markdown"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">---</span><br><span class="line">title: hexoTips</span><br><span class="line">tags: Hexo</span><br><span class="line">categories: nerdyNotes</span><br><span class="line">description: This is just my study note archiving useful tricks &amp; tips for Hexo blog development. Another boring technical post.</span><br><span class="line">---</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p><strong>Approach 2</strong>: edit theme_config file <code>yourBlog\themes\themeName\_config.yml</code>:</p><figure class="highlight yaml"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="attr">auto_excerpt:</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  enable:</span> <span class="literal">false</span></span><br><span class="line"><span class="attr">  length:</span> <span class="number">150</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>The above script will show the first 150 words of your post as abstract on the landing page. The length can be changed if needed.</p><p><strong>Approach 3</strong>: manually add Abstract in your post (md file) directly.</p><figure class="highlight markdown"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br><span class="line">9</span><br><span class="line">10</span><br><span class="line">11</span><br><span class="line">12</span><br><span class="line">13</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">---</span><br><span class="line">title: hexoTips</span><br><span class="line">tags: Hexo</span><br><span class="line">categories: nerdyNotes</span><br><span class="line">---</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="xml"><span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">img</span> <span class="attr">scr</span>=<span class="string">'sample.png'</span> <span class="attr">width</span> = <span class="string">"900"</span> <span class="attr">height</span> = <span class="string">"600"</span> <span class="attr">alt</span>=<span class="string">"sample"</span> <span class="attr">align</span>=<span class="string">center</span> /&gt;</span></span></span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">Add your Abstract...</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="xml"><span class="comment">&lt;!-- more --&gt;</span></span></span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">Add the body of the post...</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Adding-Customized-Blocks"><a href="#Adding-Customized-Blocks" class="headerlink" title="Adding Customized Blocks"></a>Adding Customized Blocks</h1><p>Date: August 2, 2019</p><p>Goal: add comment block</p><span class="lanComment"><p>This is a comment block</p></span><p>Solution: add customerized CSS </p><p>Step 1: add the following block in your CSS file under yourBlog/theme/next/source/css (details refer to post on <a href="https://lanVoyager.github.io/posts/ddb3530">LeafLet Map</a>)</p><figure class="highlight html"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">span.lanComment &#123;</span><br><span class="line">  display: block;</span><br><span class="line">  width: 100%;</span><br><span class="line">  padding: 5px;</span><br><span class="line">   background-color: #FFFACD; </span><br><span class="line">&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 2: in your mark down post, use the following when a comment block is needed.</p><figure class="highlight html"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line"><span class="tag">&lt;<span class="name">span</span> <span class="attr">class</span>=<span class="string">'lanComment'</span>&gt;</span></span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">This is a comment block</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line"><span class="tag">&lt;/<span class="name">span</span>&gt;</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Add-Centered-Quotation-Block"><a href="#Add-Centered-Quotation-Block" class="headerlink" title="Add Centered Quotation Block"></a>Add Centered Quotation Block</h1><p>Date: August 14, 2019</p><p>Goal: add centered quotation block</p><blockquote class="blockquote-center"><p>This is a test!</p></blockquote><p>Three approaches:</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br><span class="line">6</span><br><span class="line">7</span><br><span class="line">8</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">&lt;!-- 1. HTML Approach: directly write in Markdown --&gt;</span><br><span class="line">&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote-center&quot;&gt;blah blah blah&lt;/blockquote&gt;</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">&lt;!-- 2. Use Tag --&gt;</span><br><span class="line">&#123;% centerquote %&#125;blah blah blah&#123;% endcenterquote %&#125;</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">&lt;!-- 3. cq == centerquote --&gt;</span><br><span class="line">&#123;% cq %&#125; blah blah blah &#123;% endcq %&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Pin-A-Post-at-Top-of-the-Blog"><a href="#Pin-A-Post-at-Top-of-the-Blog" class="headerlink" title="Pin A Post at Top of the Blog"></a>Pin A Post at Top of the Blog</h1><p>Date: August 14, 2019</p><p>Goal:Pin a post at top of the blog. Use <code>hexo-generator-index-pin-top</code></p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1u4yGI6rII6DmTNLY9Senibm9v--_-r6-"><p>Step 1:  install the plugin</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ npm uninstall hexo-generator-index --save</span><br><span class="line">$ npm install hexo-generator-index-pin-top --save</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 2: pin the post in markdown’s front-matter</p><figure class="highlight markdown"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">title: postName</span><br><span class="line">top: true</span><br><span class="line">date: </span><br><span class="line">tags:</span><br><span class="line">categories:</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 3: Add Pin Icon. Open<code>post.swig</code> in <code>/blog/themes/next/layout/_macro</code>, locate<code>&lt;div class=&quot;post-meta&quot;&gt;</code>  div and add the following script.</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br><span class="line">4</span><br><span class="line">5</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">&#123;% if post.top %&#125;  </span><br><span class="line">&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-thumb-tack&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  </span><br><span class="line">&lt;font color=7D26CD&gt;PINNED&lt;/font&gt;  </span><br><span class="line">&lt;span class=&quot;post-meta-divider&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;</span><br><span class="line">&#123;% endif %&#125;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Font-Color-amp-Size"><a href="#Font-Color-amp-Size" class="headerlink" title="Font Color &amp; Size"></a>Font Color &amp; Size</h1><p>Date: August 14, 2019</p><p>Goal: customize font color &amp; size in a post</p><p>  <font size="12">bigger font size </font></p><p><font color="red"> this is a line of red text </font></p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">&lt;font size=12 &gt; bigger font size &lt;/font&gt;</span><br><span class="line"></span><br><span class="line">&lt;font color=&quot;red&quot;&gt; this is a line of red t &lt;/font&gt;</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Asset-Hosting"><a href="#Asset-Hosting" class="headerlink" title="Asset Hosting"></a>Asset Hosting</h1><p>Date: August 20, 2019</p><p>Goal: settle down on asset hosting sites. NOT FOR MAINLAND CHINA!!! The ones I tested are all blocked in China. The Chinese services all rejected my registrations from U.S.</p><h2 id="Initial-Hosting-Site-Dropbox"><a href="#Initial-Hosting-Site-Dropbox" class="headerlink" title="Initial Hosting Site: Dropbox"></a>Initial Hosting Site: Dropbox</h2><p><strong>Limitation:</strong> 2G only and require you to install Dropbox app to get the external link. Also I need to maintain an extra account outside Google…However, in general, it’s really good for the purpose of hosting assests of this blog. I just want to consolidate resources and reduce number of accounts and apps I use.</p><p><strong>How to Get Extneral Link?</strong></p><p>Step 1: Apply for a <a href="https://www.dropbox.com" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Dropbox</a> account</p><p>Step 2: Install the <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/install" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">Dropbox App</a></p><p>Step 3: From your sync folder or the Dropbox app, choose the file, right click and select ‘Copy Link’</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1di6O2zHzLx375H2KKPTKdfSKLidr17v3"><p>Step 4: Modify the dropbox link</p><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">original Link: https://www.dropbox.com/s/xxxxxx/hexo-add-view-count-firestore_1.png?dl=0</span><br><span class="line">modified Link: https://www.dropbox.com/s/xxxxxx/hexo-add-view-count-firestore_1.png?raw=1</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>Step 5: embed the modified link into the markdown post </p><h1 id="Current-Hosting-Site-Google-Drive"><a href="#Current-Hosting-Site-Google-Drive" class="headerlink" title="Current Hosting Site: Google Drive"></a>Current Hosting Site: Google Drive</h1><p><strong>Reason:</strong> personal perference and it meets all my needs at the moment with 15G space and linked to my Google account smoothly. Also, no app is required to use it.</p><h2 id="How-to-Get-External-Link"><a href="#How-to-Get-External-Link" class="headerlink" title="How to Get External Link"></a>How to Get External Link</h2><p>I believe most pepole know how to upload files to Google Drive. Let’s skip this step.</p><p>Step 1: On your Google Drive, select the file you want to use for the blog. Right click and select ‘Get shareable link’</p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1wF4sNAQrwqZXkoVl6bc6SwfOvuv1h_Gw"><p>Step 2: Modify ‘Link sharing’ properties, by clicking <code>More...</code></p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=1c2ErYYgPTStbiY5QdHQs8dzIuQbLqr4F"><p>Step 3: Select <code>Public on the web</code></p><img src="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&id=17oiuJ2Mm1O_d_AReiIR5L8UBlqiFytwT"><p>Step 4: Modify the link</p><p><strong>Original Link Copied from Google Drive:</strong></p><p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://drive.google.com/file/d/</a><font color="red">stringAsFileID</font>/view?usp=sharing</p><p><strong>Modified Link</strong></p><p><a href="https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=" rel="external nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;id=</a><font color="red">copyStringAsFileIDHere</font></p><p>Step 5: embed the modified link into the markdown post </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;This is just my study note archiving useful tricks &amp;amp; tips for Hexo blog development. Another boring technical post.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="nerdyNotes" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/categories/nerdyNotes/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://lanVoyager.github.io/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
